[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是CS50，这是第6周。
This is CS50, and this is week 6.
再次，这是那些罕见的日子之一，在短短的时间内
And this is, again, one of those rare days where in just a bit of time
您将可以说您学习了一门新语言。
you'll be able to say that you learned a new language.
今天的语言将是称为Python的语言。
And that language today is going to be this language called Python.
而且我们以为我们将从介绍Python开始
And we'd thought we'd begin by introducing Python
通过一些更熟悉的朋友。
by way of some more familiar friends.
因此，这当然是我们在第0周开始的课程
So this, of course, is where we began the course back in week 0
当我们介绍Scratch时，一个简单的程序
when we introduced Scratch, a simple program that
简单地说：“你好，世界。”
quite simply says "hello, world."
然后很快，事情就升级了，变成了
And then very quickly, things escalated and became
更加神秘，更神秘，我们介绍了C和语法
a lot more cryptic, a lot more arcane, and we introduced C and syntax
这样，当然可以做完全一样的事情，
like this, which of course do the exact same thing,
只是在屏幕上打印出“你好，世界”，但有要求
just printing out "hello, world" on the screen, but with the requirement
您了解并包含所有这些各种语法。
that you understand and you include all of this various syntax.
所以今天，所有这些复杂性，所有来自C的语法，
So today, all of this complexity, all of the syntax from C,
突然开始融化，以至于我们
suddenly begins to melt away, such that we're
留下了这种称为Python的新语言
left with this new language called Python
这行代码就能达到完全相同的目标
that's going to achieve the exact same goal simply with this line of code
这里。
here.
也就是说，Python往往更易于访问，
Which is to say that Python tends to be more accessible,
它往往会容易一些。
it tends to be a little easier.
但这是因为它建立在开始的传统基础上，
But that's because it's built on this tradition of having started,
像人类几年前一样，构建诸如C之类的底层语言，
as humans years ago, building these low-level languages like C,
意识到缺少哪些功能，哪些痛点，
realizing what features are missing, what some of the pain points are,
然后在这些较旧的语言之上叠加新的思想，新功能，
and then layering on top of those older languages new ideas, new features,
以及新的语言。
and in turn new languages.
因此，实际上有数十种，数百种编程语言。
So there are dozens, hundreds really, of programming languages out there.
但总会有一些子集会很受欢迎，非常流行
But there's always a subset of them that tend to be very popular, very in vogue
在任何给定时间。
at any given time.
Python是那些非常流行的语言之一。
Python is among those very popular languages.
实际上，这是我们要研究的第三种语言，
And it's the third of our languages that we'll look at, indeed,
在学期的这一点上。
at this point in the term.
因此，让我们继续介绍Python的一些语法，
So let's go ahead and introduce some of the syntax of Python,
确实是通过与过去的比较来进行的。
really by way of comparison with what we've seen in the past.
因为无论今天的某些话题有多新，
Because no matter how new some of today's topics are,
在我们将再次看到循环的意义上，他们应该都很熟悉，
they should all be familiar in the sense that we're going to see loops again,
条件，变量，函数，返回值。
conditions, variables, functions, return values.
几乎就是功能的翻译
There's pretty much just going to be a translation of features
过去到现在的功能。
past to now features present.
因此，当然，在Scratch的世界中，
So this of course, in the world of Scratch,
只是一个拼图或一个功能，其目的是生命
was just one puzzle piece or a function, whose purpose in life
在屏幕上说“你好，世界”。
is to say "hello, world" on the screen.
在第1周，我们在这里将其翻译为更隐秘的语法，
In week 1, we translated this to the more cryptic syntax here,
关键的细节是它是printf，引号，字符串，
key details being that it's printf, that you have the quote, the string,
“您好，世界”，您使用反斜杠n表示换行符。
"hello, world," you have this backslash n to represent a new line character.
然后，当然，这种陈述必须以分号结尾。
And then of course, this kind of statement has to end with a semicolon.
如今使用该语言的等效代码行
The equivalent line of code today on out in this language
被称为Python的将非常简单。
called Python is going to be quite simply this.
因此，它看起来确实很相似，但是现在是print而不是printf。
So it looks similar, certainly, but it's now print instead of printf.
我们仍然有双引号，但是反斜杠n和
We still have the double quotes, but gone are the backslash n as well as
分号。
the semicolon.
因此，如果您过于频繁地踢自己，以至于忘记
So if you've been kicking yourself all too frequently for forgetting
像分号这样的愚蠢事物，Python现在将成为您的朋友。
stupid things like the semicolons, Python will now be your friend.
好吧，让我们看另一个例子
Well, let's take a look at another example
在这里，我们也将如何获取用户输入。
here, how we might go about getting user input as well.
好吧，在这里请注意，我们有一个名为Ask的拼图。
Well, here notice that we have a puzzle piece called Ask.
它说，问“你叫什么名字？”等一下
And it says, ask "What's your name?" and wait.
接下来的拼图说，无论人类输入了什么，
And the next puzzle piece said, whatever the human had typed in,
在其前面加上“你好”一词。
precede it with the word "hello."
在C中，我们看到了这样的代码-string_answer
In C we saw code like this-- string_answer
等于get_string“你叫什么名字？”
equals get_string "what's your name?"
然后使用printf“你好％s”进行打印
and then printing out with printf, "hello %s,"
为另一个插入一个值。
plugging in one value for the other.
在Python中，这种复杂性也将消失。
In Python, some of this complexity is about to melt away, too.
在Python中，我们将看到一些类似的东西。
And in Python, we're going to see a little something like this.
因此，不再提及变量类型。
So no longer present is the mention of the type of variable.
分号末尾不再存在。
No longer present is the semicolon at the end.
不再显示％s和要打印的其他参数。
And no longer present is the %s and that additional argument to print.
因此，事实上，让我们继续来看这些事情。
So in fact, let's go ahead and see these things in action.
我将继续讨论此处，然后转到CS50 IDE。
I'm going to go ahead and go over to CS50 IDE here for just a moment.
在CS50 IDE中，我将继续编写
And within CS50 IDE, I'm going to go ahead and write
我的第一个Python程序。
my very first Python program.
为此，我将继续创建一个文件，该文件我们最初将
And to do that, I'm going to go ahead and create a file that we'll initially
叫做hello.py。
called hello.py.
就像在C语言世界中一样，Python程序具有标准的文件扩展名
Much like in the world of C, Python programs have a standard file extension
是.py而不是.c。
being .py instead of .c.
我要去做我建议的最简单的翻译。
And I'm just going to do what I proposed was the simplest translation.
我只是继续说打印，“你好，世界”。
I'm just going to go ahead and say print, "hello, world."
我要保存文件。
I'm going to save my file.
然后我要进入终端窗口。
And then I'm going to go down to my terminal window.
当然，在过去，我们会使用make
And in the past, of course, we would have used make,
然后我们会完成./hello之类的。
and then we would have done ./hello or the like.
但是今天，我非常简单地将运行一个本身称为Python的命令。
But today, I'm quite simply going to run a command that itself is called Python.
我要传递我刚才的文件名
I'm going to pass in the name of the file I just
创建为其命令行参数。
created as its command line argument.
瞧，按下Enter键，是我的第一个Python程序。
And voila, hitting Enter, there is my very first program in Python.
因此，该功能非常强大。
So that's pretty powerful.
让我们继续创建我刚才提出的第二个程序。
Let's go ahead and create the second program that I proposed a moment ago.
而不是只打印“你好，世界”
Instead of just printing out "hello, world"
整个时间，我这次也要继续
the whole time, I'm also going to go ahead this time
并给自己一个变量，我将其称为答案。
and give myself a variable that I'll call answer.
我现在要继续进行，并从用户那里获取输入。
I'm going to go ahead now and get input from the user.
我将继续使用熟悉的get_string
And I'm going to go ahead and use the familiar get_string
我们确实在C中看到了
that we did see in C.
我将继续问“您叫什么名字”问号。
I'm going to go ahead and ask, "What's your name" question mark.
我不会打分号。
I'm not going to bother with a semicolon.
但是在这里，我要继续说打印“你好”，逗号，然后
But down here, I'm going to go ahead and say print "hello," comma, and then
引号内有一个空格。
a space inside of the quotes.
而且，我实际上不会继续执行％s，而是继续
And instead of doing something like %s, I'm actually going to go ahead and just
做一个加号运算符，然后按字面意思是“答案”。
do a plus operator, and then literally the word "answer."
但是要注意的是，这还行不通。
But the catch is that this isn't going to work just yet.
这暂时还行不通，因为事实证明，使用get_string，
This isn't going to work just yet, because get_string, it turns out,
就像它不是C附带的一样，它也不是Python附带的。
just like it doesn't come with C, it also doesn't come with Python.
所以我需要做一件事
So I need to do one thing that's going to be
与过去有些不同。
a little bit different from the past.
我要说的不是散列，而是说一些东西
Instead of hash including something, I'm going to literally say
从cs50导入get_string。
from cs50 import get_string.
因此，在C语言世界中，我们记得
So in the world of C, recall that we included
cs50.h，其中具有诸如get_string和get_int之类的函数的声明
cs50.h, which had declarations for functions like get_string and get_int
等等。
and so forth.
在Python的世界中，我们将向您展示一些类似的精神，
In the world of Python, we're going to show you something similar in spirit,
但语法略有不同。
but the syntax is just a little different.
我们将从cs50说起，这是我们工作人员的Python库
We're going to say from cs50, which is our Python library that we the staff
编写，导入，即专门包含一个功能
wrote, import, that is, include a function specifically
称为get_string。
called get_string.
现在，我刚才在屏幕上可能看到的任何错误
And now any errors that I might have seen a moment ago on the screen
已经消失了。
have disappeared.
如果我继续保存该文件，然后在python空间中添加hello.py并按Enter，
If I go ahead and save this file and now do python space hello.py and hit Enter,
现在我可以输入我的真实姓名，瞧，我看到“你好”，逗号，
now I can go ahead and type in my actual name, and voila, I see "hello," comma,
“大卫。”
"David."
因此，让我们来梳理一下这段代码的不同之处
So let's tease apart what's different about this code
考虑一下此后我们还能做些什么。
and consider what more we can do after this.
再次提醒您，在第3行上，不再提及字符串。
So again, notice-- on line 3, there's no mention of string anymore.
如果我想要一个变量，我就继续给自己
If I want a variable, I just go ahead and give myself
称为答案的变量。
a variable called answer.
该函数仍称为get_string，它仍然需要一个参数
The function is still called get_string, and it still takes an argument just
类似于C版本，但该行不再以分号结尾。
like the C version, but the line no longer ends with a semicolon.
在我这里的最后一行代码中，现在确实是print而不是printf。
On my final line of code here, print is now indeed print instead of printf.
然后这是新的语法。
And then this is new syntax.
但是从某种意义上讲，它将变得更加简单。
But in some sense, it's going to be a lot more straightforward.
不必提前考虑我想要％s和占位符的位置，
Instead of having to think in advance where I want the %s and my placeholder,
这个加号运算符似乎正在为我做某事。
this plus operator seems to be doing something for me.
让我继续，在这里向小组提问。
And let me go ahead and ask a question of the group here.
那个加号运算符似乎在做什么？
What does that plus operator seem to be doing?
因为它不是算术意义上的加法。
Because it's not addition in the arithmetic sense.
我们不喜欢将数字相加。
We're not like adding numbers together.
但是，加号显然在做些可以给我们视觉效果的事情。
But the plus is clearly doing something that gives us a visual result.
彼得有什么想法吗？
Any thoughts from Peter?
这是做什么加上什么？
What's this plus doing?
听众：它是连接字符串。
AUDIENCE: It's concatenating strings.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，它是连接字符串，
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, it's concatenating strings,
这是用来描述一根弦和另一根弦的连接的技术术语。
which is the term of art to describe the joining of one string and the other.
因此，这非常类似于Scratch自己的Join块。
So it's quite like, therefore, Scratch's own Join block.
现在，我们有了该Join块的字面翻译，
We now have a literal translation of that Join block,
这在C中是没有的。在C中，我们必须使用printf，而我们必须使用％s。
which we didn't have in C. In C we had to use printf, we had to use %s.
Python将变得更加用户友好，例如
Python is going to be a little more user friendly, such
如果您想连接两个字符串，例如“ hello”，
that if you want to join two strings like "hello,"
逗号，空格和该变量的内容，
comma, space, and the contents of that variable,
我们可以直接使用加号运算符。
we can just use this plus operator instead.
当然，我们要做的最后一件事是，
And the last thing that we had to do was, of course,
导入该库，以便我们可以访问
import this library so that we have access
到get_string函数本身。
to the get_string function itself.
好吧，让我们继续浏览其他功能
Well, let's go ahead and take a tour of just some other features
的Python知识，然后主要学习当今的许多动手实例。
of Python and then dive in primarily to a lot of hands-on examples today.
所以回想一下，在我们刚才看到的示例中，
So recall that in the example we just saw,
我们有第一行代码，它从用户那里得到一个字符串，
we had this first line of code, which gets a string from the user,
将其存储在一个名为answer的变量中。
stores it in a variable called answer.
我们有第二行代码，正如彼得所说，
We had this second line of code, which as Peter notes,
将两个值串联在一起。
concatenated two values together.
事实证明，尽管这绝对比使用C语言更方便
But it turns out, even though this is definitely more convenient than in C
在那你可以只用一个现有的字符串和另一个
in that you can just take an existing string and another
并将它们连接在一起，而不必使用格式字符串等，
and join them together without having to use format strings or the like,
好吧，事实证明那是另一种方式，坦率地说，
well, it turns out there's another way, there's frankly many
像Python这样的语言中实现相同结果的方法。
ways in languages like Python to achieve the same result.
我将继续建议在此更改此行
And I'm going to go ahead and propose that we now change this line here
这种时髦的语法。
to this funky syntax.
乍看之下绝对是丑陋的，那就是
So definitely ugly at first glance, and that's
部分原因是这是Python的一个相对较新的功能。
partly because this is a relatively new feature of Python.
但是请注意，在Python中我们可以使用这些花括号，所以花括号
But notice that in Python can we use these curly braces, so curly braces
我们在C语言中使用过的方法，可以在此处插入变量的实际值。
that we have used in C, to plug in an actual value of a variable here.
因此，Python的print函数使用％大括号代替了％s，
So instead of %s, Python's print function uses these curly braces that
本质上说，在这里插入一个值。
essentially say, plug in a value here.
但是这里有一个奇怪的地方。
But there's one oddity here.
您不能只是开始将大括号和变量名放入字符串中，
You can't just start putting curly braces and variable names into strings,
在Python中用引号引起来的字符串。
that is quoted strings in Python.
您还必须告诉该语言，其后是格式化的字符串。
You also have to tell the language that what follows is a formatted string.
所以这也许是我们迄今为止所见过的最奇怪的事情。
So this is perhaps the weirdest thing we've seen yet.
但是当您确实有一对双引号时
But when you do have a pair of double quotes
就像我在这里一样，在它前面加上一个f实际上
like I have here, prefixing it with an f will actually
告诉计算机格式化该字符串的内容，
tell the computer to format the contents of that string,
在当前括号之间插入值，而不是
plugging in values between those currently braces, as opposed to
从字面上打印这些花括号本身。
literally printing those curly braces themselves.
因此，让我继续并转换到我的实际代码，然后尝试一下。
So let me go ahead and transition to my actual code here and try this out.
与其使用彼得描述的并置运算符，
Instead of using the concatenation operator as Peter described it,
这个加号运算符，让我从字面上讲
this plus operator, let me literally go ahead
最初说“你好，回答”。
and say, "hello, answer," initially.
因此，这可能不是正确的方法，
So this is probably not going to be the right approach,
因为如果我重新运行该程序，hello.py的python，
because if I rerun this program, python of hello.py,
会问我叫什么名字。
it's going to ask me what's my name.
我要输入“ David”，
I'm going to type in "David," and it's going
完全不理我，因为我在字面上硬编码了“你好，答案”。
to ignore me altogether, because I literally hardcoded "hello, answer."
但是，开始也不是很正确。
But it's also not going to be quite right to just start
将其放在花括号中，因为如果再次运行该程序，python
putting that in curly braces, because if I again run this program, python
的hello.py，然后输入我的名字，现在开始
of hello.py, and type in my name, now it's going
说“你好，大方地回答”。
to say "hello, squiggly brace answer."
所以这只是我的微妙变化
So here is just a subtle change where I have
告诉Python实际上双引号之间的这种类型的字符串
to tell Python that this type of string between the double quotes is in fact
格式化的字符串。
a formatted string.
现在，如果我重新运行hello.py的python并输入“ David”，
And now if I rerun python of hello.py and type in "David,"
我现在得到“你好，大卫”。
I now get "hello, David."
因此，它比C更加方便，因为，再次，您
So it's marginally more convenient than C, because, again, you
不必在这里有占位符，在这里有占位符，然后
don't have to have a placeholder here, a placeholder here, and then
以逗号分隔的其他参数列表。
a comma separated list of additional arguments.
因此，如果您愿意的话，这只是一种更为简洁的方法，
So it's just a more succinct way, if you will,
实际将更多值引入要创建的字符串中。
to actually introduce more values into a string that you want to create.
这些称为格式字符串，或简称为短f字符串。
These are called format strings, or for short f-strings.
这是我们编程时工具包中现在拥有的一项新功能
And it's a new feature that we now have in our toolkit when programming
使用这种称为Python的新语言。
with this new language called Python.
好吧，让我们看一下拼图的其他一些翻译
Well, let's take a look at a few other translation of puzzle pieces
看，然后转到Python，然后开始
to see, and then turn to Python and then start
建立我们自己的一些程序。
building some programs of our own.
因此，在Scratch中，这是一个变量的早期示例
So here in Scratch, this was an example early on of a variable
称为计数器，将其初始化为0。
called counter, initializing it to 0.
在第1周的C语言中，我们开始将其翻译成这样的代码-int counter
In C, in week 1, we started translating that to code like this-- int counter
等于0分号。
equals 0 semicolon.
这给了我们一个int类型的变量，其初始值为0。
And that gave us a variable of type int whose initial value was 0.
在Python中，代码将相似-
In Python, the code is going to be similar--
相似，但将会更加简单。
similar, but it's going to be a little simpler still.
注意，我不必在Python中提及我想要的变量类型。
Notice that I don't have to in Python mention the type of variable I want.
它会根据上下文推断出它是什么。
It will infer from context what it is.
而且我也不必在那里有分号。
And I also don't have to have the semicolon there.
因此，Python中的counter等于0将为您提供一个名为counter的变量。
So counter equals 0 in Python is going to give you a variable called counter.
并且因为您要为其分配值0，所以Python本身
And because you're assigning it the value 0, Python itself
语言会推断出，哦，你必须
the language will infer that, oh, you must
表示这是一个整数或整数。
mean this to be an int or an integer.
我们在Scratch中看到了什么？
What else did we see in Scratch?
换计数器加1。
Change counter by 1.
因此，这是将变量的值增加1的一种方法。
So this was a way of increasing the value of a variable by 1.
在C语言中，我们有几种不同的方法来实现这一点。
In C, we had a few different ways to implement this.
我们可以说计数器等于计数器加1。
We could say counter equals counter plus 1.
这是一种学究的方式，打字时既冗长又乏味。
It's kind of pedantic, it's kind of long and tedious to type.
因此，我们有一些简写形式表示
So instead, we had some shorthand notation that
允许我们这样做。
allowed us to do it this way instead.
在C语言中，我们可以做反加等于1
In C, we were able to do counter plus equals 1,
这将达到相同的结果。
and that was going to achieve the same result.
嗯，在Python中，我们实际上也有两种方法。
Well, in Python we actually have a couple of approaches as well.
就像在C语言中一样，我们可以像这样明确地说出来
We can, much like in C, say it explicitly like this
但只需省略分号即可。
but just omit the semicolon.
因此，counter等于counter加1。
So counter equals counter plus 1.
Python中的逻辑与C中的逻辑完全相同。
The logic in Python is exactly the same as in C.
至于这种简写形式，同样在Python中也存在
And as for this shorthand notation, this also exists in Python, again
没有分号。
without the semicolon.
故事中的这一点在Python中还不存在的一件事是
The one thing that does not exist in Python at this point in the story is
花哨的柜台++语法，或i ++，使它变得均匀的语法糖
that fancy counter++ syntax, or i++, that syntactic sugar that made it even
更简洁地只是增加一个变量，
more succinct to just increment a variable,
不幸的是在Python中不存在。
unfortunately does not exist in Python.
但是您可以做计数器加等于1或任何您碰巧的变量。
But you can do counter plus equals 1, or whatever your variable happens to be.
好吧，我们在Scratch和C之后还看到了什么？
Well, what else did we see in Scratch and then C?
回想一下。
recall this.
当然，我们很早就引入了条件。
We introduced, of course, conditions pretty early on.
这些条件使用布尔表达式
And those conditions use Boolean expressions
决定是要执行此操作，还是执行此其他操作，还是执行其他操作
to decide whether to do this, or this other thing, or something else
共。
altogether.
在C语言中，我们将其转换为看起来类似的内容。
In C, we converted this to what looked kind of similar.
的确，花括号紧紧地扣住了printf线，只是
Indeed, the curly braces kind of hug the printf line, just
就像这里的黄色状态拥抱了紫色的说块一样。
like the yellow condition here hugs the purple Say block.
而且我们在布尔表达式周围有括号，例如x小于y。
And we had parentheses around the Boolean expression, like x less than y.
我们再次在花括号内使用了printf
We again used printf inside of the curly braces
其中带有双引号，换行符的反斜杠n和分号。
which had double quotes, a backslash n for a new line, and a semicolon.
很好的是，Python的精神将完全相同
Python, nicely enough, is going to be sort of identical in spirit
但在语法上更简单。
but simpler syntactically.
Python今后将是这样的。
What Python is going to look like henceforth is just this.
因此，x小于y的括号消失了。
So the parentheses around the x less than y go away.
花括号消失。
The curly braces go away.
新线消失了。
The new line goes away.
分号消失了。
And the semicolon goes away.
在这里，您仅看到人类编程进化的一个小例子
And here you see just a tiny example of evolution of humans programming
语言。
languages.
如果你和我对所有的事情都感到沮丧
If you and I have been frustrated for some time about all
到处都是愚蠢的分号和花括号，
the stupid semicolons and curly braces all over the place,
从某种意义上讲，这会使您的代码更难阅读，
it makes it harder, in some sense, for your code to read,
更不用说是正确的了，人类在发明新语言时就决定了
let alone being correct, humans decided when inventing new languages
那，你知道什么，为什么我们不只是说我们的意思
that, you know what, why don't we just say what we mean
不用担心所有这些语法复杂性吗？
and not worry as much about all of this syntactic complexity?
让我们保持简单。
Let's keep things simpler.
的确，这就是我们在这里看到的，是Python中的一个示例。
And indeed, that's what we see here, is one example in Python.
但是有一个关键的细节。
But there's a key detail.
如果您有任何习惯，什么时候
If any of you have been in the habit, when
用C编写代码，到时有点草率
writing code in C, of being a little sloppy when it comes
根据您的缩进，也许style50一直在
to your indentation, and maybe style50 is constantly
大喊大叫您要添加空格，添加空格或删除空格或线条，
yelling at you to add spaces, add spaces, or remove spaces or lines,
好吧，在Python中，现在有必要正确缩进您的代码。
well, in Python it is now necessary to indent your code correctly.
当然，在C语言中，我们，CS50和世界上很多地方
In C, of course, we, CS50 and a lot of the world in general
建议您将代码缩进4个空格（通常是一个制表符）。
recommend that you indent your code by 4 spaces, typically, or one tab.
在Python的上下文中，您必须这样做。
In the context of Python, you must do so.
如果您不小心忽略了打印语句左侧的这些空格
If you accidentally omit these spaces just to the left of the print statement
在这里，您的Python代码根本不会运行。
here, your Python code is not going to run at all.
Python程序将无法正常工作。
The Python program just won't work.
这样就不再草率了。
So no more sloppiness.
Python将强加给您。
Python is going to impose this on you.
但是，好处是您不必费劲包括花括号。
But the upside is you don't have to bother including the curly braces.
哪里有更复杂的情况呢
What about a more complicated condition where there's
您是否可以遵循两条路径？
two paths you can follow, if or else?
好吧，在这种情况下，在C中，我们像这样直接翻译了它。
Well, in this case in C, we translated it pretty straightforwardly like this.
同样，在这里加上括号，在这里和这里使用花括号，反斜杠n，
Again, parentheses up here, curly braces here and here, backslash n,
反斜杠n和分号。
backslash n, and semicolon.
您也许可以在Python中猜到这
You can perhaps guess in Python that this
会变得更紧凑，因为动臂，
is going to get a little more compact, because boom,
现在我们不再需要括号了。
now we don't need the parentheses anymore.
我们确实需要缩进，但是不需要花括号。
We do we need to indent, but we don't need the curly braces.
我们不需要换行，也不需要分号。
We don't need the new line, and we don't need the semicolon.
因此，我们正在减少一些可以立即视为理所当然的功能。
So we're sort of shedding features that can be taken now for granted.
在Scratch中，当我们在路上有一个三向叉时，这个例子怎么样？
What about this example in Scratch when we had a three-way fork in the road,
如果，否则，如果，否则？
if, else, if, else?
好吧，在Python中-或更确切地说，在C语言中，我们将这样翻译。
Well, in Python-- or rather in C, we would have translated this like this.
而且那里没有太多的事情。
And there's not much going on there.
但这是相当数量的代码行，大约12行，
But it's pretty substantive number of lines of code, some 12 lines,
只是为了实现这个简单的想法。
just to achieve this simple idea.
在Python中，请注意这里将要消失的内容
In Python, notice what's going to go away here
再次是括号，再次是花括号，再次是反斜杠n，
is, again those parentheses, again those curly braces, again the backslash n,
和分号。
and the semicolon.
这里只有一个奇怪的地方。
There's only one oddity here.
只有一个奇怪的地方。
There's only one oddity.
对您来说看起来是错还是奇怪？
What looks wrong or weird to you?
也许，看起来像错字了吗？
Maybe, what looks like a typo to you?
我保证我不会在这里搞砸。
And I promise I haven't screwed up here.
也许在其他地方，但不在这里。
Maybe elsewhere, but not here.
安德鲁？
Andrew?
听众：如果在语法上有所不同，我想说的是elif而不是else。
AUDIENCE: I would say the elif instead of else if is different syntactically.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
因此，在C语言中，如果人类在多年前使用Python，我们会直言不讳
So whereas in C we would literally say else if, in Python, humans years ago,
决定，哎呀，为什么要说否则，并浪费所有时间将其键入，如果您
decided, heck, why say else if and waste all of that time typing that out if you
可以更简洁地说出“ elif”作为一个词，即ELIF。所以的确
can more succinctly say "elif" as one word, E-L-I-F. So indeed,
这是正确的语法。
this is correct syntax here.
而且您可以拥有更多这些。
And you can have more of those.
您可以在路上有四个叉子，之后有五个，六个，任何数量。
You can have four forks in the road, five, six, any number thereafter.
但是语法确实有所不同。
But the syntax is indeed a little different.
但这有点紧，对不对？
But it's a little tighter, right?
当您看一下这段代码时，语法上的注意力就会减少。
There's less syntactic distraction when you glance at this code.
您不必忽略许多分号和卷曲
You don't have to ignore as many semicolons and curly
大括号之类的。
braces and the like.
Python在语法上趋向于变得更加简洁。
Python tends to just be a little cleaner syntactically.
确实，这是许多其他功能的特征
And indeed, that's characteristic of a lot of more
最近，更现代的语言喜欢它。
recent, more modern languages like it.
好吧，让我们看一下Scratch以及C的其他几个块。
All right, let's take a look at a few other blocks in Scratch and in turn C.
在Scratch中，当我们想一次又一次地循环做某事时，
In Scratch, when we wanted to do something again and again as a loop,
也许永远，我们会从字面上使用Forever块。
perhaps forever, we would literally use the Forever block.
在C语言中，我们可以通过几种不同的方式来实现它。
In C, we could implement this in a few different ways.
我们很简单地提出了这一建议，而真正的印刷版是“你好，世界”，
And we proposed quite simply this one-- while true print out "hello, world,"
一遍又一遍。
again and again and again.
而且由于布尔表达式永远不变，
And because the Boolean expression never changes,
它确实将永远执行。
it's going to indeed execute forever.
因此，Python实际上非常相似，但是
So Python is actually pretty similar, but there
有一些细微的差异。
are a couple of subtle differences.
因此，您要根深蒂固这里的样子。
So ingrain in your mind what this looks like here.
括号，花括号，换行符和分号都为真。
We have true in parentheses, the curly braces, the new line, the semicolon.
许多都将消失，但它们仍然存在
A lot of that's about to go away, but they're still
会有细微的差别。
going to be a slight difference.
请注意，正如我一直强调的那样，我们正在缩进。
Notice that we're indenting, as I keep emphasizing.
我们不再需要换行，分号或当前的花括号，
We no longer have the new line or the semicolon or the currently braces,
但是是真的 -
but True--
结果是，错了-
and it turns out, False--
现在必须大写。
now must be capitalized.
因此，在C语言中，小写为false，在小写为true，在Python中
So whereas in C it was lowercase false, lowercase true, in Python
它会大写False，大写True。
it's going to be capitalized False, capitalized True.
为什么？
Why?
只是因为。
Just because.
但是还有另外一个值得注意的细节，我们的循环都需要
But there is one other detail that's important to note, both with our loops
在这里，以及我们的条件。
here, as well as with our conditions.
和以前一样，如果我倒退到最新状态，
Just as before, if I rewind to our most recent condition,
请注意，即使我们摆脱了花括号
notice that even though we've gotten rid of the curly braces
我们已经摆脱了括号，我们现在
and we've gotten rid of the parentheses, we now
已经引入了这些冒号，这是在表达之后所必需的，
have introduced these colons, which are necessary after this expression,
这个表达式和这个表达式，以使Python更加清楚
this expression, and this one, to make clear to Python
在下面缩进的代码行
that the lines of code that follow indented underneath
确实与if，elif或else有关。
are indeed relevant to that if, elif, or else.
而且我们在循环上下文中再次看到了相同的功能。
And we see that same feature again here in the context of a loop.
当然，我们看到了其他循环。
We saw other loops, of course.
在Scratch中，当我们想做某事时
In Scratch, when we wanted to do something
有限的次数（例如3次），我们将重复以下三遍。
a finite number of times like 3, we would repeat the following three times.
在C语言中，我们有几种不同的处理方法。
In C, we had a few different approaches to this.
我敢说，所有这些都是非常机械的。
And all of them, I dare say, were very mechanical.
就像，如果您想做三遍，那么C中的责任
Like, if you want to do something three times, the onus in C
在您声明变量，跟踪多少次
is on you to declare a variable, keep track of how many times
你已经数过了，增加东西。
you've counted already, increment the thing.
就像，有很多活动部件。
Like, there's a lot of moving parts.
因此在C语言中，一种方法看起来像这样。
And so in C, one approach looked like this.
我们声明一个名为i的变量等于0--
We declare a variable called i equals 0--
但我们可以称其为我们想要的任何东西-
but we could call it anything we wan--
我们这里有一个while块，再次询问布尔表达式
we have a while block here that's asking a Boolean expression again
再一次，我是否小于0--
and again, is i less than 0--
我小于3吗？
is i less than 3?
然后在循环内部，我们打印出“你好，世界”。
And then inside of the loop, we printed out "hello, world."
并使用C的语法糖，加号和加号，
And using C's syntactic sugar, the plus plus notation,
我们一直将i加1，将i加1，将i加1，
we kept adding 1 to i, add 1 to i, add 1 to i,
直到我们隐式地跳出循环
until we implicitly break out of the loop
因为它当然不小于3
because it's, of course, no longer less than 3.
因此，在Python中，其精神相似，但又有些杂乱无章。
So in Python, similar in spirit, but again, some of that clutter goes away.
我等于0是我们需要给自己一个变量的一切。
i equals 0 is all we need say to give ourselves a variable.
虽然我不足3，但我们只需要说一个冒号即可。
While i less than 3 is all we need to say there but with a colon.
然后，在其中适当缩进后，我们打印出“ hello，world”。
Then inside of that, indented properly, we print out "hello, world."
而且-我们无法做到正负加倍，如此令人失望的是-
And-- we can't do the plus plus, so minor disappointment--
但是我加上等于1的增量i。
but i plus equals 1 increments i.
因此，这将是在Python中实现完全相同的循环的一种方式
So this would be one way of implementing in Python the exact same thing a loop
执行三遍。
that executes three times.
但是我们当然在C语言中看到了其他方法，
But we saw other approaches, of course, in C,
在Python中还有其他可能的方法。
and there's other approaches possible in Python as well.
您可能还记得在C中我们看到了这种方法，即for循环。
You might recall in C that we saw this approach, the for loop.
而且很可能您一直在寻求for循环
And odds are you've been reaching for the for loop
相当频繁，因为尽管看起来有些神秘，
pretty frequently, because even though it looks a little more cryptic,
您可以将更多功能打包到这一行代码中
you can pack more features into that one line of code
在这些分号之间，如果可以的话。
in between those semicolons, if you will.
同样的逻辑，它只是打印出这个“你好，世界”
So same exact logic, it just prints out this "hello, world"
使用for循环代替3次。
three times using a for loop instead.
现在，在Python中，事情开始变得有些优雅。
In Python, things start to get a little elegant here now.
乍一看有点奇怪，但绝对更加简洁。
It's a little weird at first glance, but it's definitely more succinct.
如果您想做三遍，可以在Python中找到
If you want to do something three times, it turns out in Python
您可以为for循环使用更简洁的语法-对于我
you can use a more succinct syntax for the for loop-- for i
，然后放在方括号中的是值列表。
in, and then in square brackets a list of values.
就像我们过去在不同地方使用方括号一样
So just as we used in the past square brackets in a few different places
在Python的世界中，无论何时表示数组并索引到数组
to connote arrays and indexing into arrays, in the world of Python whenever
您围绕一堆价值观，而价值观本身之间用逗号隔开，
you surround a bunch of values that themselves have commas in between them,
然后用方括号将它们全部封装起来，
and you encapsulate them all using square brackets,
这就是我们将在Python中称为列表的内容。
that's what we're going to call in Python a list.
而且它在本质上与数组非常相似，
And it's very similar in spirit to an array,
但我们将在Python上下文中将其称为列表。
but we'll call it in the context of Python a list.
所以这行代码说的是，对于i in 0，1，2--这意味着什么？
And so what this line of code says is, for i in 0, 1, 2-- what does that mean?
这是Python中的for循环，它说给我一个变量i。
This is a for loop in Python that says, give me a variable called i.
并且在此循环的第一次迭代中，将i设为0。
And on the first iteration of this loop set i equal to 0.
在此循环的第二次迭代中，i等于1。
On the second iteration of this loop set i equal to 1.
在此循环的最后一次迭代中，为我设置i等于2。
And on the last iteration of this loop, set i equal to 2 for me.
它只是为您完成所有这些工作。
It just does all of that for you.
现在，实际上一天结束时
Now, at the end of the day it actually doesn't
不管我本身是什么，因为我没有打印i的值。
matter what i is per se, because I'm not printing the value of i.
那完全没问题。
And that's totally fine.
奇怪的是，您已经习惯了一次又一次地做某事的循环，
Odds are you've used for loops where you did something again and again,
就像打印“你好，世界”一样，即使你没有打印出来
like printing "hello, world," even though you didn't print out
i的价值
the value of i.
所以从技术上讲，我可以将任何3件事放在方括号中
So technically, I could have put any 3 things in the square brackets
如果我想要的话。
if I want.
但是约定只是枚举，就像在C，0、1、2中一样
But the convention would be just enumerate, just like in C, 0, 1, 2,
就像计算机科学家从0开始计数一样。
just like a computer scientist counting from 0.
但这很容易分解。
But this could break down pretty easily.
这可能很快变得非常丑陋。
This could become very ugly very quickly.
有人看到Python中的for循环有问题吗
Does anyone see a problem with for loops in Python
如果您必须在这些方括号之间放置值列表
if you have to put in between those square brackets the list of values
您想遍历吗？
that you want to iterate over?
诺亚？
Noah?
观众：如果您想做某件事，例如50次，
AUDIENCE: If you want to do, for example, a thing 50 times,
您必须写出0、1、2、3、4、5、6。
you'd have to write out 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
天哪，它很快就会开始显得丑陋。
My God, it would start to look hideous quickly.
提到50很有趣，因为在准备
And it's funny you mention 50, because in preparing
今天的演讲演示，我回到了第0周，
this demonstration for lecture today, I went back to week 0,
实际上在第0周的模拟是要打印出“你好，世界”
when actually the analog in week 0 was to indeed print out "hello, world"
50次。
50 times.
我心想，该死的，这是
And I thought to myself, damn it, this is
现在看起来很残酷，因为我从字面上看
going to look atrocious now, because I literally
必须放在方括号内0、1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8
have to put inside of square brackets 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8,
从9到49，就像诺亚所说的那样，这看起来简直是残酷的。
9, all the way to 49, as Noah says, which would just look atrocious.
就像，肯定有一种更好的方法。
Like, surely there's got to be a better way.
还有。
And there is.
尽管这对于极短的值可能很有吸引力，
While this might be compelling for very short values,
如果需要，Python中有一种更简单的方法
there's a simpler way in Python when you want
做一些事情。
to do something some number of times.
我们可以用这个替换这三个值的列表，
We can replace this list of three values with this,
一个称为范围的函数，它接受输入，即事物的数量
a function called range that takes an input, which is the number of things
你想回来的。
that you want to return.
从本质上讲，传递3这样的输入对您的范围有什么影响，
And essentially, what range will do for you passed an input like 3,
它将自动为您生成三个值（0、1和2）的列表。
it will automatically generate for you a list of three values, 0, 1, and 2.
然后，Python将为您迭代这三个值。
And then Python will iterate over those three values for you.
所以刚才挪亚很关心，如果我现在想重复50次，
So to Noah's concern a moment ago, if I now want to iterate 50 times,
我只是将3更改为50，我没有
I just change the 3 to a 50, I don't have
造成这种疯狂的混乱，包括手动输入的0到49列表，
to create this crazy mess of a manually typed out list of 0 through 49,
当然，这并不是一个设计得很好的程序，
which, of course, would not be a very well designed a program, it would seem,
只是因为它的长度和混乱的机会之类的东西。
just because of the length of it and the opportunity to mess up and the like.
因此，在Python中，如果可能的话，这可能是现在的最Pythonic方式
So in Python, this is perhaps now, if you will, the most Pythonic way
做一些事情。
to do something some number of times.
确实，这是Python社区中的艺术术语。
And indeed, this is a term of art in the Python community.
长话短说，技术人员，程序员，
Long story short, technical people, programmers,
从某种意义上讲，他们倾向于非常虔诚
they tend to be pretty religious in some sense
当谈到做事的“正确方法”时。
when it comes to the "right way" of doing things.
实际上，在Python编程世界中，
And indeed, within the world of Python programming,
很多Python程序员确实有两种意见
a lot of Python programmers do have both opinions
而且还有规范的建议，这些建议决定了您应该如何“做”
but also standardized recommendations that dictate how you "should"
编写Python代码。
write Python code.
像这样的技巧被认为是Pythonic。
And tricks like this are what are considered Pythonic.
如果您正在用引号，取消引号进行Python操作
You are doing something Pythonically if you're doing it the quote, unquote
“正确的方法”，这绝对不是正确的，
"right way," which doesn't mean right in the absolute,
就大多数其他人而言，
it means right in the sense that most other people, rather,
在这种意义上同意你的看法。
agree with you in this sense.
好的。
All right.
在开始之前，让我们看一下Python的一些最终功能
Let's see a few final features of Python before we now start
建立我们自己的一些功能。
to build some of our own features.
回想一下，在C语言中，我们拥有整个数据类型列表。
In C, recall, we had this whole list of data types.
当然，还有更多，您可以创建自己的。
And there are more, and you can create your own, of course.
但是我们最初看过的原语
But the primitives that we looked at initially
是这些-bool，char，double，float，int，long，string等。
were these-- bool, char, double, float, int, long, string, and so forth.
在Python中，即使我不需要它们，
In Python, even though I haven't needed them,
因为我可以给自己一个像字符串或整数这样的变量，
because I can give myself a variable like a string or an int,
只要给它起一个名字，例如counter或i或answer，
just by giving it a name like counter or i or answer,
然后为它分配一个值，然后使用Python
and then assigning it a value, and Python
从您为其分配的内容中推断出应该为哪种数据类型，
infers from what you're assigning it what data type it should be,
Python确实有数据类型。
Python does have data types.
这就是编程中所知道的
It's just what's known in the programming
世界是一种松散的语言。
world as a loosely typed language.
在C语言世界中，C是一种强类型语言，
In the world of C, C is a strongly typed language,
在哪里，不仅存在类型，还必须显式地使用它们。
where, not only do types exist, you must use them explicitly.
在Python的世界中，您拥有所谓的
In the world of Python, you have what's called
一种存在类型的松散类型语言，
a loosely typed language, in which types exist,
但您通常可以隐式推断它们。
but you can often infer them implicitly.
负担不是由程序员来指定的
The burden is not on you the programmer to specify
这些数据类型不断。
those data types incessantly.
让计算机为您解决。
Let the computer figure it out for you.
这是我们C的清单。
So this is our list from C.
现在，这将成为我们在Python世界中的类似列表。
This now is going to be our analogous list in the world of Python.
我们将仍然布尔，对与错，
We're going to have bool still, True and False,
但是大写字母T，大写字母F。我们将要有浮存金，
but capital T, capital F. We're going to have floats,
是带小数点的实数。
which are real numbers with decimal points.
我们将要有整数，当然是负1这样的数字
We're going to have ints, which of course are numbers like negative 1,
0和1，依此类推。
0, and 1, and so forth.
然后，字符串本身不是字符串，而是“ stirs”。
And then not strings per se, but "stirs", S-T-R.
在C语言的世界里，从技术上讲，没有“字符串类型”
And where is in the world of C, there was technically no "string type"--
这是cs50库提供的功能，它使更多内容
that was a feature offered by the cs50 library, which just made more
可以使用char明星的想法-
accessible the idea of a char star--
回想一下C有字符串。
recall that C has strings.
它们被称为字符串，但是没有称为字符串的数据类型。
And they're called strings, but there's no data type called string.
您给自己一个字符串的方式，当然是在C语言中
The way you give yourself a string, of course, in C
是要宣布某人为char星。
is to declare something as a char star.
在CS50的资料库中，我们给了那个char星
And in cs50's library, we just gave that char star
别名，昵称，别名，称为“字符串”。
a synonym, a nickname, an alias, called "string."
在Python中，有实际的-
In Python, there are actual--
字符串有实际的数据类型。
there is an actual data type for strings.
简称为STR。
And for short, it's called S-T-R.
好的。
All right.
这么说，我们还有哪些其他功能
So with that said, what other features do we
我们可以在这里使用Python吗？
have from Python that we can use here?
嗯，还有其他数据类型
Well, there's other data types as well in
开始时实际上将证明超级有用的Python
Python that are actually going to prove super useful as we begin
开发更复杂的程序并做
to develop more sophisticated programs and do
语言甚至更酷的东西。
even cooler things with the language.
我们已经看到了范围。
We've seen range already.
严格来说，这是Python中的一种数据类型
Strictly speaking, this is a data type of sorts within Python
会给您返回一系列值，默认情况下为0，
that gives you back a range of values, by default 0 on up,
根据您提供的输入。
based on the input you provide.
清单，我一直在口头提及。
List, I keep mentioning verbally.
列表是Python中合适的数据类型，其本质类似于数组。
A list is a proper data type in Python that's similar in spirit to arrays.
但是在数组中
But whereas in arrays--
回想一下，过去几周我们一直非常重视
recall, we've spent great emphasis over the past few weeks
注意数组是固定大小的。
noting that arrays are a fixed size.
您必须预先确定该阵列的大小。
You have to decide in advance how big that array is going to be.
就像上周一样，如果您决定，哎呀，我需要更多的内存，
And like last week, if you decide, oops, I need more memory,
您必须为其动态分配更多空间，
you have to dynamically allocate more space for it,
复制值，然后释放旧的内存。
copy values over, and then free up the old memory.
就像，有这么多跳铁圈，可以这么说，
Like, there's so much jumping through hoops, so to speak,
当您想要在C中使用数组时，如果想要增大它们甚至缩小它们。
when you want to use arrays in C if you want to grow them or even shrink them.
Python和其他类似的高级语言为您完成了所有这些工作。
Python and other higher-level languages like it do all of that for you.
因此，列表就像一个自动调整自身大小的数组，
So a list is like an array that automatically resizes itself,
越来越大。
bigger and smaller.
现在，可以免费获得该功能的语言版本。
That feature now you get for free in the language, so to speak.
您不必自己实施。
You don't have to implement it yourself.
Python具有所谓的元组。
Python has what are called tuples.
在数学或GPS等环境中，您可能
In the context of like math, or GPS, you might
具有x和y坐标或纬度和经度坐标，
have x- and y-coordinates, or latitude and longitude coordinates,
就像逗号分隔的值一样。
so like comma separated values.
元组是用Python实现的一种方法。
Tuples are one way of implementing those in Python.
字典或字典。
Dict, or dictionaries.
因此，Python具有允许您存储键和值的字典。
So Python has dictionaries that allow you to store keys and values.
或者从字面上看，在我们的人类世界中，如果您在这里拥有人类词典，
Or literally in our human world, if you have a human dictionary here,
例如英语，很像物理形式的字典，
for instance for English, much like a dictionary in physical form,
可让您存储单词及其定义，Python中的字典，
lets you store words and their definitions, a dictionary in Python,
更一般而言，可让您存储任何键和任何值。
more generally, lets you store any keys and any values.
您可以将一件事与另一件事相关联。
You can associate one thing with another.
我们将看到这是一个非常有用且用途广泛的数据结构。
And we'll see that this is a wonderfully useful and versatile data structure.
最后，出于今天的目的，
And then lastly for today's purposes, there's
这些东西叫做集合，如果你从数学上回想起，
these things called sets which, if you recall from math,
集合是值的集合，例如a，b，c或1、2、3，没有重复项。
a set is a collection of values, like a, b, c or 1, 2, 3, without duplicates.
但是Python为您管理。
But Python manages that for you.
您可以将项目添加到集合中，也可以从集合中删除项目。
You can add items to a set, you can remove items from a set.
Python将确保您没有重复项，
Python will make sure that there are no duplicates for you,
并且它将为您管理所有内存。
and it will manage all of the memory for you as well.
因此，与此同时，我们在功能方面所拥有的只是一些熟悉的朋友。
So what we have in the way of functions, meanwhile, is a few familiar friends.
回想一下，在C语言中，我们使用了CS50库来获取字符，
Recall that in C we used the cs50 library to get chars,
双打，浮点数，整数，多头和字符串。
doubles, floats, ints, longs, and strings.
幸运的是，在Python中，我们不必担心双精度或多长时间。
In Python, thankfully, we don't have to worry about doubles or longs anymore.
一点点更多。
More on that in a bit.
但是几分钟前您看到我导入了Python的cs50库，
But the cs50 library for Python, which you saw me import a few minutes ago,
确实为您提供了一个名为get_float的函数。
does give you a function called get_float.
它确实为您提供了一个名为get_int的函数，
It does give you a function called get_int,
它确实为您提供了一个名为get_string的函数，
it does give you a function called get_string,
至少就本周而言，这仅仅是
that, at least for this week's purposes, are just
将使您的生活更轻松。
going to make your life easier.
这两个是训练轮，我们将很快将其起飞
These two are training wheels that we will very quickly take off
这样您最终只会使用本机Python代码，
so that you're only using native Python code ultimately,
而不是CS50自己的库。
and not CS50'S own library.
但是为了本周从C过渡到Python，
But for the sake of transitioning this week from C to Python,
您会发现这些会让我们放松之前的生活变得更轻松
you'll find that these will just make your life easier before we relax
并把它们拿走。
and take those away, too.
因此，在C语言中，要使用该库，您必须包含cs50.h。
So in C, to use the library you had to include cs50.h.
在Python中，您将再次继续导入
In Python, again you're going to go ahead and import
cs50，或更明确地讲，您可能要导入的特定功能。
cs50, or more explicitly, the specific function that you might want to import.
事实证明，有多种导入方法。
So it turns out there's different ways to import things.
他们最终实现了基本相同的目标。
They ultimately achieve essentially the same goal.
您可以使用类似这样的行来显式
You can, with lines like this, explicitly
一次导入一个函数，就像我之前使用get_string所做的一样，
import one function at a time, like I did earlier using get_string,
或者您可以一次导入整个库
or you can import the whole library all at once
简而言之，导入cs50。
by just saying more succinctly, import cs50.
这将影响我们此后必须使用的语法，
It's going to affect the syntax we have to use hereafter,
但您会在此处的示例中看到执行此操作的多种方法。
but you'll see multiple ways of doing this in our examples here on out.
您也可以简化一下，然后
You can also simplify this a bit, and you
可以从像我们这样的库中导入以逗号分隔的函数列表。
can import a comma separated list of functions from a library like ours.
这是一个惯例，我们也会经常看到。
And this is a convention we'll see quite frequently as well.
因为如果我们开始使用流行的第三方库编写
Because if we start using popular third-party libraries written
通过互联网上的其他程序员，他们通常会
by other programmers on the internet, they will very commonly
给我们很多我们可以使用的功能，
give us lots of functions that we ourselves can use,
我们将能够一个接一个地导入这些文件，
and we will be able to import those one after the other,
通过以这种方式在此处指定它们。
by just specifying them here in this way.
好的。
All right.
让我在这里暂停一下，看看是否对Python语法有任何疑问。
Let me pause here just to see if there's any questions on Python syntax.
就像，对于我们的Python语法速成班来说，基本上就是这样。
Like, that's essentially it for our crash course in Python syntax.
现在，我们将开始构建事物并探索Python的功能
We're now going to start building things and explore what the features of Python
是，有些细微差别是什么，实际上是Python的功能。
are and what some of the nuances are, and really the power of Python.
但是首先，对语法有任何疑问吗？
But first, any questions on syntax?
我们已经看到了循环，条件，变量。
We've seen loops, conditions, variables.
奥利维亚（Olivia），问题或评论。
Olivia, question or comment.
听众：在for循环中，如果您想增加1以外的值，
AUDIENCE: In a for loop, if you want to increment by something besides 1,
但是您不想显式地键入列表，您将如何处理？
but you don't want to explicitly type out the list, how would you do that?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
因此，如果您想使用for循环并在一系列值上进行迭代，
So if you wanted to use a for loop and iterate over a range of values,
但您希望该范围为0、2、4、6、8，而不是0、1、2、3，
but you wanted that range to be 0, 2, 4, 6, 8, instead of 0, 1, 2, 3,
让我继续，回到刚才的幻灯片。
let me go ahead and go back to that slide from a moment ago.
实际上，我可以即时更改此设置。
And I can actually change this on the fly.
让我进入这张幻灯片。
Let me go into that slide, which was right here.
实际上，我可以做的是指定另一个值，可能是这个。
And what I can do, actually, is specify another value, which might be this.
如果我将输入范围更改为不是一个值而是两个值，
If I change the input to range to be not one value but two values,
这将是计算机的一个线索
that's going to be a clue to the computer
它应该计算总共三个值，
that it should count a total of three values,
但是它应该一次增加2，而不是默认值1。
but it should increment 2 at a time instead of the default, which is 1.
那里甚至还有其他功能。
And there's even other capabilities there, too.
您不必从0开始计数。
You don't have to start counting at 0.
您也可以调整它，也就是说，使用Python，您可以
You can adjust that as well, which is to say that with Python, you're
会发现该语言附带更多功能，
going to find a lot more features come with the language,
甚至更强大的功能，您可以编写
and even more powerfully, the functions that you can write
以及您可以在Python中使用的功能
and the functions that you can use in Python
也可以采用不同数量的参数。
also can take different numbers of arguments.
有时为0，有时为1，有时为2。
Sometimes it's 0, sometimes it's 1, sometimes it's 2.
但这最终往往取决于您。
But it's ultimately often up to you.
接得好。
Good catch.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
听众：我们会主要在for循环中看到序列吗？
AUDIENCE: Will we see sequences primarily in the for loops?
还是还有其他非常有用的应用程序？
Or are there other applications where they're very useful?
DAVID MALAN：序列的含义是什么？
DAVID MALAN: Sequences in what sense?
在范围或列表的意义上还是其他？
In the sense of ranges or lists or something else?
听众：是的，特别是在范围上。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, in terms of ranges, specifically.
戴维·马兰：好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
我们会在其他情况下使用它们吗？
Will we use them in other contexts?
一般来说，这是非常罕见的。
Generally speaking, it's pretty rare.
我的意思是，我现在正在为其他用例而绞尽脑汁
I mean, I'm racking my brain now as to other use cases
我用过的范围。
that I have used range for.
而且我确信我可以提出一些建议。
And I'm sure I could come up with something.
但是我认为，最常见的情况是在迭代的背景下，
But I think hands down, the most common case is in the context of iteration,
如在for循环中。
as in a for loop.
我会考虑使用它来查看其他应用程序。
And I'll think on that to see other applications.
但是任何时候您想要生成一长串值
But any time you want to generate a long list of values
遵循某种模式，无论是0、1、2还是Olivia指出，
that follow some pattern, whether it's 0, 1, 2, or as Olivia points out,
一定范围内的值与范围，范围将允许
a range of values with gaps, range will allow
您可以避免完全对其进行硬编码。
you to avoid having to hardcode it entirely.
实际上，您可以编写自己的生成器函数，可以这么说，
And you can actually write your own generator function, so to speak,
返回所需值的任何模式的函数。
a function that returns whatever pattern of values that you want.
还有其他疑问或困惑吗？
Other questions or confusion?
Brian，无论您是聊天还是其他人，对您有好处吗？
Anything on your end, Brian, from the chat or beyond?
布莱恩：看来所有问题都在这里回答了。
BRIAN: Looks like all the questions are answered here.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
好吧，让我们继续吧，做一些更有趣的事情
Well, let's go ahead now and do something more interesting
比你好，世界。
than hello, world.
因为毕竟这是编程真正有趣的地方，
Because after all, this is where programming really gets fun,
当你和我不再
really gets powerful, when you and I no longer
必须在何时实施这些低级实施细节
have to implement those low-level implementation details, when
您必须为哈希表实现内存管理，
you had to implement memory management for your hash table,
或用于链表的内存管理，或在数组中复制值。
or memory management for a linked list, or copying values in an array.
在过去的几周中，我们专注于
We've spent the past several weeks focusing really
在一些有助于理解的低级基元上，
on some low-level primitives that are useful to understand,
但是他们写的不好玩。
but they're not fun to write.
我也承认，以问题集的形式写书可能并不有趣。
And I concede that they might not be fun to write in problem set form.
在以后的生活中，写作肯定不会很有趣，
And they're certainly not going to be fun to write for the rest of your life,
每次您只想编写代码来解决一些问题。
every time you want to just write code to solve some problem.
但是，那又是库进入的地方。
But again, that's where libraries come in.
现在，这就是其他语言的用武之地。
And now, this is where other languages come in.
事实证明，Python更好，更简单
It turns out that Python is a much better, a much easier
用于解决某些类型问题的语言，
language to use for solving certain types of problems,
其中有一些我们在过去的习题集中一直在解决的问题。
among them some of the problems we have been solving in past problems sets.
因此，实际上，让我继续执行此操作。
So in fact, let me go ahead and do this.
我要继续在这里抓文件-
I'm going to go ahead and grab a file here--
给我片刻-
give me one moment--
名为bridge.bmp，您可能会从过去的问题集中回忆起它。
called bridge.bmp, which you might recall from a past problem set.
这是马萨诸塞州剑桥市查尔斯河旁美丽的Weeks桥
This is the beautiful Weeks bridge down by the Charles River in Cambridge, Mass
由哈佛。
by Harvard.
这是CS50的一名团队成员拍摄的非常清晰的照片。
And this is a very clear photograph taken by one of CS50's team members.
当然，最近几周，您编写了代码
And in recent weeks, of course, you wrote code
进行此图像的各种变异，其中包括使图像模糊。
to do all sorts of mutations of this image, among them blurring the image.
我敢说，模糊不是最容易解决的问题。
And blur, I dare say, was not the easiest problem to solve.
您必须向上，向下，向左和向右查找平均值
You had to look up, down, left, and right, sort of average
所有这些像素。
all of those pixels.
您必须了解如何一次将图像表示为一个像素。
You had to understand how an image is represented one pixel at a time.
所以那里有很多低级细节，当一天结束时，
So there's a lot of low-level minutia there, when at the end of the day,
您要做的只是模糊图像。
all you want to do is just blur an image.
因此，在过去的几周中，我们不得不思考并写在较低的水平
So whereas in past weeks we sort of had to think at and write at this lower
级别，现在有了Python，事实证明我们
level, now with Python it turns out we're
将有能力在更高的抽象水平上进行思考
going to have the ability to think at a higher level of abstraction
并为自己编写更少的代码。
and write far less code for ourselves.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
我将为此使用Mac而不是CS50 IDE，
I'm going to use my Mac for this instead of CS50 IDE,
这样我可以更快地打开图像。
so I can open the images more quickly.
这就是说，即使我们继续
This is to say that, even though we'll continue
将CS50 IDE用于Python和其他语言
using CS50 IDE for Python and for other languages
在本课程的其余部分中，您还可以安装必需的软件
over the remainder of the course, you can also install the requisite software
在Mac，PC上，有时甚至是某种手机上
on a Mac, on a PC, sometimes even kind of sort of a phone
今天，您可以在自己的设备上使用Python并以其他语言进行浏览。
today, to use Python and sort of see, in other languages, on your own devices.
但是再次，我们倾向于在上课时使用CS50 IDE
But again, we tend to CS50 IDE during the class
以便拥有一个可以正常工作的标准环境。
so as to have a standard environment that just works.
所以我要继续写，
So I'm going to go ahead and write, though,
在我的计算机上，当然有一个名为blur.py，py的程序，
on my computer a program called blur.py, py, of course,
是Python程序的文件扩展名。
being the file extension for Python programs.
所以我的程序现在看起来有些不同。
So my program looks a little different now.
我有这个黑色和蓝色和白色的窗户。
I've got this black and blue and white window.
但这只是我个人Mac上的文本编辑器。
But this is just a text editor on my own personal Mac here.
我将继续执行此操作。
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我需要一些与图像相关的功能
I need to have some functionality related to images
为了使图像模糊。
in order to blur an image.
因此，我将继续从PIL库中进行导入，
So I'm going to go ahead and import from a PIL library,
枕头库，可以这么说，一个特殊功能
a Pillow library, so to speak, a special feature
称为Image，还有一个称为ImageFilter的特殊功能。
called Image and a special feature called ImageFilter.
也就是说，这些本质上是两个功能
That is to say, these are essentially two functions
在图像处理方面，有一个比我聪明的人写道，
that someone else smarter than me when it comes to image manipulation wrote,
他们在互联网上免费和开源地免费提供了他们的代码，
they made their code freely available on the internet free and open source,
这意味着任何人都可以使用该代码，现在我可以了
which means anyone can use the code, and I am allowed now
导入到我的程序中，因为我在上课之前就已经下载并安装了
to import it into my program, because I before class downloaded and installed
它事先。
it beforehand.
现在，我要继续执行此操作。
Now I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要给自己一个叫做before的变量。
I'm going to give myself a variable called before.
我将在bridge.bmp上调用Image.open。
And I'm going to call Image.open on bridge.bmp.
再说一次，即使我们之前从未见过，也从未使用过，
So again, even though we've never seen this before, never used this before,
您可以从句法上了解发生了什么。
you can kind of glean syntactically what's going on.
我左侧有一个变量，之前曾被调用过。
I've got a variable on the left called before.
我在右边有一个名为Image.open的函数，
I've got a function on the right called Image.open,
我传入的名字是bridge.bmp。
and I'm passing in the name bridge.bmp.
因此，这听起来像是C语言世界中的fopen。
So it sounds like this is kind of like fopen in the world of C.
现在注意，该点在这里起着新的作用。
Now notice, this dot is kind of serving a new role here.
过去，我们仅将运算符用于C中的结构，
In the past, we've used the operator only for structs in C,
当我们想进入一个人对象或一个节点对象时，
when we want to go into a person object, or into a node object,
我们想进入它并在其中访问一些变量。
and we want to go inside of it and access some variable therein.
嗯，事实证明，在Python中，您的精神与结构相似
Well, it turns out in Python, you have things similar in spirit to structs
在C中。但是，不只包含变量或数据，例如名称和数字
in C. But instead of containing only variables or data, like name and number
就像我们几周前对那个人的结构所做的一样，
like we did for the person struct a few weeks back,
在Python中，您可以在结构内部
in Python you can have inside of a structure
不仅是数据，即变量，还可以
not only data, that is variables, you can also
在结构内部具有功能。
have functions inside of structures.
这就开始打开各种可能性
And that starts to open up all sorts of possibilities
就可用功能而言。
in terms of features available to you.
看来我有了这个Image对象，这个Image结构，
So it seems that I've got this Image object, this Image struct that I've,
再次，是从别人那里进口的。
again, imported from someone else.
它的内部是一个期望的开放功能
Inside of it is an open function that expects
输入打开的文件名。
as input the name of a file to open.
因此，在今天的示例过程中，我们将越来越多地看到这种语法。
So we'll see this syntax increasingly over the course of today's examples.
接下来，让我给自己第二个变量。
Let me give myself a second variable, after.
现在让我继续并将其分配给名为
Let me go ahead now and assign to this variable called
在图像的过滤器函数之前调用的结果之后，
after the results of calling that before image's filter function,
传入1的ImageFilter.BoxBlur。
passing in ImageFilter.BoxBlur of 1.
现在，这有点神秘，我们不是
Now, this is a little cryptic, and we're not
将花时间在这种特定的语法上，因为赔率是，
going to spend time on this particular syntax, because odds are,
生活中您不会有太多想要的机会
in life you're not going to have that many opportunities to want
使要运行的图像模糊并编写代码。
to blur an image for which you're going to run and write code.
但是出于今天的目的，请注意，在我的before变量中，
But for today's purposes, notice that inside of my before variable,
因为我为其分配了此新功能的返回值，
because I assigned it the return value of this new feature,
它不仅具有数据而且还具有功能，其中之一
it has inside of it not just data but also functions, one of them
现在称为过滤器。
now called filter.
并且该过滤器函数将其他函数的返回值作为输入
And this filter function takes as input the return value of some other function
长话短说，它将使我的图像模糊
called that, long story short, will blur my image using
半径为1像素的盒子。
a box of a 1-pixel radius.
因此，就像您自己的代码一样，如果您在C语言中实现了模糊处理，
So just like your own code, if you implemented blur in C,
该代码将告诉我的代码向上，向下，向左和向右查找
this code is going to tell my code to look up, down, left, and right
并通过取像素周围的平均值来模糊像素。
and blur the pixels by taking the average around them.
就是这样。
And that's kind of it.
之后，我要执行after.save。
After that I'm going to do after.save.
我将其另存为out.bmp。
And I'm going to save this as out.bmp.
我只想创建一个名为out.bmp的新文件。
I just want to create a new file called out.bmp.
如果我没有犯错，请让我现在继续
And if I've made no mistakes, let me go ahead now
并运行blur.py的python，然后按Enter。
and run python of blur.py and hit Enter.
没有错误消息，因此通常是一件好事。
No error messages, so that's usually a good thing.
如果我现在输入ls，请注意我有bridge.bmp，
If I type ls now, notice that I've got bridge.bmp,
我已经打开过的，刚刚写的blur.py和out.bmp。
which I already opened, blur.py, which I just wrote, and out.bmp.
如果我继续打开open.bmp，让我们继续看看。
And if I go ahead and open out.bmp, let's go ahead and take a look.
这里是之前，这里是之后。
Here's before, here's after.
嗯
Huh.
之前，之后。
Before, after.
现在，通过互联网可能不会
Now, over the internet it probably doesn't
看起来很模糊，尽管在几英寸外的Mac上，
look that blurred, though on my Mac right here a few inches away,
它肯定看起来很模糊。
it definitely looks blurred.
但是，让我们做些更引人注目的事情。
But let's do it a little more compellingly.
怎么样，而不是向上，向下，向左和向右看一个像素，
How about, instead of looking one pixel up, down, left, and right,
为什么我们一次不看10个像素？
why don't we look 10 pixels at a time?
因此，我们通过查看更多的值和更多的平均值来模糊它。
So we really blur it by looking at more values and averaging more.
现在让我继续并运行blur.py的python。
Let me go ahead now and run python of blur.py.
现在让我继续并重新打开。
Now let me go ahead and reopen.
现在您可以看到之前和之后。
And now you see before and after.
之前和之后。
Before and after.
那么这是什么意思呢？
So what is this to say?
好吧，这是在四行代码中使图像模糊的问题集4。
Well, here is, what, problem set 4 in four lines of code blurring an image.
非常酷，非常强大。
So pretty cool, pretty powerful.
通过站在他人的肩膀上并利用他们的图书馆，可以
By standing on the shoulders of others and using their libraries can
我们很快就会做其他事情。
we do other things quite quickly.
注意，我在这里也可以解决最近的问题。
Notice what I can also do here, too, is solve a more recent problem.
让我转到另一个目录，我已经在该目录中了-
Let me go over to a different directory, where I have in advance--
您可以从课程的网站上下载这些文件，
and you can download these files off of the course's website--
我们在上课之前写的一些文件。
a few files that we wrote before class.
一个叫做speller.py。
One is called speller.py.
长话短说，speller.py是C语言的翻译
So long story short, speller.py is a translation from C
到Python中speller.c的代码。
into Python the code for speller.c.
回想一下，这是问题集5的分发代码的一部分。
Recall that that was part of the distribution code for problem set 5,
然后在speller.c中，我们现在将其翻译为speller.py。
and in speller.c, we translated it now to speller.py.
在字典和文字中，我们看到的是相同的文件，
And in dictionaries and in texts, we see the same files,
如习题集5，两个不同大小的字典和一整堆
as in problem set 5, two different sized dictionaries and a whole bunch
短文本和长文本。
of short and long texts.
尚未创建的相当于字典。c，又名
What hasn't been created yet is the equivalent of a dictionary.c, a.k.a.
现在，dictionary.py。
now, dictionary.py.
因此，让我继续并在Python中实现我的拼写检查器。
So let me go ahead and implement my spell checker in Python.
让我继续创建一个名为dictionary.py的文件，同样，
Let me go ahead and create a file called dictionary.py, as is again,
惯例。
the convention.
让我们继续吧。
And let's go ahead.
我们必须实现四个功能，对不对？
We have to implement four functions, right?
我们必须实现检查，加载，大小和卸载。
We have to implement check, load, size, and unload.
但是我可能需要一个全局变量来存储字典。
But I probably need like a global variable here to store my dictionary.
这就是大家都用指针实现哈希表的地方，
And this is where you all implemented your hash table with a pointer,
然后是链表和数组，所有这些都非常复杂。
and then linked lists, and arrays, and all of that, a lot of complexity.
你知道吗，我要继续给自己一个变量，叫做
You know what, I'm just going to go ahead and give myself a variable called
并将其声明为集合。
words and declare it as a set.
所以回想一下，集合只是值的集合
So recall that a set is just a collection of values
为您处理重复项。
that handles duplicates for you.
坦白说，这就是我真正需要的。
And frankly, that's all I really need.
我需要能够将所有单词存储在字典中
I need to be able to store all of the words in a dictionary
并把它们放到一个集合中，这样就不会有重复的值
and just throw them into a set, so that there's no duplicate values
我可以检查一下，是集合中的一个单词还是不是。
and I can just check, is one word in the set or is it not.
好吧，让我们现在继续并将单词加载到该集合中。
Well, let's go ahead now and load words into that set.
我将继续定义一个名为load的函数
I'm going to go ahead and define a function called load
需要打开文件的名称。
that takes the name of a file to open.
诚然，这里有一些新语法。
And here is some admittedly some new syntax.
到目前为止，我们仅在文件本身中键入了代码。
So thus far, we've only typed code into the file itself.
实际上，迄今为止最显着的差异是
In fact, the most striking difference thus far,
敢于说，关于Python与C，是我从来没有
dare say, about Python versus C, is that I have never
甚至曾经写过一个主要功能。
once even written a main function.
这也是Python的功能。
And that, too, is a feature of Python.
如果您要编写程序，则不需要
If you want to write a program, you don't
必须在名为main的函数中编写默认代码。
have to bother writing your default code in a function called main.
只需开始编写代码即可。
Just start writing your code.
这就是我们能够取得世界问候的方式
And that's how we were able to get hello, world
从C语言中的这么多代码行到Python语言中的一行代码。
down from this many lines of code in C to one line in Python.
我们甚至不需要main。
We didn't even need to have main.
但是，如果我想定义自己的函数，事实证明是在Python中，
But if I want to define my own functions, it turns out in Python,
您使用关键字def进行定义，然后输入函数的名称，
you use the key word def for define, then you put the name of the function ,
然后在括号中（如在C中），将变量的名称放入
and then in parentheses, like in C, you put the names of the variables
或您希望函数采用的参数。
or parameters that you want the function to take.
不过，您不必指定数据类型。
You don't have to specify data types, though.
同样，我们不使用花括号，而是使用冒号。
And again, we don't use curly braces, we're instead using a colon.
所以说，嘿，Python，给我一个叫做load的函数
So this says, hey, Python, give me a function called load that
接受一个称为字典的参数。
takes an argument called dictionary.
该功能应该做什么？
And what should this function do?
好吧，拼写器中加载功能的目的
Well, the purpose of the load function in speller
是要从字典中加载每个单词
was to load each word from the dictionary
并以某种方式将其放入您的哈希表中。
and somehow put it into your hash table.
我将继续进行相同的操作-从字典中读取每个单词
I'm going to go ahead and do the same-- read each word from the dictionary
并将其放入这个所谓的集合中，我的变量称为单词。
and put it into this so-called set, my variable called words.
因此，我将继续打开文件，我可以使用此功能
So I'm going to go ahead and open the file, which I can do with this function
这里。
here.
在Python中，您不使用fopen。
In Python, you don't use fopen.
您只需使用一个称为open的函数。
You just use a function called open.
我将把open的返回值签名到一个名为file的变量中。
And I'm going to sign the return value of open to a variable called file.
但是我可以说任何我想要的东西。
But I could call that anything I want.
这就是Python真正酷的地方。
This is where Python gets really cool.
回想一下从Python中读到的代码-
Recall that reading the lines from Python--
从C中的文件有点辛苦吧？
from the file in C was kind of arduous, right?
您必须使用fread或其他功能
You had to use fread or some other function
为了阅读一个又一个字符
in order to read character after character
字符之后，一次一行。
after character, one line at a time.
好吧，在Python中，如果我知道
Well, here in Python, you know what, if I
要遍历文件中的所有行，
want to iterate over all the lines in the file,
我们只说文件中的一行。
we'll just say for line in file.
这将自动给我一个for循环，
This is going to automatically give me a for loop that
为我将变量行分配给文件中的每个连续行。
assigns the variable line to each successive line in the file for me.
它将找出所有这些行的位置。
It will figure out where all of those lines are.
我想对每一行做什么？
What do I want to do with each line?
好吧，我想继续添加到该行中的单词集。
Well, I want to go ahead and add to my set of words that line.
就每个字而言-
Insofar as each word--
每行代表一个单词，我只想将其添加到全局变量单词中
each line represents a word, I just want to add to my global variable words
那条线。
that line.
那是不对的，因为那是什么
And that's not quite right, because what's
在文件中每一行的末尾？
at the end of every line in my file?
根据定义，我文件中的每一行都有一个反斜杠n，对吗？
Every line in my file by definition has a backslash n, right?
这就是为什么大词典中所有单词的原因
That is why all of the words in the big dictionary
我们给你每行一个。
we gave you are one per line.
那么，如何删除字符串末尾的新行呢？
So how do you get rid of the new line at the end of a string?
好吧，在C中，我的天哪，我们将不得不使用malloc进行复制，
Well, in C, my God, we would have to use malloc to make a copy,
然后将所有字符移开，然后将其缩短一点
and then move all of the characters over, and then shorten it a little bit
通过消除反斜杠
by getting rid of the backslash n.
嗯
Uh-uh.
在Python中，如果您要在字符串末尾删除新行，
In Python, if you want to strip off the new line at the end of a string,
只是做rstrip。
just do rstrip.
剥离字符默认情况下意味着剥离空白。
To strip characters means by default to strip off white space.
空白包括空格键，制表符和反斜杠n。
White space includes the space bar, the tab character, and backslash n.
因此，如果您想把每一行都扔掉
And so if you want to take each line and throw away
在末尾的尾随新行，您可以简单地说line.rstrip。
the trailing new line at the end of it, you can simply say line.rstrip.
这就是Python中字符串再次强大的地方。
And this is where strings again in Python are powerful.
因为它们是自己的数据类型，所以它们包含在其中，
Because they are their own data type, they have inside of them,
不仅是构成字符串的所有字符，而且还有功能，
not only all of the characters composing the string, but also functions,
就像rstrip从行尾开始剥离
like rstrip which strips from the end of the line
任何可能存在的空白。
any white space that might be there.
你知道吗，在此之后我想我完成了。
You know what, after this I think I'm done.
我将继续关闭文件，
I'm just going to go ahead and close the file,
我将继续并返回True。
and I'm going to go ahead and return True.
就是这样了。
So that's it.
那就是Python中的load函数。
That's the load function in Python.
打开字典，针对文件中的每一行
Open the dictionary, for each line in the file
将其添加到全局变量，关闭文件，返回True。
add it to your global variable, close the file, return True.
我的意思是，我非常确定我的代码可能是几行，并且当然
I mean, I'm pretty sure that my code is probably several lines, and certainly
很多小时，比您的代码可能要短
many hours, shorter than your code might have
也是为了实现这一点。
been for implementing that as well.
好吧，检查呢？
Well, what about checking?
也许复杂性就在别处。
Maybe the complexity is just elsewhere.
好吧，让我继续定义一个函数
Well, let me go ahead and define a function
称为检查，它以一个特定的单词作为输入作为其参数。
called check that takes a specific word as input as its argument.
然后，我将检查该给定单词是否在我的单词集中。
And then I'm just going to check if that given word is in my set of words.
好吧，事实证明在C中，您可能会
Well, it turns out in C you would probably
必须使用for循环或while循环，
have to use a for loop or a while loop, and you'd
必须遍历整个单词列表
have to iterate over the whole list of words
使用二进制搜索或线性搜索等加载的内容。
that you've loaded using binary search or linear search or the like.
gh，我已经过去了这么多星期。
Ugh, I'm so past that at this point so many weeks in.
我只是要说，如果一个字接一个字，请继续并返回True，否则返回
I'm just going to say, if word in words, go ahead and return True, else return
错误的。
False.
现在，这就是我对check的实现。
And that now is my implementation of check.
现在，这是一个小车。
Now, it's a little buggy.
我会解决这个问题。
And I will fix this.
有人发现了这个错误吗？
Does anyone spot the bug?
即使您以前从未见过Python，但花了数小时实施
Even if you've never seen Python before, but having spent hours implementing
您自己的支票版本，在逻辑上我缺少某些步骤吗？
your own version of check, is there some step I'm missing logically?
这里有一个错误。
There is a bug here.
有没有人发现我没有做什么，你可能
Does anyone spot what I'm not doing that you probably
检查字典中是否确实有给定单词时该怎么办？
did do when checking if a given word is in fact in the dictionary?
布莱恩：几个人对区分大小写发表评论。
BRIAN: A couple of people are commenting on case sensitivity.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，区分大小写。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, case sensitivity.
很有可能，在C中的实现中，您可能
So odds are, in your implementation in C you probably
将单词强制全部大写，或者将单词强制全部小写。
forced the word to all uppercase, or you forced it to all lowercase.
完全可行，但是您可能必须像对待每个角色一样做到这一点。
Totally doable, but you probably had to do it like character for character.
您可能不得不使用malloc复制输入，或将其放入
You might have had to copy the input using malloc, or putting it
变成一个字符数组，然后
into an array character for character, then
使用大写字母或小写字母将每个字母大写或小写。
using a toupper or tolower to capitalize or lowercase each individual letter.
像这样，呃，那将是永远的，确实如此。
Ugh, like, that would take forever, as indeed it might have.
因此，您知道什么，如果您想接受一个给定的单词并将其小写，
So you know what, if you want to take a given word and lowercase it,
只说一句话。
just say word.lower.
Python将负责所有这些迭代步骤
And Python will take care of all of those steps of iterating
在每个字符上，将每个字符都更改为小写，然后返回给您
over every character, changing each one to lowercase, and returning to you
新结果。实际上，我现在想，
the new result. And indeed, this now, I would think,
也与您在示例中所做的一致。
is consistent with what you did in your example as well.
好吧，尺寸呢？
Well, how about size?
好吧，在尺寸记忆中，您必须定义
Well, in size recall that you had to define
一个不接受任何输入但返回字数的函数
a function that doesn't take any inputs but returns the number of words
在这组话中。
in the set of words.
我将继续在这里-实际上，我
And I'm going to go ahead here-- and actually, I
我的邀请到这里了。
got my invitation slightly off here.
让我快速解决这个问题。
Let me fix this real fast.
如果您要返回字典的大小，
If you want to return the size of your dictionary,
或实际上是您集合中的单词数，
or really the number of words in your set,
您可以只返回该全局变量字的长度。
you can just return the length of that global variable words.
完毕。
Done.
最后，如果您要卸载字典，
And lastly, if you want to unload the dictionary,
让我继续卸货。
let me go ahead and unload things.
也不接受输入。
Doesn't take input as well.
老实说，因为我还没有做过等同于malloc的工作，
Honestly, because I've not done any equivalent of malloc,
我还没有执行任何内存管理-为什么？
I've not done any memory management-- why?
您不必使用Python
You don't have to in Python--
我可以在所有情况下都可以返回True，因为毫无疑问，我的代码
I can literally just return True in all cases, because my code is undoubtedly
正确，因为我不必理会指针，地址和内存
correct, because I didn't have to bother with pointers and addresses and memory
管理。
management.
因此，过去几周可能引起的所有压力
So all of the stress that might have been induced over the past few weeks
当您了解了内存管理的较低级别的详细信息时
as you understood the lower level details of memory management now
走开，不是因为它不在引擎盖下发生，
go away, not because it's not happening underneath the hood,
但是因为Python正在为您做这件事。
but because Python is doing it for you.
我确实在这里发现了一个错误。
And I did spot one bug here actually.
注意，我在这里有点陷入了C代码中。
Notice I kind of relapsed into C code here.
我在这里应该说的是它实际上是file.close。
What I should have said here is it's actually file.close.
所以在这里，当我关闭正在加载的文件时，我实际上必须调用file.close，
So here when I close the file in load, I actually have to call file.close,
因为现在该函数close与该变量相关联。
because now that function close is associated with that variable for me.
同样，内存管理也在发生。
So again, there is memory management happening.
Malloc和free或realloc都是为您而发生的
Malloc and free or realloc are all happening sort of for you
引擎盖下。
underneath the hood.
但是该语言在做什么Python
But what Python the language is doing for
您现在正在为您管理所有这些。
you now is managing all of that for you.
那就是通过使用所谓的高级语言获得的
That's what you get by using a so-called higher-level language instead
一种较低级的语言。
of a lower-level language.
您可以获得更多功能，在这种情况下，
You get more features, and in turn in this case,
您会为您解决所有这些问题，
you get all of those problems taken care of for you,
这样您和我就可以专注于构建我们的拼写检查器，
so that you and I can focus on building our spell checker,
这样您和我就可以专注于构建我们的Instagram过滤器，
so you and I can focus on building our Instagram filters,
而不是分配内存，复制字符串，大写字母和其他东西，
not on allocating memory, copying strings, uppercase and things, which
老实说，虽然这可能很有趣，而且第一次让我很满意
honestly, while it might have been fun and very gratifying the first time
你使那些事情起作用了，编程很快就会变成
you got those things working, programming would very quickly become
如果有的话，这是世界上最乏味的事情
the most tedious thing in the world if any time you
想要编写一个程序，您必须在这样的低级水平上思考和编写代码。
want to write a program you have to think and write code at that low level.
好的。
All right.
让我继续前进，真正跨过我没有在这里弄糟的手指，
Let me go ahead and really cross my fingers that I didn't screw up here,
并继续运行此代码。
and go ahead and run this code.
因此，我将继续运行speller.py的python--
So I'm going to go ahead and run python of speller.py--
坦率地说，我事先写过，因为就像分布
which, admittedly, I wrote in advance, because just like the distribution
拼写中的代码，我们为您编写了speller.c，我们事先编写了speller.py。
code in speller, we wrote speller.c for you, we wrote speller.py in advance.
但是，我们不会研究它的内部。
But we won't look at the internals of that.
我将继续进行测试，如何
I'm going to go ahead and test this on, how
关于莎士比亚这样的大事。
about something big like Shakespeare.
我将在这里用手指交叉。
And I'm going to cross my fingers here.
到目前为止，一切都很好。
And so far so good.
这个词有点飞过去。
The words are kind of flying by.
我将假设它们是正确的。
I'm going to assume they're correct.
希望我们能得到输出。
Hopefully we'll get to the output.
是的，是的，我想我在这里看到了一些熟悉的数字。
And it looks like, yeah, I think I see some familiar numbers here.
我有143,091个字。
I've got 143,091 words.
然后在这里，所涉及的总时间不到1秒。
And then down here, the total time involved was just under 1 second.
所以这真是太快了。
So that's pretty darn fast.
需要明确的是，我使用的是Mac而不是IDE，
And to be clear, I'm using my Mac instead of the IDE,
因此我的数字可能与云中的数字略有不同，但为0.9
so my numbers might be a little different than in the cloud, but 0.9
秒。
seconds.
但是出于好奇，您知道什么让我快速打开另一个标签，
But you know what, out of curiosity, let me open up a different tab real quick,
让我继续，从问题5开始拼写。
and let me go ahead and make speller from problem set 5.
因此，我提前带来了我们自己的拼写工具实施人员
So I brought in advance our own implementation of speller, the staff
解决方案，用C语言编写的dictionary.c和speller.c，
solution, written in C in dictionary.c and speller.c,
而且我刚刚用make对其进行了编译。
and I've just compiled it with make.
然后让我继续使用莎士比亚上的相同文字来运行./speller。
And let me go ahead and run ./speller using the same text on Shakespeare.
再说一次，我现在运行的是Python版本
So again, I just ran the Python version, now
我想使用人员的实现来运行C版本。
I want to run the C version using the staff's implementation.
好的。
All right.
哇。
Wow.
好吧，它飞得更快，快两倍。
All right, it flew by way faster, kind of twice as fast.
请注意，即使上面的数字相同，但时间却不同。
And notice, even though the numbers are the same up above, the times are not.
我的C版本花了0.52秒，所以花了半秒钟。
My C version took 0.52 seconds, so half a second.
我的Python版本花了0.9，或大约1秒。
My Python version took 0.9, or roughly 1 second.
因此，看来我的C版本更快，而我的Python版本则慢。
So it would seem that my C version is faster, my Python version is slower.
为什么会这样呢？
Why might that be?
因为如果我们花这么长时间都让我感到失望
Because I'm kind of disappointed if we just spent all this time
宣讲Python的优点，但在这里我们
preaching the virtues of Python, and yet here we
从某种意义上说，他们正在编写更糟糕的代码。
are writing worse code, in some sense.
圣地亚哥？
Santiago?
听众：可能是因为C即使水平很低，
AUDIENCE: Could it be because C, even though it's low level,
它明确地告诉计算机该怎么做，
it explicitly tells the computer what to do,
这样可以使其更快一点，而在Python中则可以
and so that makes it a little faster, whilst in Python it all
就像你说的那样，发生在引擎盖下面
happens like underneath the hood, as you were saying,
这样可能会使速度变慢。
so that could make it a little slower.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
在Python中，您有一个通用的解决方案
In Python, you have a general-purpose solution
关于内存管理和大小写的问题，
to the problem of memory management, and capitalization,
以及我们自己的所有其他功能
and all of these other features, that we ourselves
必须使用C来实现自己。Python具有通用实现
have to implement ourselves in C. Python has general-purpose implementations
所有这些。
of all of those.
但是使用其他人的代码来实现需要付出一定的代价
But there's a price you pay by using someone else's code to implement
所有这些东西都给你。
all of those things for you.
而且您使用语言的类型会付出更大的代价
And you pay an even greater price by using the type of language
Python在某种意义上是。
that Python is in a sense.
所以还有其他明显的不同
So there's been this other salient difference
在使用C和使用Python之间。
between using C and using Python.
当我编写C代码时，我将从源代码编译我的代码
When I wrote C code, I would compile my code from source code
变成机器代码。
into machine code.
并记得机器码是0和1的理解
And recall that machine code are 0's and 1's understood
由计算机的大脑，即所谓的CPU或中央处理器。
by the computer's brain, the so-called CPU, or Central Processing Unit.
每当更改源代码时，我们总是不得不编译我们的代码。
We always had to compile our code every time we changed the source code.
然后我们确实希望./hello运行该程序。
And then we did like ./hello to run the program.
但是到目前为止，在Python中的每个演示都没有使用过make或clang。
But every demo thus far in Python, I haven't used make or clang.
我没有使用./hello，而是使用python空格来命名程序。
I have used not ./hello, but rather python space the name of the program.
那为什么呢？
And why is that?
好吧，事实证明，Python通常被实现为
Well, it turns out that Python is often implemented as what
我们用口译员来描述。
we describe with an interpreter.
因此，Python不仅是我们一直在写的语言，
So Python is not only a language like we've been writing,
它本身也是一个程序。
it's also a program unto itself.
我一直运行的Python程序是一个同名程序
The Python program I keep running is an identically named program
理解Python语言。
that understands the Python language.
但是，发生的事情是，可以使用口译员，可以这么说，
And what's happening, though, is that by using an interpreter, so to speak,
要运行我的程序，您会产生一些开销。
to run my programs you're incurring some amount of overhead.
您要支付性能价格。
You're paying a performance price.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，回想起从第0周开始的计算机，
Well, computers, recall from week 0, at the end of the day,
只了解0和1。
only understand 0's and 1's.
这就是让他们打勾的原因。
That's what makes them tick.
但是我还没有输出0和1。
But I have not outputted any 0's and 1's.
我人类只是在写Python。
I the human have only been writing Python.
因此，我的Python代码之间需要进行某种翻译，
So there needs to be some kind of translation between my Python code,
以这种类似于英语的语法，将其转化为计算机本身可以理解的内容。
in this English-like syntax, into what the computer itself understands.
如果您不打算进行编译，
And if you're not going to go through the effort of compiling
每次进行更改时，您的代码，但是
your code every time you make a change, but instead
您将要通过解释器运行代码，
you're just going to run your code through an interpreter,
就像Python世界中的规范一样，
as is the norm in the Python world, you're
要付出代价，因为有人必须为您实现翻译。
going to pay a price, because someone had to implement a translator for you.
实际上，对此有正式的术语。
And in fact, there's formal terminology for this.
例如，在Python的世界中，
In the world of Python we have, for instance,
看起来更像这样的图片。
a picture that looks more like this.
而在C语言世界中，我们实际上将源代码作为输入
Whereas in the world of C, we would actually take our source code as input
然后输出，首先输出机器码，
and output, first machine code is output,
然后运行机器代码，到目前为止在Python的世界中，
and then run the machine code, in the world of Python thus far,
我正在编写源代码，然后立即运行它。
I'm writing source code, and then I'm immediately running it.
我没有事先将其编译为0和1。
I'm not compiling it into 0's and 1's in advance.
我相信这里有一个程序，恰好叫做Python，
I'm trusting that there's a program, coincidentally called Python,
他一生的目的是为我翻译代码
whose purpose in life is to translate that code for me
变成计算机可以理解的东西。
into something the computer does understand.
这实际上意味着什么呢？
And what does that actually mean in real terms?
好吧，这意味着如果我回想一下
Well, it means that if I were to think back
像这样的算法，可能对你们许多人来说都是个秘密
to an algorithm like this, which probably cryptic to many of you,
虽然不是全部，但可能是西班牙语算法
though not all, might be a Spanish algorithm
用于搜索某人的电话簿。
for searching a phone book for someone.
并且假设我一点也不说西班牙语。
And suppose that I don't speak Spanish at all.
理想情况下，我可能会将此程序，该算法编译成某种形式
I might, ideally, compile this program, this algorithm, into something
我确实通过使用将西班牙语翻译成英语的编译器来理解。
I do understand by using a compiler that translates Spanish to English.
像voila这样的英文版本，要更好地阅读和理解，
Like voila, this English version, much better reading and understanding this,
我可以很快地执行该算法，
I can execute this algorithm pretty fast,
因为我英文很好。
because I'm pretty good at English.
但是如果您只给我西班牙语版本的源代码，
But if you only give me the Spanish version, the source code,
并且您需要我逐行翻译或解释它，
and you require that I translate it or interpret it line by line,
老实说那真的会让我慢下来，
honestly that's really going to slow me down,
因为就像我必须像西班牙语字典一样
because it's like me having to go take like a Spanish dictionary
然后看每个字-
and look up every word--
“夺回圭亚那电信。”
"Recoge guia telefonica."
好吧，什么是“补偿”？
All right, well, what's "recoge"?
我必须查一下。
I have to look that up.
什么是“ guia”，什么是“ telefonica”？
What's "guia", what's "telefonica"?
哦好的。
Oh, OK.
拿起电话簿。
Pick up phone book.
知道了。
Got that.
第一步。
Step one.
第二步是什么？
What's step two?
“ Abre a la mitad de guia telefonica。”
"Abre a la mitad de guia telefonica."
因此，“向中间敞开”-好吧，等等，我不知道。
So "open to the middle"-- well, wait, I don't know that.
剧透
Spoiler.
“ abre”是什么意思？
What does that mean, "abre"?
好吧，让我查一下。
All right, let me look that up.
它的意思是“开放”。
And it means "open."
“ la mitad”，意思是“到中间”。
"A la mitad," that means "to the middle."
“电话簿”，“电话簿”。
"De guia telefonica," "of the phone book."
哦，这意味着“打开电话簿的中间”。
Oh, that means "open to the middle of the phone book."
所以，我很努力地在这里来回走动。
So I'm struggling to go back and forth here, clearly.
但这显然是一个较慢的过程。
But it's clearly a slower process.
如果我继续走，“ Ve la pagina”，“看看页面”，
And if I keep going, "Ve la pagina," "Look at the page,"
抬头看，翻译每一行，无疑
looking up, translating every line, it's undoubtedly
会减慢这个过程。
going to slow down the process.
因此，这实际上是我们正在发生的事情
And so that's effectively what's happening for us
当我们运行这些Python程序时。
when we run these Python programs.
可以说，有一个翻译，中间是一个人，
There is a translator, a man in the middle, so to speak,
在查看您的源代码并从上至下阅读它，
that's looking at your source code and reading it top to bottom,
从左到右，基本上分别翻译了每一行
left to right, and essentially translating each line respectively
转换为计算机可以理解的相应代码。
into the corresponding code that the computer understands.
因此，幸运的是，我们的好处是
So the upside of this is that, thankfully, we
不必运行make或clang。
don't have to run make or clang.
我们不必再编译代码了。
We don't have to compile our code anymore.
就像，这里有多少人做了改变
Like, how many people here have made a change
到C中的较早pset，忘记了保存文件，但是您重新运行了-
to an earlier pset in C, forgotten to save the file but you rerun the--
抱歉，您忘记了重新编译文件，然后重新运行它，
sorry, you forgot to recompile the file, and you rerun it,
而且程序显然没有改变
and the program obviously has not changed
因为您实际上并没有保存，而是重新编译了它？
because you haven't actually, not only saved but recompiled it?
这样，愚蠢而烦人的步骤就消失了。
So that stupid, annoying human step is gone.
在Python的世界中，如果您更改文件，请继续并重新运行它，
In the world of Python, if you change your file, go ahead and just rerun it,
重新解释它。
reinterpret it.
您可以保存该步骤。
You can save that step.
但是，您要支付的价格有些开销。
But the price you're going to pay is a little bit of overhead.
确实，我们在这里以我的Python版本来看
And indeed, we see that here in terms of my Python version
花大约1秒钟来拼写莎士比亚，
taking roughly 1 second to spellcheck Shakespeare,
而我的C版本只花了半秒的时间。
and my C version taking only one half of a second.
因此，在过去的几周中，我也曾承诺要权衡这一主题。
So here, too, I promised in past weeks this theme of trade-offs.
这在计算机科学和编程领域非常普遍，
This is so prevalent in the world of computer science and programming,
坦率地说，在现实世界中。
and frankly in the real world.
任何时候只要您有所改善或获得收益，
Any time you make some improvement or gain some benefit,
赔率是您付出了一些代价。
odds are you are paying some price.
也许是时间，也许是空间，也许是金钱，也许是复杂性，
Maybe it's time, maybe it's space, maybe it's money, maybe it's complexity,
也许还有别的。
maybe it's anything else.
存在这种资源的永久权衡。
There's this perpetual trade-off of resources.
最终，成为一名优秀的程序员是
And being a good programmer, ultimately, is
关于找到那些拐点并最终了解
about finding those inflection points and knowing ultimately
使用什么工具进行交易。
what tools to use for the trade.
好吧，让我们继续前进，休息5分钟。
All right, let's go ahead here, take a 5-minute break.
当我们回来时，我们将看看Python的其他功能，
And when we come back, we'll look at other features of Python,
我们最终将在今天结束时带来一些真正强大的功能。
we'll end ultimately today with some really powerful capabilities.
回到五。
Back in five.
好的。
All right.
我们回来了。
We are back.
首先，如果可以的话，我要退缩。
And first, a retraction if I may.
布莱恩（Brian）友善地指出，我对奥利维亚（Olivia）和诺亚（Noah）的后续问题的回答
Brian kindly pointed out that my answer to Olivia and Noah's follow-up question
不幸的是错过了分数，因为我是在忙着做事
unfortunately missed the mark, as I was doing things on the fly instead
阅读文档。
of reading the documentation.
因此，让我在这里为我们回顾一下这个例子，
So let me recall for us this example here,
其中，我们有一个range函数返回了三个值。
wherein we had the range function returning three values.
这样代码正确，我们得到的值分别为0、1和2。
So that code correct, that gives us the values 0, 1, and 2.
但是我认为奥利维亚（Olivia）问的是，如果您想跳过价值观，
But what I think Olivia asked was that if you wanted to skip values,
例如每两位数字，我们该怎么做？
and for instance do every two digits, how do we do that?
不幸的是，我为此搞砸了语法，
And I unfortunately screwed up the syntax for that,
仅提供两个范围内的输入，而不是三个，
providing only two inputs to range instead of three,
如此处所需。
as would be needed here.
例如，假设我们要打印
So for instance, suppose that we wanted to print out
0到100之间（包括0和100）的所有数字，
all of the numbers between 0 and 100, inclusive,
但彼此跳过-所以0、2、4、6、8等
but skipping every other-- so, 0, 2, 4, 6, 8, so all the even
最多可以有100个数字。
numbers on up through 100.
实际上，我们实际上想做这样的事情。
We would actually want to do something like this instead.
我们可以说，因为i在0逗号101逗号2的范围内。
We would say, for i in range of 0 comma 101 comma 2.
这是为什么？
Why is that?
好吧，我们稍后会整理文档，
Well, we'll pull up the documentation in just a moment,
但是0是您要开始计数的位置。
but 0 is where you want to start counting.
第二个值101是您要停止计数的位置。
The second value, 101, is where you want to stop counting.
但这是排他性的，所以我们有
But it is by definition exclusive, so we have
比我们关心的价值高1。
to go 1 past the value we care about.
然后第三个参数2是多少
And then the 2, the third argument, is how many
您想一次增加一个数字，从0到2到4到6到8，
numbers do you want to increment at a time, from 0 to 2 to 4 to 6 to 8,
直到100。
on up through 100.
所以我怎么能事先弄清楚
So how could I have figured this out in advance
而不是现在让自己尴尬？
rather than embarrassing myself now?
好吧，事实证明，这里有Python的官方文档。
Well, it turns out there is official documentation for Python.
我们将始终将其链接到您。
And we'll always link this to you.
这是最顶部的搜索框。
And here there is this search box at the very top.
您可以看到，在休息期间，我一直在搜索
And you can see that during the break I was searching
有关范围的文档。
for the documentation for range.
毫无疑问，如果我搜索范围文档，乍一看
And sure enough, if I search for the range documentation, at first glance
这似乎有点让人不知所措，因为
it might seem kind of overwhelming, because there's
在文档中对范围之类的东西有很多提及。
a lot of mentions of something like range in the documentation.
幸运的是，这里的第一个结果就是我们想要的结果。
Fortunately, the first result here is the one we want.
如果我单击该按钮，您会看到一些文档
And if I click on that, you'll see some documentation that's
乍一看有点神秘。
a little cryptic at first glance.
但是有趣的是这个范围
But what's interesting about this is that range
有两种不同的口味。
comes in two different flavors.
即使我一直称其为函数，
And even though I keep calling it a function,
从技术上讲，这就是所谓的课程。
technically it's what's called a class.
但是在另一时间。
But more on that another time.
就我们的目的而言，它表现为一种功能。
It behaves for our purposes as a function.
请注意，这里有两行。
Notice that there's two lines here.
它们相似但又不同。
And they're similar but different.
第一个指定此范围功能
The first one specifies that this range function
可以接受一个输入，即停止值。
can take one input, the stop value.
那么，您要停止计数的价值是多少？
So at what value do you want to stop counting?
因此，以前，当我们将范围设为3时，可以推断默认情况下，
So before, when we did range of 3, it stands to reason that by default,
如果您从0开始计数，然后从3停止，那将
if you start counting at 0 and you stop at 3, that will
让您使用i等于0、1和2。
get you to use i equals 0, 1, and 2.
但是范围函数还有另一种味道，
But there's another flavor of the range function, which
不是我提出的那个。
is not the one that I proposed exists.
还有另一个可能包含三个参数的地方，在这里
There's another that takes in potentially three arguments, here
或从技术上讲两个。
or technically two.
但是它以以下方式工作。
But it works in the following way.
当您在Python文档中看到类似这样的语法时，
When you see syntax like this in Python's documentation,
这意味着范围的替代形式
this means that the alternate form of range
接受一个叫做start的参数，然后跟一个叫做stop的参数，
takes an argument called start, followed by an argument called stop,
接下来是可选的第三个参数，称为step。
followed by, optionally, a third argument called step.
作为读者，我知道它是可选的，因为它在方括号中。
And I know as the reader it's optional, because it's in square brackets here.
因此，与列表或数组或类似内容无关。
So nothing to do with lists or arrays or anything like this.
这只是人工文档。
This is just human documentation.
每当您看到方括号中的内容时，
Anytime you see things in square brackets,
这倾向于向人类读者暗示这是可选的。
that tends to imply to the human reader that this is optional.
那是什么意思呢？
So what does that mean?
好吧，请注意，没有范围的味道
Well, notice that there is no flavor of range that
让我指定一个停止点和一个步骤，我认为这是片刻之前
lets me specify a stop and a step, which I thought there was a moment ago when
回答奥利维亚和诺亚。
answering Olivia and Noah.
而是有此三输入版本。
But rather, there is this three-input version.
因此，如果我指定我要从0开始，我想
So if I specify I want to start at 0, I want
停在101，刚好超过我所关心的100，
to stop at 101, which is just past the 100 I care about,
然后提供2的可选步骤
and then provide an optional step of 2, this
最终会给我一个程序，该程序将打印出来
will give me a program ultimately that will print out
所有这些偶数。
all of those even numbers.
因此，让我这样做。
So let me do this.
首先让我在这里进入一个程序。
First let me go into a program here.
我称它为count.py。
I'll call it count.py.
我将继续从0开始，直到但不超过101，
And I'm going to go ahead and start at 0, go up to but not through 101,
一次踩2。
stepping 2 at a time.
这次我要打印我。
And this time I'm going to print out i.
这也是Python的另一个便捷功能-
And here, too, another handy feature of Python--
没有更多的％s，也没有更多的％i。
no more %s, and also no more %i.
如果您要打印出名为i的变量的值，
If you want to print out the value of a variable called i,
只是说打印，打开括号，我，关闭括号。
just say print, open paren, i, close paren.
您不需要像C中一样的其他格式字符串。
You don't need another format string as in C.
现在让我继续并运行count.py的python，然后按Enter。
Let me go ahead now and run python of count.py, Enter.
它滚动得非常快。
And it scrolled by really fast.
但是请注意，它停止在100，并且如果我滚动
But notice that it stopped at 100, and if I scroll
到开始时，它从0开始。
to the beginning it started at 0.
因此，我深表歉意。
So my apologies.
Mea culpa较早将其弄乱了。
Mea culpa for messing that up earlier.
但是，这是介绍官方文档的绝佳机会
But what a wonderful opportunity to introduce the official documentation
对于Python，它将很快成为您的朋友，
for Python, which will soon become your friend,
乍一看似乎很神秘。
cryptic though it might feel at first glance.
好的。
All right.
让我们继续，然后重新访问另一个程序
Let's go ahead then and revisit one other program
是我们较早开始的。
that we started with earlier.
那个程序又是这个相对简单的Hello程序
And that program was again this relatively simple Hello program
在这种状态下我们放弃了。
that we left off in this state.
我们在Python中使用CS50库中的get_string函数。
We were using the get_string function from the CS50 library in Python.
我们有一个名为answer的变量正在获得回报
We had a variable called answer that was getting the return
该版本的get_string的值。
value of that version of get_string.
我们正在以某种方式打印“ hello”（逗号）。
And we were printing out "hello," comma, so-and-so.
而且我们正在使用该新的隐秘功能，但是很方便，
And we were using that new cryptic feature, but handy,
被称为格式字符串或f字符串，这仅表示替换所有内容
known as a format string or an f-string, which just means replace whatever's
用大括号括起来并带有实际值。
in curly braces with the actual value.
因此，让我们现在开始卸下训练轮
So let's start to now take off the training wheels
我们只是在一个小时前戴上了
that we just put on only an hour ago.
让我们摆脱CS50库。
Let's get rid of the CS50 library.
我们如何在不使用Python的情况下实际获得输入
How can we actually get input in Python without using
像CS50这样的人提供的图书馆？
a library from someone like CS50?
好吧，get_string不再存在。
Well, get_string no longer exists.
但值得庆幸的是，还有一个我们可以使用的函数，叫做输入。
But thankfully there is another function we can use called, quite simply, input.
输入是一个函数，与C和Python中的get_string非常相似，
Input is a function that, quite similar to get_string in both C and Python,
向用户提示一个短语，例如此处的“您叫什么名字？”；
prompts the user with a phrase, like this one here, "What's your name?";
等待他们键入一个值；当他们按下Enter键后，
waits for them to type in a value; and as soon as they hit Enter,
它会返回人类为您输入的内容。
it returns whatever the human has typed in for you.
因此，如果我现在继续执行并重新运行该程序，即hello.py的python，
So if I go ahead now and rerun this program, python of hello.py,
摆脱CS50库并使用输入代替get_string之后，
after getting rid of the CS50 library and using input instead of get_string,
我的名字是什么？
what's my name?
大卫。
David.
“你好，”逗号，“大卫”。
"Hello," comma, "David."
所以现在已经在那里，这是原始的原生Python
So already there now, this is raw, native Python
完全与CS50无关的代码。
code completely unrelated to anything CS50 specific.
但是，现在让我们继续前进，让我们最初继续使用CS50库，
But now let's go ahead, and let's keep using the CS50 library initially,
因为我们很快就会发现使用它的好处，
because we'll see that very quickly are there advantages of using it,
因为我们为您做了很多错误检查。
because we do a lot of error checking for you.
但是，我们最终也将完全取消这些训练轮。
But we'll eventually take those training wheels off entirely as well.
但是请注意，这样做确实相对简单。
But notice, indeed, how relatively simple it is to do so.
让我继续并打开我们预先编写的程序。
Let me go ahead and open up a program that we wrote in advance.
我将继续进行此操作。
And I'm going to go ahead and grab this.
与往常一样，可以在课程的网站上找到该文件。
This is available, as always, on the course's website.
我将继续打开一个名为additional0.c的文件，
And I'm going to go ahead and open a file called addition0.c,
这是我们之前真正见过的。
which we've actually seen before.
我要继续在这里做这个花哨的事情
And I'm going to go ahead and do this fancy thing here
稍后，我将在其中拆分窗口，以便
where, in just a moment, I'm going to split my window so
我一次可以看到两个文件。
that I can see two files at a time.
在这里，我将创建一个新文件，并将其命名为additioning.py。
And over here I'm going to create a new file, and I'll call this addition.py.
就是说，我只是暂时重新排列我的IDE
So that is to say, I'm just going to rearrange my IDE temporarily
今天，以便我们可以在左侧看到一种语言，C，然后
today so that we can see one language on the left, C, and then
Python中右侧的相应语言。
corresponding language on the right in Python.
同样，您可以在线下载所有这些示例
And again, you can download all these examples online
如果您想自己跟随。
if you'd like to follow along on your own.
因此，如果我要将左侧的程序翻译为右侧的程序，
So if I'm translating this program on the left to this program on the right,
让我们首先回顾一下左侧程序的实际操作。
let's first recall what the program on the left actually did.
这个程序提示用户输入x，提示用户输入y，
This was a program that prompts the user for x, prompts the user for y,
并且非常简单地对两者进行加法运算。
and quite simply performs addition on the two.
这是第1周的内容，可以追溯到现在。
So this is week 1 stuff, way back when now.
好吧，让我们继续翻译一下。
Well, let's go ahead and translate this.
我将使用CS50库中的get_int函数，
I will use the get_int function from the CS50 library,
因为这将使我的生活现在更轻松一些。
because it's going to make my life a little easier for now.
我要说的是从cs50 import get_int。
I'm going to say from cs50 import get_int.
我将继续使用，并从用户那里获取一个int
I'm going to then go ahead and get an int from the user using
get_int并提示他们输入x。
get_int and prompting them for x.
然后，我将从用户那里获取一个整数，提示他们输入y。
I'm going to then go ahead and get an int from the user prompting them for y.
然后，我将继续打印，例如，打印出x加y。
I'm going to then finally go ahead and, let's say, print out x plus y.
让我继续这里并运行additioning.py的python。
And let me go ahead down here and run python of addition.py.
现在提示我输入x，让我们输入1，y，让我们输入2，瞧，
I'm now being prompted for x, let's type in 1, y, let's type in 2, and voila,
3是我的程序在这里。
3 is my program here.
非常简单。
So pretty straightforward.
更少的代码行，因为其中之一，我没有这些不必要的代码
Fewer lines of code, because one, I don't have these unnecessary
包括stdio.h。
includes like stdio.h.
我没有花括号。
I don't have any of the curly braces.
公平地说，我没有任何评论。
To be fair, I don't have any of the comments.
因此，让我写评论。
So let me write comments.
在Python中，它将是一个不同的符号。
In Python, it's going to be a different symbol.
现在应在“提示用户输入x”前面加上一个井号，而不是//。
"Prompt user for x" should be prefixed with a hash symbol now instead of a //.
我将继续提示用户输入y，然后在这里执行加法操作。
I'll go ahead and prompt user for y, and then, how about here, perform addition.
但即使如此，它仍然很紧。
But even still, it's pretty tight.
仅有10行代码，其中有一些注释。
It's only 10 lines of code with some of those comments there.
好吧，那我可以做什么呢？
All right, well, what might I do that's a little bit different?
好吧，让我们卸下训练轮。
Well, let's take off the training wheels.
让我们卸下训练轮，摆脱CS50库
Let's take off the training wheels and get rid of the CS50 library
再次在这里获取输入。
again and get input here.
好吧，如果我继续在这里获得输入，在这里获得输入，
Well, if I go ahead and get input here, get input here,
将值分别分配给x和y，我现在要继续
assigning the values to x and y respectively, I'm going to go ahead now
并运行additioning.py的python。
and run python of addition.py.
x将再次为1，y将再次为2，答案当然是-
x will be 1 again, y will be 2 again, and the answer, of course, is--
12.
好吧，那是错误的。
Well, that's wrong.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
我怎么已经搞砸了这样一个简单的程序？
How did I screw up such a simple program already?
尽管对我来说是一种新的语言，Python。
Albeit in a new language for me, Python.
我在这里做什么？
What did I do here?
是的，本？
Yeah, Ben?
听众：因为实际上是把它当作两个字符串，
AUDIENCE: Because it's really taking it in as two strings,
所以只是将它们彼此相邻
so it's just putting them next to each other
而不是对它进行实际的数学计算。
as opposed to doing the actual math on it.
它没有像int那样读取它。
It's not reading it as in int.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
因此，输入，Python附带的此功能，
So input, this function that comes with Python,
确实类似于Cs50的get_string。
really is analogous to Cs50's get_string.
无论人类是什么类型，
No matter what the human types, it's going
返回为键盘输入字符或ASCII字符，
to come back as keyboard input characters, or ASCII characters,
或过去几周的Unicode字符。
or Unicode characters from weeks past.
即使它们看起来像数字，也不是
Even if they look like numbers, they're not
除非我们强制如此，否则将被视为数字（也称为整数）。
going to be treated as numbers, a.k.a., integers, unless we coerce them so.
现在请记住，在C语言中，我们具有将值从一个值转换到另一个值的功能。
Now remember in C, we had this ability to cast values from one to another.
强制转换是指将一种数据类型转换为另一种数据类型。
Casting meant to convert one data type to another.
我们被允许这样做，以便将char转换为int或将ints转换为char，
And we were allowed to do that for chars to ints or ints to chars,
但对于字符串到整数或从整数到字符串，您无法执行此操作。
but you could not do it for strings to ints, or from ints to strings.
为此，我们需要特殊的功能。
For that we needed special functions.
你们中有些人可能曾经使用过atoi，ASCII到int，
And some of you might have used atoi, ASCII to int,
这实际上是一个功能，可以查看ASCII中的所有字符
which was a function that actually looks at all of the characters in an ASCII
字符串并将其转换为相应的整数。
string and converts it to the corresponding integer.
坦白说，在Python中，它要简单一些。
In Python, frankly, it's a little simpler.
我们可以将它从一件事投射到另一件事。
We can just cast it from one thing to another.
所以我要继续进行并转换输入的返回值
So I'm going to go ahead and cast the return value of input
作为使用此，诠释。
as using this, int.
我将对y进行同样的操作，在此处传递输入的返回值
And I'm going to do the same for y, passing the return value of input there
将看起来像字符串的东西转换为-
to convert what looks like a string to what's--
看起来像int的东西实际上是int的东西。
what looks like an int to what's actually an int.
现在，让我继续执行附加操作，addition.py的python。
And now let me go ahead and perform the additions again, python of addition.py.
并注意这次，希望能达到Ben的观点，
And notice this time, hopefully to Ben's point,
正如我们所见，它不会连接两个字符串
it's not going to concatenate two strings, as we saw
当左右有两个字符串时，是默认的加号行为。
is the default behavior of plus when you have two strings left and right.
希望现在它将在x等于1，y等于2上做一个do加法。
Hopefully now it will do a do addition on x equals 1, y equals 2.
瞧，现在我们重新营业了。
And voila, now we're back in business.
但是，如果我不是最合作或最敏锐的用户，该怎么办？
However, what if I'm not the most cooperative or sharp user,
并输入x的“ cat”？
and I type in "cat" for x?
现在一些疯狂的事情开始发生。
Now some crazy stuff starts to happen.
因此请注意，我们在以下情况下触发了第一个错误
So notice we've triggered our very first error when
涉及到运行一个程序，而我的程序甚至不会
it comes to running a program whereby my program won't even
首先运行。
run in the first place.
并请注意，我在这里得到一些含糊的语法-
And notice I'm getting some somewhat cryptic syntax here--
追溯，最近一次调用，文件addition.py第2行。
traceback, most recent call last, file addition.py line 2.
好吧，至少是熟悉的。
All right, that's at least familiar.
我在2号线的某个地方搞砸了。
I screwed up somewhere on line 2.
它在这里向我显示了代码行。
It's showing me the line of code here.
并说“ ValueError-以10为基数的int无效的文字，猫。”
And it's saying "ValueError-- invalid literal for int with base 10, cat."
这是一个非常神秘的说法，我只是
That's a very cryptic way of saying I just
尝试将非整数的内容转换为整数。
have tried to cast something that's not an integer to an integer.
因此，这就是为什么我们使用CS50库之类的原因。
And so this is why we use things like the CS50 library.
编写所有代码实际上有点烦人
It's actually kind of annoying to write all of the code
检查并确保用户是否键入了一个数字，并且只键入了一个数字，
that checks and makes sure did the user type in a number and only a number,
而不是“ cat”或“ dog”或其他一些神秘的字符串。
and not "cat" or "dog" or some other cryptic string.
我们自己现在必须实施这种错误检查
We ourselves now would have to implement that kind of error checking
如果我们不想使用CS50库。
if we don't want to use the CS50 library.
因此，需要进行权衡。
So there, trade-off.
也许您自己编写所有代码感到更自在。
Maybe you feel more comfortable writing all of the code yourself.
您不想在互联网的图书馆中使用一些随意的人，
You don't want to use some random person on the internet's library,
无论是CS50还是别人的CS50，即使它是免费开放源代码。
whether it's CS50's or someone else's, even if it's free and open source.
您想自己写。
You want to write it yourself.
好的。
OK, fine.
如果你想自己写，现在我已经
If you want to write it yourself, now I've
必须添加更多代码行进行检查，
got to add a bunch more lines of code to check,
人类是一个接一个的十进制数字输入，还是他们
did the human type in a decimal digit one after the other, or did they
输入其他ASCII字符？
type in other ASCII characters?
同样，使用库之间的折衷并非如此。
So again, trade-off between using libraries are not.
通常，答案将是使用公共库来做-
Generally, the answer is going to be use a common library to do--
解决这类问题。
to solve these kinds of problems.
好吧，让我们继续进行一些更改。
Well, let's go ahead and change the program a little bit.
让我继续打开一个名为divation.py的新文件，
Let me go ahead and open a new file called division.py just
在这里做一些划分。
to do a bit of division here.
让我在右侧继续进行复制
And let me go ahead on the right-hand side and copy
粘贴我们之前所做的操作，但只需在此处更改为除法即可。
paste what we did before, but just change to division here.
让我继续将x除以y。
Let me go ahead and divide x by y.
我继续输入1代表x，输入2代表y。
And I keep typing in 1 for x, 2 for y.
稍后，我将运行Division.py的python并输入
In a moment I'm going to run python of division.py and type
x为1，y为2。
in 1 for x and 2 for y.
但是在我按Enter键之前，如果这是C语言程序，答案是什么？
But before I hit Enter, if this were a program in C, what would the answer be?
如果需要，请随时在聊天中回复。
Feel free to just respond in the chat if you'd like.
如果这是C语言中的程序，而我将x除以y，
If this were a program in C, and I'm dividing x by y,
从第一周开始，我每周会得到什么？
what would I have gotten in week 1 and every week since, Brian?
布莱恩：共识看起来像0。
BRIAN: The consensus looks like 0.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，因为被截断了。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, because of truncation.
如果将1除以2，则当然是1/2或0.5，则0.5是浮点数。
If 1 divided by 2, of course, is 1/2, or 0.5, 0.5 is a float.
但是，如果我正在处理整数，即使它是隐式的
But if I'm dealing with integers, even though it's implicitly
到目前为止的整数，现在我已经将其强制转换为整数，
integers thus far, and now explicitly now that I've casted them,
我似乎会丢掉0.5，然后又回到0。
I would seem to throw away the 0.5 and just get back 0.
但是让我继续运行python的division.py并将x等于1，
But let me go ahead and run python of division.py and putting x equals 1,
y等于2。
y equals 2.
哇，哇，这是C语言中最令人讨厌的功能之一，或者说缺乏功能，
And voila, wow, one of the most annoying features, or lack of features in C,
似乎是-
seems to have been--
在Python中似乎可以通过除以所需的方式来解决。
seems to have been solved in Python by division doing what you want.
如果您在Python中将一个整数除以另一个，
And if you divide one integer by another in Python,
事实证明，今天的语言还有其他功能之一
it turns out one of the other features of today's language
是它可以满足程序员的要求
is that it does what you the programmer would
无需花草就可以期待花车的细微差别
expect, without having to get into the weeds, of the nuances of floats
和整数。
and ints.
只是引用而已，请取消引用“正确的事情”。
Just does the quote, unquote "right thing" instead.
好吧，我还是从第一周开始在这里打开另一个程序。
Well, let me go ahead and open up another program here, also from week 1.
这被称为conditions.c。
This one was called conditions.c.
这一个-给我一点时间在左侧打开它-
And this one-- give me one moment to open this up on the left--
这是一个程序，其目的是生活
this one here was a program whose purpose in life
是要从名为x的用户那里获取一个int，然后再获取一个名为y的用户。
was to get an int from the user called x, get another called y.
然后它就这样做了-如果x小于y，则打印出尽可能多的内容。
And then it just did this-- if x less than y, print out as much.
否则，如果x大于y，则打印尽可能多的内容，依此类推。
Else if x greater than y, print out as much, and so forth.
让我们继续翻译这个程序
Let's go ahead and translate this program
使用我们已经看到的一些语法转换为相应的Python代码。
into the corresponding Python code using some of the syntax we've seen already.
我将继续并将其保存为conditions.py。
I'm going to go ahead and save this as conditions.py.
我想我要继续
And I think I'm going to go ahead and keep
使用该库，CS50库，以便我
using the library, the CS50 library, so that I
不必担心这些错误
don't have to worry about those kinds of errors
当向另一个输入错误的输入时。
when casting bad input to another.
因此，从cs50导入get_int。
So from cs50 import get_int.
让我继续，现在从用户那里获取一个int，称为x。
And let me go ahead and now get an int from the user, calling it x.
让我们继续从用户那里获取一个int，将其称为y。
Let's go ahead and get an int from the user, calling it y.
我不会为了时间的缘故而这次打扰评论。
And I won't bother typing comments this time, just for time's sake.
现在让我问一个问题。
And now let me ask the question.
在C语言中，如果x小于y，我会做的。
In C, I would have done if x less than y.
Python更加简洁。
Python's a little more terse.
如果x小于y就足够了，但是带有冒号。
If x less than y suffices, but with a colon.
在此之下，我将继续说“ x小于y”。
Under that, I'm going to go ahead and say print "x is less than y."
Elif-这很奇怪-
Elif-- this is the weird one--
x大于y，请继续打印“ x大于y”。
x is greater than y, go ahead and print out "x is greater than y."
然后，还有一个冒号，打印出“ x等于y”。
And then else, also with a colon, print out "x is equal to y."
我想就是这样。
And I think that's just about it.
我将继续在这里运行python的conditions.py。
I'm going to go ahead down here and run python of conditions.py.
我将输入1，将输入2，实际上x小于y。
I'll type in 1, I'll type in 2, and indeed x is less than y.
我将再次运行它，这次是2和1。
I'll run it again, this time with 2 and 1.
X大于y。
X is greater than y.
我再用1和1再次运行它。
And let me run it again with 1 and 1.
X等于y。
X is equal to y.
所以这似乎奏效了。
So that seems to have worked.
让我指出另一件事。
And let me point out one other thing.
我之前提到过，您还有其他速记语法，其中
I mentioned earlier that you have this other shorthand syntax where
如果您不想打扰，可以说导入CS50库
you can just say import the CS50 library if you don't want to bother typing out
各个函数的名称。
individual function names.
没关系的
That's totally fine.
但是请注意，IDE在第3行和第4行对我大吼大叫
But notice that the IDE is yelling at me at lines 3 and 4
该get_int不再被识别。
that get_int is no longer recognized.
那是因为Python支持此功能，
That's because Python supports this feature,
使用其他人的库时，它可以为您命名。
when using other people's libraries, that it can namespace them for you.
也就是说，您不能再直接引用get_int。
That is to say, you can't refer to get_int anymore directly.
您必须更明确地说，调用
You have to more explicitly say, call the get_int function that's
在CS50库中。
inside of the CS50 library.
同样，使用我们熟悉的点运算符，
And so again, using our familiar dot operator,
意味着像C结构一样进入该CS50库，
means go inside of that CS50 library, just like a C struct,
并在其中调用名为get_int的函数。
and call the function called get_int therein.
因此，我现在可以继续并重新运行此代码，即conditions.py的python，
So I can now go ahead and rerun this, python of conditions.py,
输入1和1，瞧，代码现在又可以工作了。
typing in 1 and 1, and voila, the code is now working again.
那么哪个更好呢？
So which is better?
这取决于。
It depends.
我的意思是，如果只写get_int更具可读性
I mean, if it's sort of more readable to just write get_int
到处都可以为您节省很多按键操作-您不需要
all over the place, that's going to save you a lot of keystrokes-- you don't
必须继续输入cs50点，cs50点。
have to keep typing cs50 dot, cs50 dot.
但是，如果您正在编写一个非常大的程序，
If, though, you're writing a pretty big program,
也许您正在使用两个都实现的不同库
and maybe you're using two different libraries that both implement
一个名为get_int的函数，您想成为
a function called get_int, you want to be
能够将彼此区分开。
able to distinguish one from the other.
因此，您可能只想按库的名称导入它们，
So you might want to just import the libraries by their name,
然后在函数调用前面加上前缀，就像我在这里所做的那样，
and then prefix the function calls, as I've done here,
这称为命名空间。
which is known as namespacing.
Namespacing意味着您可以拥有两个名称相同的变量
Namespacing means that you can have two identically named variables
或存在于两个不同名称空间中的函数。
or functions existing in two different namespaces.
只要它们在里面，它们就不会碰撞
They don't collide, so long as they are inside
CS50库的名称或其他库的名称。
of the CS50 library or some other library's name instead.
让我在这里根据条件做另一件事。
Let me do one other thing with conditions here.
让我继续，打开第一周的另一个文件。
Let me go ahead and open up another file from week 1.
这个人是同意的。c。
This one was agree.c.
并且该程序提示用户输入他们是否同意。
And this program prompted the user to input whether or not they agree.
我们好奇地检查了第一周是否使用等于
And we checked a little curiously that first week using equals
等于引号，不引号“ Y”或小写字母“ y”，或引号，不引号大写字母“ N”
equals quote, unquote "Y" or lowercase "y," or quote, unquote capital "N"
或小写的“ n”。
or lowercase "n."
好吧，我们如何进行转换呢？
Well, how do we go about converting this one?
让我继续，给我自己一个新文件。
Let me go ahead and give myself a new file over here.
在这种情况下，我称其为同意。
I'll call it agree.py in this case.
事实证明，我们可以通过几种不同的方式解决这一问题。
And it turns out we can solve this one in a few different ways.
让我继续，从CS50 get_int导入开始，
Let me go ahead and start off by importing from CS50 get_int,
只是因为-哦，不，get_string，而是因为它很方便。
just because it's-- oh, no, get_string, rather, because it's convenient.
让我继续通过get_string获取用户的输入
Let me go ahead and get the user's input via get_string
并问他们相同的问题，“您是否同意”，问号带有空格。
and ask them the same question, "Do you agree," question mark with a space.
然后让我检查一下。
Then let me check.
如果s等于引号，请取消引号“ Y”，或者s等于小写字母“ y”，然后
If s equals equals quote, unquote "Y" or s equals equals lowercase "y," then
我将继续打印“同意”。
I'm going to go ahead and print out "Agreed."
否则-哦，不，省略号等于大写字母“ N”
Else-- oh, no, elif s equals equals capital "N"
或s等于小写字母“ n”，让我继续在此处打印报价，
or s equals equals lowercase "n," let me go ahead and print out here quote,
取消引号，“不同意”。
unquote, "Not agreed."
我认为应该这样做。
And I think that should do it.
但是这里有些奇怪。
But something's weird here.
有一些区别。
There's a few differences.
是什么让您与C格格不入？
What strikes you as different from C?
您现在必须打破什么肌肉记忆
What muscle memory might you have to break now
当使用带有多个布尔表达式的条件时
when using conditions with multiple Boolean expressions
以这种方式结合？
combined in this way?
还有另一个微妙之处。
And there's another subtlety.
C和Python之间至少有两个明显的区别
There's at least two salient differences between C and Python
仅以这个例子为例。
with just this example alone.
在聊天中有任何想法或[听不清]？
Any thoughts in chat or [INAUDIBLE]?
瑞安
Ryan?
听众：我要说的是这个
AUDIENCE: I was going to say, for this one,
而不是将符号用于逻辑运算符，
instead of using the symbols for the logical operators,
您可以直接输入文字。
you can just type the text directly.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
我们可以从字面上键入英文单词“或”
We can literally just type the English word "or"
如果我们要表达逻辑或。
if we want to express a logical or.
因此，在C中，回想一下左侧，我们将完成此垂直条
So in C, recall on the left, we would have done this vertical bar
东西，这很好。
thing, which is fine.
你会习惯的。
You get used to it.
但这不是很可读，至少在任何英语意义上都是如此。
But it's not very readable, at least in any English sense.
Python采用了更频繁使用的方法
Python took the approach of using more frequently
实际上是从左到右阅读的实际英语或类似英语的单词。
actual English or English-like words that actually do read left to right.
实际上，这里正在出现一个主题。
And indeed, a theme is emerging here.
当您阅读Python代码时，它更接近英语
When you read Python code, it is closer to English
比起C来说，是因为您不会碰到太多的标点符号。
than C is, because you don't trip over as much punctuation.
每行Python代码都倾向于阅读更多内容
Each line of Python code tends to read a little more
例如英语短语或英语句子。
like an English phrase or an English sentence.
这里还有另一个微妙之处。
And there's one other subtlety here.
在第1周的左后方，我小心使用单引号
On the left back in week 1, I took care to use single quotes
在Ys和Ns周围。
around the Ys and the Ns.
这周我用双引号。
This week I'm using double quotes.
但老实说，这实际上并不重要。
But to be honest, it actually doesn't matter.
只要我保持一致，我也可以在任何地方都使用单引号。
I can alternatively use single quotes everywhere, so long as I'm consistent.
但是在Python中没有根本的区别
But in Python there is no fundamental difference
只要您保持一致，就可以在双引号和单引号之间进行选择。
between double quotes and single quotes, so long as you are consistent.
原因是，当我们查看C之间存在的数据类型时
The reason being, when we looked at the data types that existed between C
而现在，Python，没有出现在Python数据类型列表中的是char。
and now Python, absent from the list of Python data types was char.
在Python中，没有像单个字符这样的东西。
In Python there is no such thing as an individual char.
所有基于字符的内容都是一个字符串。
Everything that's character-based is a string.
即使只有一个字符长，也都是字符串。
Even if it's just one character long, everything is a string.
缺点是我们没有非常精细的控制。
Downside is we don't have quite as fine grained control.
好处是，这些字符串结构为我们提供了更多功能，
Upside is we get a lot more features with those string structures,
正如我们已经看到的，例如，做某事
as we've already seen with, for instance, doing something
就像那些大写字母一样。
like uppercase with those as well.
好吧，让我继续-
Well, let me go ahead and--
我想我可以简化一下。
I think I can simplify this.
例如，假设我想容忍类似“ Y”之类的东西
For instance, suppose I wanted to tolerate something like not just "Y"
或“ y”（大写或小写）。
or "y," in uppercase or lowercase.
假设我也想容忍大写或小写的“是”。
Suppose I wanted to also tolerate "Yes" in uppercase or lowercase as well.
好吧，您可以想象刚刚开始添加到代码中
Well, you could imagine just starting to add to the code
或s等于“是”，或s等于“是”。
or s equals equals "Yes," or s equals equals "yes."
但是请稍等，如果用户有点草率呢？
But wait a minute, what if the user is being a little sloppy?
如果我想说的真的好吗，如果他们大喊大叫怎么办？
And what if I want to actually say like, well, what if they're yelling?
或s等于在所有大写字母中均等于“ YES”。
Or s equals equals "YES" in all caps.
还有其他一些排列。
And there's a few other permutations as well.
就像，这很快演变成一团糟。
Like, this is quickly devolving into quite the mess.
但是如果在一天结束时，您真的只想检测“ Y”或单词
But if at the end of the day you really just want to detect "Y" or the word
“是的。”无论大小写如何，我敢打赌我们在Python中会非常聪明
"Yes," irrespective of capitalization, I bet we can be pretty clever in Python
这里。
here.
如果我继续说，如果s是带引号的，请取消引号“ y”或“是”怎么办-
What if I go ahead and say, if s is in quote, unquote "y" or "yes"--
实际上，我可以借鉴较早的想法，
in fact, I can borrow an idea from earlier,
借此我可以使用方括号符号来给我
whereby I can use the square bracket notation to give me
一个列表，它又像一个数组，但是它会自动增长
a list, which again, is like an array, but it will automatically grow
或根据需要收缩。
or shrink as you need it.
您不必事先决定它的大小。
You don't have to decide in advance how big it is.
这个介词是Python中的新关键字
This preposition here, in, is a new keyword in Python
从字面上可以为我回答这个问题。
that will literally answer that question for me.
而且我们之前已经使用过它。
And we've used it before earlier.
实施拼写检查时，我说如果单词在我的单词集中，请返回
When I implemented speller, I said if the word is in my set of words, return
真的。
True.
因此，如果s在此列表中，我将返回True或False
So if s in this list, I'll get back True or False
根据该问题的答案。
based on the answer to that question.
但同样，这是不能容忍的情况。
But again, it's not tolerating case.
但是没什么大不了的
But no big deal--
我可以说点小点是s的小写版本，
dot lower, now I can say, is the lowercase version of s,
无论人类输入了什么，在此两个值列表中？
no matter what the human typed in, in this list of two values?
这意味着用户现在可以输入所有大写字母，
That means now the user can type in all caps,
交替使用大写字母，一个大写字母或任何其他排列形式
in alternating caps, and one capitalized letter, or any other permutation
任何。
whatsoever.
好的。
All right.
因此，这就是我们的条件。
So that, then, is our conditions.
让我在这里暂停一下，看看是否有任何问题。
Let me pause here to see if there's any questions.
有什么问题或困惑可以解决吗？
Any questions or confusion that we can clear up?
具有语法，条件，布尔变量-
With syntax, with conditions, Boolean variable--
布尔值？
Boolean values?
布莱恩：所以提出了一个问题。
BRIAN: So a question came up.
因此，在Python中，我们允许使用equals equals语法
So in Python we are allowed to use the equals equals syntax
比较两个字符串？
to compare two strings?
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
因此，另一个非常好的收获。
So another really good catch.
在Python中，没有指针。
In Python, there are no pointers.
引擎盖下仍然有地址。
Underneath the hood, there are still addresses.
就像，您的记忆没有任何地方。
Like, your memory hasn't gone anywhere.
但是在幕后，所有这些现在都由该语言为您管理
But underneath the hood, all, of that is now managed for you by the language
本身。
itself.
因此，如果您想在概念上将一个字符串与另一个字符串进行比较，
So if you want to conceptually compare one string against another,
就像我现在在第7行所做的一样，您确实可以使用equals equals，
just as I did here now on line 7, you can indeed use equals equals,
Python将为您提供引用，为您取消引用“正确的事情”。
and Python will do the quote, unquote "right thing" for you.
您无需回归使用strcmp。
You don't need to regress into using strcmp instead.
为了清楚起见，让我继续进行更新。
Just for clarity, let me go ahead and update this.
如果引号较低，请取消引号“ n”或逗号“ no”，
If s.lower in quote, unquote "n" or comma "no,"
我们可以通过执行相同的技术来达到相同的结果。
we can achieve the same result there by doing the same technique.
好吧，让我继续讲一个例子
Well, let me go ahead and open up another example
您可能还记得我们做了一系列的例子
that you might recall we did a progression of examples
使它变得更好，更好，然后再好，这涉及
to make it good, better, and then best, this one involving
只是某种形式的猫叫声。
just a cat meowing in some form.
所以让我继续，从第一周开始
So let me go ahead and open up from week 1
一个相对简单的名为meow0的示例
an example that was called meow0, relatively straightforward, that
简单地做到了。
simply did this.
它只叫了三声。
It simply meowed three times.
现在就可以这么说了，在Python中，这是微不足道的
So suffice it to say now, in Python, it's pretty trivial
做三遍这样的事情。
to do something three times like this.
我将继续进行操作，并将其称为meow.py。
I'm going to go ahead and call this meow.py.
当然，我可以做类似打印“喵”的事情。
And of course, I can just do something like print "meow."
我可以复制粘贴。
And I can just copy paste that.
但是，当然，这个例子的全部要追溯到第1周
But of course, the whole point of this example back in week 1
不应只复制粘贴。
was not to devolve into just copy paste.
当然，有更好的方法。
Surely there's a better way.
这次我们看到了一种更好的方法。
And we've seen a better way this time.
如果我们想将其更改为C语言中的for循环，
If we wanted to change this into a for loop in C,
我们可以做一些类似的事情，因为int我得到0，我少于3，我++。
we could have done something like for int i get 0, i less than 3, i++.
然后在一些花括号中，我们可以完成
Then in some curly braces we could have done
“喵”的行，换行符，分号。
printf of "meow," new line, semicolon.
因此，这是C语言中喵代码的下一个版本。
So that was the next version of our meow code in C.
但是，在Python中，当然要简洁得多。
But in Python, of course, it's a little more succinct.
我可以为我做范围3的打印报价，取消报价“喵”。
I can just do for i in range 3 print quote, unquote "meow."
在精神上与我们之前的世界非常相似。
So very similar in spirit to our hello, world of before.
但是同样，我们不必为此包含任何库。
But again, we don't have to include any libraries for this.
我们不需要主要功能。
We don't need to have a main function.
我们不需要任何花括号或分号之类的东西。
We don't need any of those curly braces or semicolon or the like.
我们可以深入研究代码本身。
We can just dive in and focus on the code itself.
但是回想一下，我们上次也改进了喵程序
But recall that we also, last time, evolved the meow program
拥有自己的助手功能，我们自己的功能
into having our own helper function, our own function that
实际上允许我们在喵声之上创建一个抽象。
actually allowed us to create an abstraction on top of meowing.
那是我们的第三个版本，又叫喵喵。
And that was in our third version, a.k.a., meow2.
让我继续并在标签中打开此版本。
Let me go ahead and open up this version in a tab.
并请注意，这个版本开始涉及到一点点，因为
And notice that this version starts to get a little involved, because one,
我们需要顶部的原型，因为我现在
we needed a prototype at the top, because I now
在生活的最终目的中具有喵喵功能
have meow function at the bottom whose purpose in life
只是打印“喵”，而将其抽象化
was just to print "meow," but to abstract that away
作为新的辅助功能。
as a new helper function.
然后，我在此代码中包含了一个for循环。
And then I had this code here with a for loop inside.
好吧，在Python中，它在这里也会变得更加简单。
Well, in Python it's going to work out to be a little simpler here, too.
如果我想做三遍，因为我的范围是3
If I want to do something three times, for i in range of 3
继续叫喵。
go ahead and call meow.
现在，当然，喵并不存在。
Now of course, meow doesn't yet exist.
所以我可以解决这个问题。
So I can solve that problem.
我们在拼写法中早就看到了（尽管很快）
We've seen earlier, albeit quickly, in speller that I
可以定义我自己的功能，例如喵。
can define my own functions like meow.
没有更多的空虚，因为如果你不这样做
There's no more void, because if you don't
想要在函数中包含参数，只是不要将其放在那里。
want to have arguments in a function, just don't put them there.
在Python中没有指定返回值。
There's no return value specified in Python.
相反，它们是隐式的。
They're implicit instead.
这样就足够了。
So it suffices to do this.
现在，我可以打印出“喵”了。
And now I can just print out "meow."
所以现在在这里，我有一个程序迭代了三遍，
So here now, I have a program that iterates three times,
每次都调用喵，并且喵在下面定义。
calling meow each time, and meow is defined down below.
让我继续运行此程序，meow.py的python。
Let me go ahead and run this, python of meow.py.
嗯
Huh.
追溯，最近一次通话持续。
Traceback, most recent call last.
meow.py的第2行出现了一个问题，原因是NameError-name
There's a problem on line 2 of meow.py because of NameError-- name
“喵”没有定义。
"meow" is not defined.
现在，Python在此使用的语言与C有所不同。
Now, the language being used there by Python is a little different from C's.
坦率地说，它更加人性化。
It's frankly a little more human friendly.
但是到底发生了什么？
But what just happened?
出现了什么问题，直到现在我还没有绊倒？
What problem has arisen that I yet haven't tripped over until now?
即使您以前从未使用Python进行编程，
Even if you've never programmed in Python before,
即使您还没有运行help50，那里可能是什么问题？
and even if you haven't run help50 yet, what might be the issue there?
金妮
Ginny?
听众：这是我们尝试调用该函数时找不到的，
AUDIENCE: It's that the function is not found when we are trying to call it,
因为下面将在我们调用它时对其进行描述。
because it's described below when we are calling it.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
听众：没有原型。
AUDIENCE: There is no prototype.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，没有原型。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, there's no prototype.
事实证明，在Python中，没有原型的概念。
And it turns out in Python, there isn't a notion of prototypes.
不幸的是，我们在第1周看到的解决方案
So unfortunately, the solution we saw in week 1
不只是复制并粘贴上面的第一行
is not to just copy and paste the first line up above
并以分号结束。
and end it with a semicolon.
那不是什么。
That's just not a thing.
我可以做到的。
I could do this.
我可以将喵功能移到文件顶部，
I could just move my meow function to the top of the file,
从而首先定义函数，然后再使用它。
thereby defining the function first, and then using it last.
这实际上可以解决问题，“喵喵喵喵”。
And that would actually solve the problem, "meow meow meow."
当然，那从长远来看并没有真正帮助我们，
That, of course, doesn't really help us long term,
因为您可能会想象这种功能想要的情况
because you could probably imagine a situation where this function wants
调用此函数，但此函数调用此函数，
to call this function, but this function calls this one,
而且您无法以某种安全的方式真正整洁地订购它们。
and you just can't really neatly order them in some safe way.
而且它只是不会保持可维护性，对吗？
And it's just not going to be as maintainable, right?
回想一下，将main放在我们的C程序顶部的价值之一。
Recall that one of the values of putting main at the top of our C programs
是任何想要了解您的代码的理性人
was that any reasonable person who wants to understand your code
可能会开始从头到尾阅读。
is probably going to start reading top to bottom.
他们不需要浏览所有代码
They're not going to want to have to scroll through all of your code
寻找实际的主要代码。
looking for the actual main code.
所以事实证明，即使您不需要主要功能，也可以在Python中使用，
So it turns out in Python, even though you don't need a main function,
尽管如此，定义一个实际上是很常见的。
it's actually common to define one nonetheless.
它将通过类似这样的方式实现。
It's going to be implemented with something like this.
我只是在此处缩进代码。
And I'm just going to indent my code below that there.
所以现在我定义了main。
So now I've defined main.
但是我还没有执行任何代码。
But I haven't executed any code yet.
在第6行，我现在已经定义了喵，但是我还没有执行任何代码。
On line 6, I've now defined meow, but I haven't executed any code yet.
我的意思是从字面上看。
And I mean that literally.
如果我现在运行喵喵的python并按Enter，
If I run python of meow now and hit Enter,
我希望看到“喵喵喵”，但我什么也没看见。
I would hope to see "meow meow meow," but I see nothing.
这有点奇怪。
And this is a little weird.
但是Python实际上是按照我的指示去做的。
But Python is doing literally what I told it to do.
我告诉它定义一个名为main的函数，
I told it to define a function called main,
我告诉它定义一个叫做喵的函数。
and I told it to define a function called meow.
我从未告诉过它要做的是调用这些函数中的任何一个。
What I never told it to do is to call either of those functions.
因此，这里最简单的解决方案-与C稍有不同，并且有些怪异-
So the simplest fix here-- it's a little different from C and a little weird--
只是调用main是文件中的最后一个想法。
is just call main is your very last thought in the file.
因此，将main定义在顶部，这正是大多数程序员期望的位置，
So define main up at the top, just where most programmers would expect it to be,
但请一路打到底部。
but call it all the way at the bottom.
现在让我继续运行我的程序。
And let me go ahead and now and run my program.
现在瞧，“喵喵喵”又回来了，因为我定义了main，
And now voila, "meow meow meow" is back, because I've defined main,
我定义了喵，现在我叫main。
I've defined meow, and now I am calling main.
现在，顺便说一句，您会经常在各种文档中看到
Now, as an aside, you will very often see in various documentation
和在线教程比这更加神秘，
and tutorials online a much more cryptic incantation than this,
这将让您输入此内容。
which will have you typing out this.
这可以达到相同的目标，但并非绝对必要
This achieves the same goal, but it's not strictly necessary
为了我们的目的。
for our purposes.
如果您在任何在线参考资料或示例中都看到了这一行代码，
This line of code, if you see it in any online references, or examples,
或书籍，版面等
or books, or sections or the like, it is necessary
仅当您实施时，
only when you're implementing, essentially,
您自己的库-例如您自己的CS50库，
your own libraries-- like your own CS50 library,
或您自己的图像模糊库等。
or your own image blurring library or the like.
当我们只是编写自己的单个程序时，这是没有必要的。
It's not necessary when we're just writing individual programs of our own.
因此，我将继续进行操作，保持简单，从字面上讲就是main。
So I'm going to go ahead and keep mine simple and literally just call main.
让我挥舞一下为什么您否则需要该语法
And let me just wave my hand at why you'd need that syntax otherwise
在这种情况下。
in this context.
但是，让我继续进行最后一次修改。
But let me go ahead and modify this one last time.
因为记得在C中，我程序的最新版本
Because recall that in C, the last version of my program
让我运行喵并传递输入。
had me running meow and passing it input.
因为我将喵定义为接受n之类的输入，
Because I defined meow as taking an input like n,
然后做类似int的事情，我得到0，我小于n，i ++，
and then doing something like for int i get 0, i less than n, i++,
然后我在花括号内打印了喵声，
and then inside of my curly braces did I print meow,
所以现在我有了一个助手功能，需要一个
so that now I have a helper function that I've invented that takes one
输入，一个称为n的int。
input, an int called n.
它循环了很多次，并打印出了多次喵声。
And it loops that many times and prints out meow that many times.
现在我有了一个非常不错的抽象，现在我的程序已经精炼了，
And now I have a real nice abstraction, and that now my program is distilled,
它只有三声喵叫。
it's just meow three times.
而且我如何实现喵叫也没关系。
And it doesn't matter how I implemented meow.
我可以在Python中做同样的事情。
I can do the same thing in Python.
我可以继续说喵叫一个叫做n的参数。
I can go ahead and say that meow takes an argument called n.
我不必费心指定它的类型。
I don't have to bother specifying its type.
我现在可以说我在n范围内，并且我可以多次打印“喵”声。
I can now say for i in range of n, and I can print "meow" that many times.
现在我可以摆脱主循环了，只说三遍“喵”。
And now I can get rid of my loop in main and just say "meow" three times.
等等相同的功能。
And so same functionality.
如果我最后一次运行，“喵喵喵”，
If I run this a final time, "meow meow meow,"
但现在我有点以更复杂的方式设计代码
but now I'm kind of designing my code in a more sophisticated way
通过现在给自己一些实际的助手功能。
by actually giving myself now some of my own actual helper functions.
好吧，那么，关于这个进展有什么问题吗？
All right, any questions, then, on this progression?
现在，我们并没有真正看到新的Python语法。
Now, we're not really seeing new Python syntax.
现在，我们看到的是过去一些实际的C程序的翻译
We're now just seeing a translation of some actual past C programs
到Python中，以显示出真正的等效性。
into Python to show really the equivalence.
好的。
All right.
好吧，让我们继续，然后打开另一个版本
Well, let's go ahead, then, and open another version
从名为positive.c的程序的第1周开始，
from week 1 of a program called positive.c,
那时，这是一个机会，不仅是定义我们自己的助手功能
which was an opportunity back then, not only to define our own helper function
名为get_positive_int，但它也向我们介绍了
called get_positive_int, but it also introduced us
熟悉的do while循环。
to the familiar do while loop.
不幸的是，我们现在将把它从您手中夺走。
And unfortunately, we're going to take that away from you now.
Python没有do while循环。
Python does not have a do while loop.
但这当然是一件非常有用的事情
But it's, of course, a very useful thing to be able to do something
当条件为真时。
while a condition is true.
毕竟，几乎在我们上课的任何时候，
After all, pretty much any time we've gotten user input in the class,
我们已经使用了do，所以我们至少一次提示他们，然后可选地
we've used do while, so that we prompt them at least once and then optionally
一遍又一遍，直到他们合作。
again and again and again, until they cooperate.
因此，让我继续并在Python中实现它
So let me go ahead and implement this in Python
现在放在一个名为positive.py的文件中，然后再转到positive.py，
now in a file called positive.py, and go ahead here in positive.py,
并将其翻译如下。
and translate this thing as follows.
让我继续，从cs50导入get_int。
Let me go ahead and from cs50 import get_int.
让我继续定义一个名为main的函数。
Let me go ahead and define a function called main.
所以现在我要开始养成这个习惯。
So now I'm just going to start to get into this habit.
我要继续给自己一个变量，叫做i
I'm going to go ahead and give myself a variable called i
并调用get_positive_int。
and call get_positive_int.
然后我要继续打印我
And then I'm just going to go ahead and print out i,
保持美观和简单。
keeping it nice and simple.
现在，我必须实现get_positive_int。
Now I have to implement get_positive_int.
它不需要任何输入，因此我不会给它提供任何参数。
It doesn't need to take any input, so I'm not going to give it any arguments.
现在我必须做一件事情。
And now I have to do to do while thing.
因此，在Python中执行此操作的Pythonic方式几乎总是
So the Pythonic way to do this in Python is almost always
故意引起无限循环。
to deliberately induce an infinite loop.
想法是，如果您想一次又一次地做某事，
And the idea being, if you want to do something again and again,
只是永远地开始做，然后跳出循环
just start doing it forever and then break out of the loop
当你准备好了。
when you are ready to.
那么，我想在此功能中永远做些什么？
So what do I want to do forever in this function?
好吧，我想继续并获得一个int和提示
Well, I want to go ahead and get an int and prompt
人类为一个正整数。
the human for a positive integer.
然后，我想继续下一行并提出一个问题。
And then I want to go ahead on the next line and ask a question.
好吧，如果n大于0，从而使其为正，则中断。
Well, if n is greater than 0, thereby making it positive, break.
最后的代码行将返回n。
And the last line of code here is going to be to return n.
因此，请注意左侧的C，我做了整个事情。
So notice in C on the left, I did this do whole thing.
我必须在do while循环之外声明n，
I had to declare n outside of the do while loop,
因为它必须在花括号之外才能使用。
because it had to be outside the curly braces to be in scope.
但是在这里的Python中，请注意我在这里做什么
But in Python here, notice what I'm doing here
实际上有点不同。
is actually a little bit different.
我搞砸了吗？
And did I screw up?
哦，是的，我确实搞砸了。
Oh, yes, I did screw up.
好的。
OK.
如果询问实际问题，则n大于0。
If ask the actual question, if n greater than 0.
那么，我实际上在右侧做了什么不同的事情？
So what did I do actually differently here on the right-hand side?
好吧，注意，我故意引起了这个无限循环
Well, notice, I deliberately induced this infinite loop
在第10行上，这意味着永远做下面的事情。
on line 10, which just means, do the following forever.
然后，我用get_int向用户询问变量n，然后检查，
I then ask the user for a variable n with get_int, and then I check,
n是否大于0？
is n greater than 0?
如果是这样，请跳出循环。
If so, break out of the loop.
我该如何跳出循环？
How do I break out of the loop?
好吧，请注意，此处的缩进非常一致。
Well, notice that the indentation here has been very consistent.
因此，当我跳出循环圈时，这会让我退缩
So when I break out of the loop, that puts me back
与第14行的原始缩进一致。
in line with the original indentation which is now on line 14.
请注意，返回与while循环对齐，这意味着
Notice that the return lines up with the while loop, which means it's
该循环之外的第一行代码。
the first line of code that's outside of that loop.
在过去，我们会使用非常明确的花括号。
In the past, we would have had very explicit curly braces.
现在，我们仅依靠缩进，然后让我返回n。
Now we rely only on indentation that then lets me return n.
那么这里有什么区别呢？
So what are some of the differences here?
第一，do while循环完全消失了。
One, the do while loop is completely gone.
但是两个，范围不再是问题。
But two, scope is no longer an issue.
在Python中，您声明变量的那一刻，
It turns out in Python that the moment you declare a variable,
它存在直到该功能结束。
it exists until the end of that function.
您不必担心像我们这样先声明变量的细微差别
You don't have to worry about the nuance of declaring a variable first like we
在C中在这里做了，然后在下面将其返回。
did in C up here and then returning it down below.
我们在这里执行此行代码11的那一刻，n
The moment we execute this line of code 11 here, n
在该功能的其余部分中突然存在。
suddenly exists for the entirety of the remainder of that function.
因此，即使我们在循环内声明了它，可以这么说，
So even though we declared it inside of the loop, so to speak,
根据缩进，return语句仍然可以访问它
as per the indentation, it is still accessible to the return statement
在程序末尾。
here at the end of the program.
好的。
All right.
让我在那里停下来看看是否有任何疑问或困惑
Let me pause there and see if there's any questions or confusion
在获得用户输入方面，从逻辑上讲，与之同时做，
on getting user input, doing the equivalent, logically, of do while,
但是现在以这种更加Python化的方式进行。
but doing it now in this more Pythonic way.
彼得？
Peter?
听众：在Python中，变量是否可以跨函数访问？
AUDIENCE: In Python, are variables accessible across functions or no?
戴维·马兰：好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
不。
No.
因此，如果您在函数内部声明变量，
So if you declare a variable inside of a function,
可以说，它仅限于该功能。
it is scoped, so to speak, to that function.
它在其他地方不可用。
It is not available elsewhere.
您将必须返回它，并将其作为输出传递给输入。
You would have to return it and pass it as output to input.
或者，您必须将其定义为例如全局变量。
Or you would have to define it, for instance, as a global variable instead.
好的。
All right.
那么，我们还能翻译什么呢？
Well, what else, then, might we translate?
好吧，回想一下我们在第1周所做的早期工作
Well, recall from our earlier endeavors in week 1,
我们玩了Mario的这些例子。
we played around with these examples from Mario.
例如，我们想用Python打印出一些东西
And for instance, we wanted to print something out in Python--
在C中模仿这些金字塔或这些硬币的概念，
in C that mimics the notion of these pyramids, or these coins,
或屏幕上的这些小砖头。
or these little bricks on the screen.
好吧，让我继续打开一个名为mario.py的新文件。
Well, here let me go ahead and open up a new file called mario.py.
而且我要从始终显示之前和之后过渡
And I'm going to transition away from always showing the before and after
现在只是开始更多地关注Python代码。
and now just start to focus more on the Python code.
但是，如果您想要相应的C版本，则可以随时进行回顾。
But you can always look back if you wanted the corresponding C versions.
我该如何垂直打印出三块这样的积木？
How do I go about printing out three bricks like this vertically?
好吧，在Python中我可能会说类似的话，
Well, in Python I might say something like,
很简单，因为我们已经做过几次了，所以我在3的范围内，
for i in range of 3, quite simply, as we've done a few times already,
然后继续打印哈希值。
and just go ahead and print out a hash.
我不需要担心新的生产线，因为您可以免费获得它，
I don't need to worry about the new line, because you get it for free,
可以这么说。
so to speak.
但是我现在要继续并运行mario.py的python。
But I'm going to go ahead now and run python of mario.py.
瞧，这是我非常简单的ASCII版本的Mario结构。
And voila, there's my very simple ASCII version of this Mario structure.
但是，如果我想做硬币怎么办？
But what if I want to do the coins instead?
如果我要执行出现在这四个积木中的水平硬币怎么办
What if I want to do this horizontal coins that appear in these four bricks
并打印出一个版本？
and print out a version of that?
好吧，我该怎么做？
Well, how might I do that?
好吧，让我继续并将其更改为-
Well, let me go ahead and change this to be--
相反，在我的代码中，我的范围是4，因此我可以打印其中的四个。
instead in my code for i in range of 4, so I can print four of these things.
让我继续并打印一个问号，然后运行它。
Let me go ahead and print out a question mark and then run this.
因此，让我运行mario.py。
So let me run mario.py.
瞧，该死。
And voila-- damn.
喜欢，不是我想要的。
Like, not what I wanted.
权衡取舍就在这里。
And so here is that trade-off.
到目前为止，您可能会有些激动
You might have been kind of excited, so far
因为有可能对代码感到兴奋，哦，天哪，
as it's possible to be excited about code, that, oh, my God,
您无需再处理愚蠢的换行符。
you don't need to do the stupid new line characters anymore.
但是，如果您不想要该怎么办？
But what if you don't want it?
现在，我们发现自动获取这些新行的弊端。
Now we've kind of found a downside of getting those new lines automatically.
好吧，事实证明，如果我们阅读了有关打印功能的文档
Well, it turns out if we read the documentation for the print function
在Python中，它也可以采用多个参数。
in Python, it, too, can take multiple arguments.
而且，Python的强大功能还在于
And what's powerful about Python, too, is
它不仅支持位置参数，
that it supports not just positional arguments,
您只需在其中用逗号分隔一个函数的多个参数列表即可。
where you just do a comma separated list of multiple arguments to a function.
Python支持所谓的命名参数，从而
Python supports what are called named arguments, whereby
如果一项功能，特别是像打印这样的超级强大的功能，
if a function, especially one that's super powerful like print,
接受多个输入，例如此输入，另一输入和另一输入。
takes multiple inputs, like this one, this other one, and this other thing.
这些输入中的每一个都可以具有名称。
Each of those inputs can have names.
您，该函数的用户，可以指定名称。
And you, the user of that function, can specify the name.
事实证明，Python中的print支持一个称为“ end”的参数。
And it turns out that print in Python supports an argument called "end."
您可以明确地说出您想为该参数赋予什么值
And you can explicitly say what value you want to give to that parameter
提起它的名字。
by mentioning its name.
在这里，我将按照字面意思进行操作。
And here I'm going to literally do this.
我要告诉打印功能
I'm going to tell the print function that I
希望将“结束”的值，参数，参数作为引号取消引用。
want the value of "end," a parameter, an argument to it, to be quote, unquote.
这样做的原因是，如果我阅读了文档，
The reason for that is that if I read the documentation,
默认实际上是这个。
the default is actually this.
如果您阅读了文档，它将告诉您打印的默认值
If you read the documentation, it will tell you print's default value
因为它的结束参数是反斜杠n。
for its end argument is backslash n.
这也是C所没有的功能。
This, too, is a feature that C did not have.
C没有可选参数。
C did not have optional arguments.
他们在那儿或者不在。
They're either there or they're not.
相反，它们要么必须存在，要么不能在那里。
Rather, they either have to be there, or they cannot be there.
Python支持甚至具有默认值的可选参数。
Python supports optional arguments that even have default values.
因此，在这种情况下，根据文档的默认值，
And so in this case, the default value of this, per the documentation,
那个末端是引号，反引号反引号n，这是
is that end is quote, unquote backslash n, which
这就是为什么每一行都以该值结尾的原因。
is why every line ends with that value.
如果您想将其更改为空，
If you want to change that to be nothing,
所谓的空字符串，您将其更改为引用，取消引用。
the so-called empty string, you change it to quote, unquote.
因此，让我继续并立即运行此命令，瞧，更近一点。
So let me go ahead and run this now, and voila, closer.
看起来有点愚蠢，因为现在我的光标结束了-
It's a little stupid looking, because now my cursor ended up--
我的提示在同一行结束。
my prompt ended up on the same line.
因此，也许在这一行之后，让我继续进行，不打印任何内容，也就是说，
So maybe after this line, let me just go ahead and print nothing, that is,
新线。
a new line.
现在，如果我运行mario.py，瞧，现在就可以得到想要的效果。
And now if I run mario.py, voila, now I get the effect I want.
如果您想看看这里到底发生了什么，
And if you want to see what's really going on here,
我可以做一些愚蠢的事情，例如“ HELLO”。
I can do something stupid like "HELLO."
现在，我可以用“ HELLO”，“ HELLO”，“ HELLO”，“ HELLO”结束所有打印。
And now I can end every print with "HELLO," "HELLO," "HELLO," "HELLO."
并非您会那样做，仅此而已。
Not that you would do that, but that's all it means.
它结束了每次使用该表达式进行打印的调用。
It's ending every call to print with that expression.
但是，正确的版本当然只是以这种方式将其清除。
But the correct version, of course, is just to blank it out in this way.
但是这里有些很棒。
But here's something that's kind of cool.
如果您是个极客，这就是这里
And this is where if you're kind of a geek,
生活开始变得非常有趣。
life starts to get really interesting fast.
我实际上可以更改我的Python代码以打印出这四个问题
I can actually change my Python code to print out these four question
天空中的标记可以很简单地打印报价单，取消报价单问题
marks in the sky to be quite simply print quote, unquote question
标记时间4。
mark times 4.
现在，如果我重新运行该程序，繁荣就完成了。
And now if I rerun this program, boom, done.
再次在这里，您将获得该语言的许多功能
And here's where, again, you're getting a lot of features in the language
您无需考虑循环的地方，
where you don't have to think about loops,
您不必考虑很多语法。
you don't have to think about a lot of syntax.
如果您想打一个问号并重复四次，
If you want to take a question mark and do it four times,
您可以从字面上使用star运算符，
you can literally use the star operator, which
已被重载，不仅支持与数字相乘
has been overloaded to support not only multiplication with numbers
而且还可以通过这种方式自动连接字符串（如果愿意的话）。
but also automatic concatenation, if you will, with strings in this way.
因此，让我继续为马里奥做一个最终版本。
So let me go ahead and do one final version for mario.
回想一下，我们用马里奥打造的最后一件事
Recall that the last thing we built with mario
看起来有点像这样。
looked a little something like this.
让我继续，现在更改我的马里奥代码，使之适合我，范围为3，
Let me go ahead and change my mario code now to be for i in range of 3,
因为这是一个3 x 3的砖块，所以可以说。
because this is a 3 by 3 grid of bricks, let's say.
让我们继续，现在，在这个循环中，
And let's go ahead and now, inside of this loop,
进行另一个嵌套循环，在该循环中我也做三列。
do another nested loop where I do three columns as well.
在这里，我想一次打印出一个哈希值。
And in here, I want to print out a single hash at a time.
但是我不想打印新行。
But I don't want to print out a new line.
我只想在这里打印换行。
I only want to print out a new line here.
事实证明，这是因为Python为您提供了
So it turns out that essentially, because Python gives you
反斜杠n是自动的，基本上是任何逻辑
the backslash n's automatically, essentially any logic
您过去写的内容现在需要颠倒。
you wrote in the past now needs to be reversed.
如果您曾经打印过新行，现在就不想再打印新行了。
If you ever printed a new line, now you don't want to print a new line.
而且，如果您从未打印过新行，则从某种意义上说现在可以了。
And if you ever didn't print a new line, now you do, in some sense.
所以让我继续-
So let me go ahead and--
不正确，语言错误-mario.py的python。
not make, wrong language-- python of mario.py.
瞧，我的3乘3格。
And voila, my 3 by 3 grid.
这就是说在Python中，我们可以嵌套循环
So this is to say that in Python, we can nest loops, just
就像我们在C中所做的那样。我可以使用多个变量名，例如
like we did in C. I can use multiple variable names, like i
和j是常规的。
and j being conventional.
没有花括号，没有分号。
There's no curly braces, there's no semicolons.
但是，逻辑又是相同的。
But again, the logic, the ideas are still the same.
例如，它只需要一点时间就可以习惯
It just takes a little bit of time to get used to, for instance,
一些新语法。
some of the new syntax.
您会记得在C语言中，我们很早就遇到了整数问题。
You'll recall that in C, we ran into a problem pretty early on with integers.
让我在这里创建一个名为int.py的程序。
And let me create a program here called int.py.
然后让我将名为i的变量初始化为1。
And let me initialize a variable called i to 1.
让我继续做下去，直到永远。
And let me go ahead and do this forever.
让我永远做到这一点。
Let me do this forever.
而不是一会儿True块。
Instead of a while True block.
让我打印出我是什么。
Let me print out whatever i is.
然后让我继续，在每次迭代中给i加1。
And then let me go ahead and just add 1 to i on each iteration.
让我继续运行该程序。
Let me go ahead and run this program.
现在，让我增加窗口的大小，然后运行该程序即可。
And let me increase the size of my window for now and just run this thing.
哎呀，那是马里奥。
Whoops, that was mario.
让我运行这个东西，即int.py的python。
Let me run this thing, python of int.py.
您会看到它的数量一直到无限。
And you'll see that it's counting up to infinity.
老实说，这将需要一段时间。
And honestly, this is going to take a while.
您知道什么比计数为1 /乘以2更快。
You know what's faster than counting by 1/ maybe multiplying by 2.
因此，让我继续乘以2。
So let me go ahead and multiply by 2 instead.
要杀死程序，就像在CI中使用Control-C一样。
To kill the program, just like in C I used Control-C.
这就是为什么我看到键盘中断的原因。
And that's why I see keyboard interrupt.
它尊重我要取消该程序的意愿。
It respected my wanting to cancel the program.
现在让我重新运行一下，只算非常大。
Let me rerun this now and just count really big.
即使互联网有点慢，
And even though the internet's being a little slow,
这就是为什么有点不稳定的原因，这已经是一个很大的数字
which is why it's a little shaky, that's a really big number already
如果我继续加倍我。
if I keep doubling i.
此时已经发生了什么
What would have happened already at this point
如果我使用C来实现此程序？
if I were using C to implement this program?
如果在CI中声明了一个名为i的变量，并且它是一个int，
If in C I declared a variable called i, and it was an int,
我不断地将它翻倍
and I kept doubling it, again and again and again
一次又一次，从字面上永远吗？
and again and again, literally forever?
有什么想法吗？
Any thoughts?
是的。
Yeah.
C. Joy会发生什么？
What would have happened in C. Joy?
听众：是的，我想它会崩溃的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, I think it would have crashed.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：它将崩溃吗？
DAVID MALAN: It would have crashed?
为什么？
Why?
听众：因为这会占用很多内存。
AUDIENCE: Because it would be taking much memory.
DAVID MALAN：好主意。
DAVID MALAN: Good thought.
因此它本身不会崩溃。
So it wouldn't crash per se.
会出问题。
Something would go wrong.
它不会崩溃。
It wouldn't crash.
因为它仍然是一个int，至少在C语言中，
Because it's still an int, and in C at least,
在典型的计算机上，它仍将占用32位或4字节。
it would still be taking up on a typical computer 32 bits or 4 bytes.
但说实话，该程序可能会开始打印0
But honestly, the program probably would have started printing 0
现在，甚至是负数。
by now, or even negative numbers.
因为回忆，C的局限性之一
Because recall, one of the limitations of C
是整数是有限大小的吗？
is that integers are a finite size--
只有32位或4个字节。
only 32 bits or 4 bytes.
这意味着如果您继续从1、2、4、8、16开始
Which means if you keep going from 1, 2, 4 8, 16,
一百万，两百万，四百万，八百万，
a million, 2 million, 4 million, 8 million,
依此类推，最终您将涉足数十亿美元。
and so forth, eventually you're going to get into the billions.
而一旦您越过20亿甚至40亿的门槛
And as soon as you cross the 2 billion threshold or maybe the 4 billion
阈值，如果使用带符号或无符号数字，它将变得太大。
threshold, if using signed or unsigned numbers, it's going to get too big.
您将有整数溢出。
You're going to have integer overflow.
但是在Python的世界中，整数溢出已经不复存在了。
But in the world of Python, integer overflow, not a thing anymore.
在Python的世界中，您的数字将
In the world of Python, your numbers will
扩大到您需要的大小。
get as big as you need them to get.
他们将自动为您解决此问题。
They will automatically address this problem for you.
不幸的是，浮点数不精确，仍然是一回事。
Unfortunately, floating point imprecision, still a thing.
因此，我之前只将1除以2。
So I only divided 1 by 2 earlier.
但是，如果我继续除以其他值，并查看了足够的小数点，
But if I continue to divide other values and I looked at enough decimal points,
不幸的是，我们仍然会遭受浮点不精确的困扰。
we would still suffer, unfortunately, from floating point imprecision.
但是，在Python的世界中，例如Java和其他语言，
However, in the world of Python, like in Java and other languages,
有图书馆，科学图书馆
there are libraries, scientific libraries
使您可以根据需要使用尽可能多的精度，
that allow you to use as much precision as you need,
或至少与您的计算机一样多的内存。
or at least as much memory as your computer has.
因此，这些问题也已经用更现代的语言更好地解决了
So those problems, too, have been better solved in more modern languages
而不是像C代码这样的开箱即用的东西。
than in something out of the box like C code.
但是，只要一次又一次地乘以那个数字，我就可以了，
But just by multiplying that number again and again was I able, then,
展示出比过去几周更大的数字。
to demonstrate much larger numbers than we ever saw in weeks past.
好吧，让我继续在这里做另一个程序，
Well, let me go ahead and do another program here,
这个叫做scores.py。
this one called scores.py.
这将是保持真实状态的一个例子
That's going to be an example of really keeping
跟踪分数，这是我们在课程的第2周初期所做的一个示例。
track of scores, which was an example we did early on in week 2 of the class.
在Python中，我将继续前进
And in Python, I'm going to go ahead and give myself
像这样的分数列表
a list of scores like this--
72、73和33--
72, 73, and 33--
再次，有趣地引用了我们的ASCII数字。
again, sort of a playful reference to our ASCII numbers.
但是在这种情况下，它们是测验分数-所以
But in this context, they're quiz scores-- so
两个OK测验分数和一种低测验分数，
two OK quiz scores, and one kind of low quiz score,
假设这些东西不超过100。
assuming these things are out of like 100.
但是请注意我使用的语法。
But notice the syntax I'm using.
Python中的方括号为我提供了一个列表。
Square brackets in Python give me a list.
我不必事先决定它的大小。
I don't have to decide in advance how big it is.
它本身不是数组，但是在精神上是相似的。
It's not an array per se, but it's similar in spirit.
但是它会自动增长或收缩。
But it will automatically grow or shrink.
而且语法甚至更简单。
And the syntax is even simpler.
假设我想在Python中平均这些分数。
Suppose I want to average these scores in Python.
我可以做这样的事情。
I could do something like this.
我可以打印出这些分数的平均值，例如-
I could print out that the average of these scores is, for instance--
然后我可以做这样的事情。
and then I could do something like this.
我可以将分数之和除以分数的长度。
I could do the sum of scores divided by the length of scores.
其中一些实际上已经是新的。
And some of this is actually kind of new already.
事实证明，在Python中，有sum函数将一个列表作为输入
It turns out in Python that there is sum function that will take a list as input
并将这些项目的总和返还给您。
and return to you the sum of those items.
而且我们已经看到了len函数LEN
And we've seen already there's a len function, L-E-N
告诉您列表的长度。
that tells you the length of a list.
因此，如果我将所有分数相加然后除以分数总数，
So if I add up all my scores and then divide by the total number of scores,
从定义上讲，这应该给我我的平均值。
that should give me by definition my average.
因此，scores.py的蟒蛇，瞧-
So python of scores.py, voila--
哎呀，我在这里做什么？
whoops, what did I do here?
啊，我搞砸了。
Ah, I screwed up.
坦率地说，这是意料之外的，但让我在这里尝试保存自己。
So unintended, admittedly, but let me try to save myself here.
那到底发生了什么？
So what just happened?
好吧，此错误消息有点含糊不清。
Well, this error message is a little cryptic.
它说：“ TypeError-只能将str串联，而不能将float串联到str。”
It says, "TypeError-- can only concatenate str, not float, to str."
长。
long.
简而言之，Python在这种情况下不
Story short, Python in this case does not
就像我尝试在左侧取平均弦的事实
like the fact that I'm trying to take a string, average, on the left
并在右边连接一个浮点数。
and concatenate to it a float on the right.
因此，有两种方法可以解决此问题。
So there's a couple of ways I can solve this.
而且，我们早些时候已经看到了基本的解决方案。
And we saw the fundamental solution earlier.
如果我在这里强调了这个表达
If this expression here that I've highlighted
从定义上讲，它是一个浮点数，但我希望它成为一个字符串，
is by definition mathematically a float, but I want it to become a string,
我可以告诉Python，将浮点数转换为字符串。
I can just tell Python, convert that float to a string.
就像有些人发现了itoa函数一样，
So much like there's the itoa function that some of you discovered,
与atoi函数相反
which is the opposite of the atoi function,
我可以使用Python（在这种情况下为float），
I can take in Python, in this case a float,
并将其转换为等效的字符串。
and convert it to a string equivalent.
因此，如果我现在运行scores.py，voila的python，我的平均值为59.333333。
So now if I run python of scores.py, voila, my average is 59.333333.
而且您已经看到了一些不精确的地方。
And you already see a bit of imprecision.
最后有一些舍入误差，这不是完美的三分之一。
There's some rounding error at the end there that is not a perfect one third.
但是我还有另一种方式可以做到这一点。
But there's another way I could do this.
而且有点难看。
And it's a little uglier.
但是我可以使用其中的F弦之一。
But I could use one of those f-strings.
我可以说，插入一个值
I could, say, go ahead and plug in a value
在这里，只需打印出用户的平均值即可。
here and just print out the user's average.
事实证明，在这些花括号内，
So it turns out that inside of these curly braces,
您不必只打印变量。
you don't have to print just variables.
您实际上可以放置整个编码表达式。
You can actually put entire coding expressions.
而且我鼓励您不要粘贴疯狂的冗长的代码行，
And I would encourage you not to paste crazy long lines of code,
因为它很快就会变得不可读。
because it's going to very quickly get unreadable.
在那时，您可能应该使用一个变量。
At that point you probably should use a variable.
但是在这里我可以继续并运行scores.py的python。
But here I can go ahead and run python of scores.py.
瞧-我又搞砸了。
And voila-- I screwed up again.
同样不是故意的，但是我可以解决这个问题。
Also not intentional, but I can fix this.
是的，我在开始时就缺少f来使它成为格式化的字符串。
Yeah, I'm missing the f at the beginning to make this a formatted string.
现在，如果我重新运行它，瞧，同样的答案。
And now if I rerun it, voila, same exact answer.
同样，我有多种方法。
So again, I have multiple approaches.
这里有第三个。
There's a third one here.
我可以做点什么-实际上，在这种情况下，我不需要str，
I could do something-- and actually, I don't need the str in that context,
因为现在如果它在格式字符串中，
because now if it's inside of a format string,
Python会假定我要自动将其转换为字符串。
Python will presume that I want to automatically convert it to a string.
很好。
So that's nice.
或者我可以将其排除在外，然后我可以说些什么
Or I can just factor this out, and I can say something
这样-给我一个称为平均值的变量，将其分配为等于该数学值，
like this-- give me a variable called average, assign it equal to that math,
然后打印出平均值。
and then print out the average.
同样，就像在C语言中一样，有很多不同的方法可以解决问题。
So again, just like in C, so many different ways to solve the problem.
而哪一个最好则取决于什么
And which one is best depends really on what
可能是最易读，最易维护或最容易做到的。
might be most readable, most maintainable, or easiest to do.
让我继续，现在动态添加一些分数。
Let me go ahead and add some scores dynamically now.
不用硬编码我的三个分数，而是
Instead of hardcoding my three scores, let
我问自己在整个学期的成绩。
me ask myself for my scores over the course of the semester.
从cs50开始，让我get_int，这样我就可以轻松获得一些数字。
From cs50 let me get_int, just so I can get some numbers easily.
让我给自己一个空的分数列表，其语法
Let me give myself an empty list of scores, the syntax for which
只是开括号，右括号，所以最初没有任何内容。
is just open bracket, close bracket, so nothing inside of it initially.
现在让我继续执行此操作。
And now let me go ahead and do this.
我给自己打三分
Let me get myself three scores--
也许现在该学期结束了。
maybe it's the end of the term now.
对于3范围内的我，让我继续并附加到分数数组中
For i in range of 3, let me go ahead and append to the scores array
不管get_int的返回值是什么样的。
whatever the return value of get_int is like this.
现在，我也可以通过多种方式做到这一点。
Now, this, too, I could do in a bunch of ways.
让我在这里摆脱它。
Let me get rid of this here.
哎呀
Whoops.
不，我们将其留在那儿。
Nope, we'll leave that there.
我可以通过多种方式做到这一点。
This I could do in a bunch of ways.
但是请注意我在做什么。
But notice what I'm doing.
我正在获取int，并且正在传递int的返回值
I'm getting int, and I'm passing the return value of int
到一个名为append的新函数中。
to a new function called append.
事实证明，列表，方括号，
It turns out that lists, the square brackets,
在将它们定义为诸如scores之类的变量后，
once you've defined them in a variable like scores,
它们也具有内置的功能。
they, too, have functions built into them.
因此，我可以执行scores.append以便将数字添加到列表中。
So I can do scores.append in order to add a number to the list.
因此，现在让我继续运行此程序，运行scores.py的python。
So now let me go ahead and run this, python of scores.py.
让我手动输入72、73和33。
Let me manually type in my 72, my 73, and my 33.
瞧，同样的答案。
And voila, same exact answer.
但是想想这会带来多大的痛苦
But think about how much of a pain this would
如果您必须决定使用C
have been in C, if you had to either decide
预先确定数组的大小，还是不预先确定
in advance the size of the array, or not decide in advance
并使用malloc和realloc使其不断增长和缩小。
and use malloc and realloc to keep growing and shrinking it.
Python，使用此附加函数，其中
Python, using this append function, which
进入该列表变量的内部，处理
comes inside of that list variable, handles
所有这些对我们来说都是自动的。
all of this automatically for us.
好的。
All right.
因此，这也是一堆功能。
So that, too, is a whole bunch of features.
但是，我有什么要回答的问题吗？
Any questions, though, that I can answer here?
任何问题？
Any questions?
不？
No?
是的，去圣地亚哥。
Yeah, over to Santiago.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
我有一个问题-
I had a question about--
因此，即使append减少了您必须编写的代码量，
so even if append reduces the amount of code you have to write,
它在引擎盖下是否恰好做了我们所要做的
does it underneath the hood just do exactly what we
用C做的，就像malloc和realloc之类的？
were doing in C, which is like, malloc and realloc, or something like that?
这就是全部-这是在Python内部发生的吗？
Is that all-- is that happening inside Python?
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: It is.
是的，这就是您免费获得的东西，
Yeah, that's exactly what you're getting for free,
可以说，用语言。
so to speak, with the language.
所有这些malloc的东西，realloc的东西，也许是
All of that malloc stuff, realloc stuff, maybe it's
用引擎盖下面的阵列实现，
implemented with an array underneath the hood,
就像在实际计算机的内存中一样。
like in the actual computer's memory.
也许是像我们上周看到的那样的链表。
Maybe it's a linked list like we saw last week.
但是所有这些都在为您发生。
But all of that is happening for you.
但这又是代码最终的原因之一
But that, again, is one of the reasons why the code ultimately
运行速度稍慢，因为您之间有其他人的代码
runs a little slower, because you have someone else's code in between you
而计算机中的CPU会为您完成一些工作。
and the CPU in your computer doing a bit of that work for you.
索菲亚？
Sophia?
听众：有效率差异吗
AUDIENCE: Are there efficiency differences
在我们打印的方式之间，利用f格式
in between the ways that we print, of utilizing the f formatting
还是我们使用的其他形式？
or the other forms that we've used?
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：如果我的理解正确，则不必如此
DAVID MALAN: You don't have to be-- if I'm understanding correctly,
它有一些花哨的功能。
there are some fancy features of it.
例如，您可以使用一些语法
For instance, there is syntax you can use
指定您想要多少个小数点
to specify how many decimal points you want
在浮点值之后打印。
to print after a floating point value.
但这不再是％i，％s，％f等的全部。
But it's no longer all of the %i, %s, %f, and so forth.
它们的语法略有不同，但幸运的是，
They're slightly different syntax, but fortunately less of it,
因为您不必担心这些约定。
since you don't have to worry as much about those conventions.
还有其他疑问或困惑吗？
Other questions or confusion?
不？
No?
好的。
All right.
好吧，让我继续做一个例子
Well, let me go ahead and do one other example that
在过去的几周内可能会很熟悉。
might be familiar from some weeks past.
让我继续讲一个简单的例子，只是
Let me go ahead and whip up a quick example of uppercasing, just
结合我们前面的例子之一
to tie together one of our earlier examples
我们更自然地看到了或降低了外壳。
that we saw more organically, or lowercasing.
在这种情况下，一个名为uppercase.py的文件。
In this case, a file called uppercase.py.
让我继续前进，从CS50库中，让我继续前进
Let me go ahead, and from the CS50 library, let me go ahead
并导入get_string。
and import get_string.
然后，有了这个，让我继续从用户那里获取字符串
And then once I have this, let me go ahead and get a string from the user
并要求他们输入“之前”。
and ask them for, "Before," for instance.
然后让我继续执行以下操作。
And then let me go ahead and do the following.
让我继续打印“之后”，目标是我
Let me go ahead and print out "After," the goal being I
想要为用户将整个字符串大写。
want to uppercase this whole string for the user.
我将把所有这些保持在同一行。
And I'm going to keep this all on the same line.
再说一遍，我想要一个可以打印“之前”的程序，
So again, I want a program that's going to print "Before,"
要求人类进行一些输入，然后，
ask the human for some input, and then after,
显示整个字符串的大写版本。
show the capitalized version of the whole string.
那我该怎么做呢？
So how can I do this?
好吧，我们已经看到了一种方法。
Well, we've seen one way already.
我可以按字面意思做，例如s.upper。
I can do literally, for instance, s.upper.
让我继续保存。
And let me go ahead and save this.
现在运行uppercase.py的python。
And now run python of uppercase.py.
现在让我以小写形式输入“ hi”，然后开始繁荣
Let me type in "hi" in lowercase, and boom, now
我得到了大写版本。
I get back the uppercase version.
但是如果您愿意，您实际上可以操纵单个字符
But if you want, you can actually manipulate individual characters
也一样
as well.
让我继续前进，然后进行一些更有趣的操作。
Let me go ahead and a little more pedantically do this.
对于c in s，打印c。
For c in s, print c.
现在，这还不是我想要的，但这是一个垫脚石。
Now, this isn't quite what I want yet, but it's a stepping stone.
现在注意，如果我以小写形式输入“ hi”，
Notice now if I type in "hi" in lowercase,
我看到“ h”，“ i”，感叹号都全是小写。
I see "h," "i," exclamation point, all still lowercase.
所以我没有做任何有趣的事情。
So I haven't done anything interesting.
但是你知道吗，让我摆脱新的界限，
But you know what, let me get rid of the new line,
只是一切都保持在同一行，因为那有点丑陋。
just so it all stays on the same line, because that was kind of ugly.
让我再做一次。
Let me do it again.
好，好一点
OK, a little better.
让我实际上在程序的最后添加新行
Let me actually add a new line at the very end of the program
将光标移动到新行。
to move my cursor to the new line.
让我们再做一次，“嗨”。
Let's do it once more, "hi."
好吧，我什么都没写。
OK, I'm not uppercasing anything.
但是，如果我将c更改为c.upper，我可以按预期进行。
But if I change c to c.upper, I can do that as expected.
让我再次运行它，“嗨”，繁荣发展。
And let me run it again, "hi," and boom.
现在，我有另一个工作程序。
Now I have another working program.
但是现在的新功能是，请注意第5行的这种酷炫性。
But the new feature now is, notice this coolness on line 5.
如果您要遍历字符串的字符，
If you want to iterate over a string's characters,
您不需要将i初始化为0，然后使用方括号表示法
you don't need to initialize i to 0 and then use square bracket notation
就像您在C中所做的一样。您只是说，对于c中的s，对于x和y，无论是什么。
like you did in C. You just say, for c in s, or for x and y, whatever it is.
也可以用于迭代字符串中的各个字符，
For can also be used to iterate over the individual characters in a string,
正如您在做某事时可能想做的
as you might want to do when doing something
像密码学之类的。
like cryptography or the like.
因此，我们不必一次全部将整个字符串都大写。
So we don't have to just uppercase the whole string all at once.
我们仍然可以使用我们的个人价值观。
We can still gain access to our individual values.
您还可以在Python中完成其他一些事情，就像在C语言中可以完成的一样。
And there's other things you can do in Python as well that we could do in C.
让我继续在这里创建一个名为argv.py的程序，
Let me go ahead and create a program here called argv.py,
参数向量，回想一下，它是main输入的名称
for argument vector, which, recall, was the name of the input to main
允许您访问命令行参数。
that allows you to access command line arguments.
今天，我们已经看到您可以拥有一个主要功能
Now today, we have seen that you can have a main function
但是您不需要，但是这很传统。
but you don't need to, but it's conventional.
不再需要了。
It's not required anymore.
因此，我们还没有看到argc或argv，但这是
And so we haven't seen argc or argv yet, but that's
因为它们在Python中的其他位置。
because they're elsewhere in Python.
如果您想在Python中访问命令行参数，
If you want to access command line arguments in Python,
事实证明，您可以导入一个名为argv的模块。
it turns out that you can import a module called argv.
这有点新，但是它遵循与CS50库相同的模式。
And this is a little new, but it follows the same pattern as the CS50's library.
我将从系统库中导入一个名为argv的功能。
I'm going to import from the System library a feature called argv.
所以这只是意味着它是Python附带的，但是要使用它
So this just means that it comes with Python, but to use it
您必须显式导入它。
you have to import it explicitly.
现在，我要执行此操作。
And now I'm going to do this.
如果argv的长度等于2，那么我要
If the length of argv equals 2, then I'm going
继续进行打印，就像我们几周前所做的一样，
to go ahead and print out, just like we did a few weeks ago,
“ hello”，然后是argv括号1。
"hello," and then argv bracket 1.
有点晦涩难懂，但是我稍后会再讲到这一点。
Somewhat cryptic, but I'll come back to this in a moment.
否则，我将继续打印默认的“你好，世界”。
Else, I'm going to go ahead and print out a default of "hello, world."
因此，我们在几周前（第二周）进行了此操作
So we did this some weeks ago, in week 2,
因此，我们运行了一个程序，如果用户在提示符下键入了他们的姓名，
whereby we ran a program that if the user typed their name at the prompt,
它会说“你好，大卫”或“你好，布莱恩”。
it would say "hello, David" or "hello, Brian."
如果他们没有，它只会说“你好，世界”。
If they didn't, it would just say "hello, world."
因此要明确，如果我运行此程序并在没有任何命令行的情况下运行它
So to be clear, if I run this thing and run it without any command line
论据，我只看到“你好，世界”。
arguments, I just see "hello, world."
不过，如果我再次运行它，然后输入我的名字，然后按Enter键，
If I run it again, though, and type my name in and hit Enter,
现在我看到“你好，大卫。”
now I see "hello, David."
那怎么运作的呢？
So how is that working?
好的，这第一行代码使我可以访问argv，
Well, this first line of code gives me access to argv,
现在将其藏在sys库中，如果您愿意的话，
which is now tucked away in the sys library, if you will,
sys包，可以这么说。
the sys package, so to speak.
但它的工作方式相同。
But it works the same way.
没有argc，但没有问题。
There's no argc, but no problem.
如果argv是一个命令行参数列表，则为
If argv is a list of command line arguments, which it is,
len（LEN）会告诉我该列表的长度，它等于argc。
len, L-E-N, will tell me the length of that list, which is equivalent to argc.
因此，我可以从C版本中重建相同的想法。
So I can reconstruct the same idea from my version in C.
然后，在这里，我有一个格式字符串，它打印出“ hello”（逗号），
And here, then, I have a format string that prints out "hello," comma,
然后大括号中的所有内容
and then whatever's in curly braces.
argv是一个列表。
And argv is a list.
就像在C中有数组一样，一个列表
And just like in C, which had arrays, a list
只是可以为您动态增长和收缩的数组。
is just an array that can dynamically grow and shrink for you.
在这种情况下，您仍然可以使用方括号表示法
You can still use square bracket notation to get at, in this case,
人类打字的第二件事。
the second thing the human typed.
因此，为了清楚起见，让我将其更改为0。
So let me change this just for clarity to be 0.
如果我现在重新运行并输入David，
And if I rerun this now and type in David,
它奇怪地说：“您好，argv.py。”
it says weirdly, "hello, argv.py."
因此，您看不到的是“ Python”一词。
So what you don't see is the word "Python."
Python是解释器，但这不是程序执行的一部分
Python is the interpreter, but that's not part of your program's execution
本身。
per se.
argv 0将成为您正在运行的Python程序的名称，
argv 0 is going to be the name of the Python program you're running,
argv 1将成为其后的第一个单词，依此类推。
and argv 1 is going to be the first word thereafter, and so forth.
因此，我们仍然可以使用该功能，但是现在
So we still have access to that feature, but now
我们现在可以将其转换为Python。
we can convert it now to Python.
实际上，如果我想打印出所有命令行参数，
And in fact, if I want to print out all the command line arguments,
我可以更简单地做到这一点-
I can just more simply do this--
对于argv中的arg，请继续并打印arg。
for arg in argv, go ahead and print arg.
如此简洁，即使乍一看也不是很明显。
So very succinct, if not obvious at first glance.
现在让我继续输入
Now let me go ahead and type in something
像“大卫·马兰”两个词。
like "David Malan," two words.
输入，现在您将看到在程序名称之后打印或键入的所有内容，
Enter, you now see everything printed or typed after the program's name,
等等。
and so forth.
因此，在这里也请注意，我们可以多么巧妙地遍历Python中的列表。
So here, too, notice how neatly we can iterate over a list in Python.
没有i，不一定有方括号。
There's no i, there's no square brackets necessarily.
您可以说，对于argv中的arg，就像刚才我对c in s所说的那样。
You can just say, for arg in argv, just like a moment ago I said for c in s.
Python for循环几乎足够聪明
Pretty much the Python for loop is smart enough
弄清楚你想要它迭代什么，
to figure out what it is you want it to iterate over,
无论是字符串还是列表。
whether it's a string or a list.
我的天哪，编程真是太有趣了，还是太愉快了
And my God, it's just so much more fun or pleasant to program
现在，当您不必担心所有愚蠢的机制时
now, when you don't have to worry about all the stupid mechanics
，加号，加号，分号以及所有
of incrementing, and plus plus, and semicolons, and all
语法混乱。
of that syntactical mess.
好吧，让我在这里暂停看看是否有任何问题。
All right, let me pause here to see if there's any questions.
我知道我们正在快速研究其中的一些例子，
I know we're going through some of these examples quickly,
但实际上它们只是翻译而已。
but they're really just translations again.
对于即将出现的问题和问题集
And for upcoming problems and problems sets
您还能更系统地比较之前和之后的情况吗？
will you be able to more methodically compare before and after as well.
Brian，您到底要做什么？
Anything at all on your end, Brian?
布莱恩：什么都没有。
BRIAN: Nothing here.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
因此，让我们看一下过去的一些最终示例。
So let's look at some of our final past examples.
然后，我们将在今天结束时保留一些时间
And then we'll reserve some time at the end of today
看一些更强大的东西
to look at some even more powerful things
之所以能够做到，是因为现在有了Python之类的语言。
that we can do because now of languages like Python.
让我继续创建一个程序，这次称为exit.py，exit.py。
Let me go ahead and create a program, this time called exit.py, exit.py.
这个程序的目的是
And this program's purpose in life, it's just
将展示退出状态。
going to demonstrate exit statuses.
回想一下，最终在C语言中，我们引入了
Recall that eventually in C, we introduced
返回0或返回1或来自main的任何其他值的概念。
the notion of returning 0, or returning 1, or any other value from main.
我们现在在Python中也确实具有这种能力，
We do have that ability now in Python, too,
您将在更大的程序中开始看到它。
that you'll start to see in more larger programs.
在这里，我也要继续导入
Here, too, I'm going to go ahead and import
sys，这整个过程，只是为了展示执行此操作的另一种方式。
sys, the whole thing this time, just to show a different way of doing this.
我要说的是，如果sys.argv的长度
I'm going to say, if the length of sys.argv
不等于2，让我继续对用户大喊，
does not equal 2, let me go ahead and yell at the user,
“缺少命令行参数。”
"Missing command-line arguments."
然后，在此之后，我将继续执行sys.exit 1。
And then after this, I'm going to go ahead and do sys.exit 1.
否则，我将继续打印出格式化的字符串，
Otherwise, I'm going to go ahead and print out a formatted string that
说“你好”，逗号arg v括号1，前面是sys
says "hello," comma arg v bracket 1, with sys now in front of it
由于种种原因，我会在稍后解释。
for reasons I'll explain in a moment.
然后最后，我将继续进行操作，默认情况下，打印sys.exit 0。
And then at the end, I'm going to go ahead and by default print sys.exit 0.
好的。
All right.
那么这是怎么回事？
So what is going on here?
第一，因为我现在将sys用于两种不同的情况，
One, because I'm now using sys for two different things,
我决定不专门导入argv，
I decided not to import argv specifically,
但只是导入整个库。
but just to import the whole library.
但是因为这样做了，所以我不能只在任何地方写“ argv”一词。
But because I did that, I can't just write the word "argv" anywhere.
现在，我必须在其中加上包或库的名称作为前缀。
I now have to prefix it with the name of the package or library that it's in.
所以这就是为什么我开始做sys.argv，sys.argv的原因。
So that's why I started doing sys.argv, sys.argv.
但是我还使用了sys库的另一个功能，该功能使我可以访问
But I'm also using another feature of the sys library, which gives me access
到退出函数，相当于从main返回。
to an exit function, which is the equivalent to returning from main.
所以这有点二分法。
So this is a bit of a dichotomy.
在C语言中，您必须从main返回0或1，或其他整数。
In C, you had to return 0 or 1, or some other integer from main.
在Python中，您可以使用相同的数字来调用sys.exit。
In Python, you instead call sys.exit with the same kinds of numbers.
语法上有些许不同，但这是相同的基本思想。
So a little bit different syntactically, but it's the same fundamental idea.
该程序的目的是什么？
What's the purpose of this program?
好吧，如果我运行这个东西，它的目的仅仅是
Well, if I run this thing, its purpose is just
让我输入一个单词，然后在程序名称后面输入一个单词。
to make me type in one word and only one word after my program's name.
所以请注意，如果我只是运行exit.py的python，
So notice, if I just run python of exit.py,
对我大喊：“缺少命令行参数。”
it's yelling at me, "Missing command-line argument."
如果我改用我的名字来运行它，现在它说“你好，大卫”。
If I run it instead with my name after that, now it says "hello, David."
如此愚蠢的程序。
So stupid program.
这只是为了演示如何现在可以返回不同的值
It's only meant to demonstrate how you can now return different values
或真的从程序中过早地返回，
or really return prematurely from a program,
因为你不再是主要的。
because you're no longer in main.
您本身无法返回，但是现在可以根据需要在Python中退出。
You can't return per se, but you can now in Python exit as needed.
这就是那里的可比线。
So that's the comparable line there.
好吧，关于出口状态有什么问题吗？
All right, any questions, then, on exit statuses?
再说一遍，我们只是在浏览功能列表
Again, we're just kind of churning through the list of features
我们在C语言中看到了，即使他们不是很自然地来找您-
we saw in C, even if they don't come to you super naturally--
双关语不是故意的，而是Python世界中的类似物。
pun not intended-- but rather, there are analogs here in the Python world.
不？
No?
好的。
All right.
好吧，回想一下之后，我们开始真正地专注于
Well, recall that after that we started focusing really
在算法课上。
in the class on algorithms.
那就是我们数据集的大小
And that's when the size of our data sets
我们的代码效率开始变得至关重要。
and our-- the efficiency of our code started to really matter.
让我继续编写一个名为numbers.py的程序
Let me go ahead and write a program called numbers.py
例如，在sys的顶部包含一个导入，
that, for instance, contains an import at the top for sys,
因为我稍后会需要它。
because I'll need that in a moment.
然后它给了我-
And then it gives me--
让我给自己一个数字数组，例如4、6、8、2、7、5、0。
and let me give myself an array of numbers, like 4, 6, 8, 2, 7, 5, 0.
您可能还记得，这些都是第3周的数字。
And you might recall that those were the numbers behind the doors in week 3.
并假设我要搜索数字0。
And suppose that I want to search for the number 0.
好吧，在C语言中，要实现线性搜索，您可以使用for循环
Well, in C, to implement linear search you would use a for loop
和像i这样的变量，然后检查所有位置。
and a variable like i, and check all of the locations.
Python更简单。
Python is way simpler.
如果数字为0，则继续打印“找到”。
If 0 in numbers, go ahead and print out "Found."
然后，我继续进行操作，否则打印出“未找到”。
And then I'll go ahead and else print out "Not found."
就是这样。
And that's it.
因此，现在让我继续进行python number.py的编写。
So let me go ahead now and do python of numbers.py.
希望我能找到[音频不清晰]，因为它确实存在。
Hopefully I will see [INAUDIBLE] found, because it's in fact there.
就是这样了。
So that's it.
线性搜索只是介词短语，如果数字为0，
Linear search is just a prepositional phrase, if 0 in numbers,
为您提供所需的答案是非。
gives you the answer True or False that you want.
因此，存在我们的线性搜索。
So there is our linear search.
如果我想用名字怎么办？
What if I want to do it for names?
好吧，让我继续，给我自己第二份文件，本着相似的精神，
Well, let me go ahead and give myself a second file, similar in spirit,
叫做names.py。
called names.py.
让我再次导入-
Let me again import--
实际上，如果我真的想与我们的C版本相同，
and actually, if I really want to be identical to our C version,
让我继续并在这里以0退出，然后让我在这里1退出。
let me go ahead and exit with 0 here, and let me exit with 1 here.
但是严格来说，这不是必需的。
But strictly speaking, that's not necessary.
那恰好是我在C中执行此操作时所执行的操作。
That just happens to be what I did when we did this in C instead.
名义上，让我继续做类似的事情。
In names, let me go ahead and do something similar.
让我给自己列出一堆名字-
Let me give myself a names list with a whole bunch of names--
“比尔”，“查理”，“弗雷德”，“乔治”，“金妮”和“珀西”
"Bill," and "Charlie," and "Fred," and "George," and "Ginny," and "Percy,"
最后是“罗恩”，一直到最后。
and lastly "Ron," all the way at the end.
然后，让我使用线性搜索检查“ Ron”是否在该列表中。
And then let me just check if "Ron" is in that list using linear search.
如果名称中有“ Ron”，请继续打印“ Found”。
If "Ron" in names, go ahead and print out "Found."
否则，继续打印“找不到”。
Else, go ahead and print out "Not found."
这次我不会打扰打印或退出0或1。
And I won't bother printing out or exiting with 0 or 1 this time.
但是让我继续并运行python的名称-
But let me go ahead and run python of names--
哎呀，名字的巨蟒。
whoops, python of names.
瞧，我们找到了“罗恩”。
And voila, we found "Ron."
注意，我不是在作弊。
And notice, I'm not cheating.
我不认为我搞砸了。
I don't think I've screwed up.
如果我继续说“罗纳德”，如果那实际上是他的正式名字，
If I go ahead and say "Ronald," if that was in fact his formal name,
现在，我搜索“ Ron”，但找不到。
now I search for "Ron," not found.
确实是在寻找完全匹配的东西。
It's looking, indeed, for an exact match.
所以这很酷，我们可以蒸馏出一些东西
So that's pretty cool, that we can distill something
像那样很容易。
like that pretty readily.
好吧，回想一下，我曾提议Python具有其他数据
Well, recall that a little bit ago, I proposed that Python has other data
类型，其中有一些叫做字典或字典的东西，
types as well, among which are these things called dictionaries or dicts,
DICT，代表了精神上相似的键值对的集合
D-I-C-T, which represent a collection of key-value pairs similar in spirit
到字典。
to a dictionary.
像，西班牙语字典有西班牙语键和英语值转换一个
Like, the Spanish dictionary has Spanish keys and English values converting one
另一方面，这本英语词典有
to the other, this English dictionary has
英文单词和英文定义。
English words and English definitions.
但是同样的想法-键和值的集合。
But the same idea-- a collection of keys and values.
使用一个，您可以找到另一个。
Using one, you can find the other.
好吧，让我们继续将其在程序中转换为Python
Well, let's go ahead and translate this into Python in a program
称为phonebook.py，并实现了一些功能
called phonebook.py, and implements something
就像我们的C电话簿一样，回想一下，
like our C phone book a while back, which, recall,
在C语言中，我们最初使用了两个数组，然后我们进行了刮擦，
in C, we used a couple of arrays initially, then we scratched that,
而我们使用了一个结构数组。
and we used an array of structs instead.
现在让我们使用字典，这是一个更通用的数据
Now let's use a dictionary, which is a more general-purpose data
结构如下。
structure, as follows.
让我继续前进，然后从cs50导入get_string。
Let me go ahead here and from cs50 import get_string.
然后，让我继续前进，给自己写一本人文字典。
Then let me go ahead and give myself a dictionary of people.
而且这里的语法有些不同，
And the syntax here is a little different,
但我将继续使用花括号。
but I'm going to go ahead and preemptively use curly braces.
为了字典的目的，它们又回来了。
They are back for the purposes of dictionaries.
然后是定义键值对的方式。
And then here's how you define key-value pairs.
一个关键就是“布莱恩”。
One key is going to be "Brian."
他的价值将是“ + 1-617-495-1000”。
And his value is going to be "+1-617-495-1000."
那是他的电话。
That's his number.
然后从现在起我将成为其他关键人物之一
And then I'll be one of the other keys from now
我们将其保留为非常小的电话簿或字典。
We'll keep it a very small phone book or dictionary.
我的电话是“ + 1-949-468-2750”。
Mine will be "+1-949-468-2750."
就是这样。
And that's it.
因此，花括号在技术上可以位于不同的行上。
So the curly braces can technically be on different lines.
我可以把它移到这里，我可以摆脱它。
I could move this up here, I could get rid of this.
但是Python中有某些样式约定。
But there are certain style conventions in Python.
不过，重点是字典用花括号定义
The point, though, here is that a dictionary is defined with curly braces
在开始和结束时；键和值之间用冒号隔开；
at the beginning and end; the keys and values are separated by colons;
键值对之间用逗号分隔。
and the key-value pairs are separated by commas.
这就是为什么按照我的习惯编写它的原因。
So that's why it's conventional to write it the way I did.
更明显的是
It's just a little more obvious that this
是具有两个键的字典，每个键都有一个值。
is a dictionary with two keys, each of which has a value.
可以这么说，它只是将左右关联起来。
It's just associating left with right, so to speak.
现在，这是什么意思？
Now, what does this mean?
假设我要搜索某人的名字。
Suppose I want to search for someone's name.
好吧，让我继续，给我自己一个名为get_string的名称变量，询问
Well, let me go ahead and give myself a name variable called get_string, asking
以人为名。
the human for a name.
让我实现自己的虚拟电话簿，就像“联系人”应用程序一样
And let me implement my own virtual phone book, much like the Contacts app
在您的手机上。
on your phone.
让我继续，然后说，一旦我有了名字，
Let me go ahead and then say, once I have the name,
如果有人称呼，那就太好了。
if name in people, that's great.
如果我在别人身上找到名字，让我继续
If I found the name in people, let me go ahead
并打印出该人的号码是人括号名称。
and print out that the number for that person is people bracket name.
这就是字典将变得真正强大的地方。
And this is where dictionaries are going to get really powerful.
让我先运行它，然后再解释。
Let me run it first and then explain.
phonebook.py的Python，请输入-
Python of phonebook.py, Enter--
糟糕，phonebook.py的python。
whoops, python of phonebook.py.
让我搜索Brian的电话号码。
Let me search for Brian's number.
oom，有布莱恩的电话。
Boom, there's Brian's number.
让我继续并使用大卫的名字来运行它。
Let me go ahead and run it with David's name.
景气，有那个数字。
Boom, there's that number.
让我继续使用Montague的名字来运行它。
Let me go ahead and run it with, say, Montague's name.
暂时没有他的电话号码。
Don't have his phone number just yet.
他没有被列出，我输入的其他人也都没有列出。
He's unlisted, as would be anyone else that I type in.
那么，这里发生了什么？
So what has gone on here?
好吧，在顶部，我要声明这个称为人的新变量。
Well, at the top I'm declaring this new variable called people.
这是一本字典，左右一组键值对。
And it's a dictionary, a set of key-value pairs left and right.
然后，我像以前一样使用get_string从用户那里得到一个字符串。
Then I'm just getting a string from the user using get_string as before.
然后它也很强大。
And then this is powerful, too.
从本质上讲，这是在第9行上，搜索整个词典
This is essentially, on line 9, searching the whole dictionary
给定名称。
for the given name.
现在，它又回到了与之相关的名称，或者，对不起，
And it's returning to me down here the name associated with that-- or, sorry,
与该人的姓名相关联的号码。
the number associated with that person's name.
让我通过将其排除在外来使这一点更加清楚。
And let me make this more clear by factoring this out.
让我给自己一个变量，称为数字，然后更多
Let me give myself a variable called number and then more
显式打印出该变量的名称。
explicitly print out that variable's name.
这就是今天的不同之处。
Here's what's different today.
这里的“如果以人命名”，这就是Python
"If name in people" in here, what this does is Python
在所有键中搜索该名称。
searches all of the keys for that name.
它不搜索值。
It doesn't search values.
当您说给定词典中的名字是否像人一样时，
When you say if name in a given dictionary, like people is,
它仅搜索键。
it searches only the keys.
如果您随后找到了钥匙，我一定会知道
If you've then found the key, I know definitively
字典中有“ David”或“ Brian”。
that "David" or "Brian" are in the dictionary.
并注意这一点。
And notice this.
就像在C的数组语法中一样。
It's just like in C's arrays syntax.
您现在可以使用方括号表示法编制索引
You can now use square bracket notation to index
使用“ David”或“ Brian”之类的词进入字典，
into a dictionary using a word like "David" or "Brian,"
然后找回我们的电话号码之类的值。
and get back a value like our phone number.
在C语言中，甚至在Python中，每当
In C, and thus far even in Python, whenever
我们已经看到了方括号符号，通常只用于数字，
we've seen square bracket notation, it would only be typically for numbers,
因为数组或列表具有索引，数字
because arrays or lists have indices, numbers
指出第一个位置，中间位置和最后一个位置，
that addresses the first location, middle, and last,
等等，介于两者之间的所有内容。
and so forth, everything in between.
但是字典的强大之处在于它们在其他方面
But what's powerful about dictionaries is that they're otherwise
称为关联数组。
known as associative arrays.
字典是键值对的集合。
A dictionary is a collection of key-value pairs.
如果您想查找一个钥匙，您只需
And if you want to look up a key, you simply
使用方括号表示法，就像我们以前使用的
use square bracket notation, just like we used
在数字上使用方括号。
to use square brackets for numbers.
而且由于Python是一种非常漂亮的语言，
And because Python is a pretty fancy language,
它会处理您的搜索。
it handles the searching for you.
甚至更好的是，它不使用线性搜索。
And even better, it does not use linear search.
搜索字典时，它渴望为您提供
When searching a dictionary, it aspires to give you
通过使用我们上周称为哈希表的固定时间。
constant time by using what we called last week a hash table.
字典通常是在幕后使用某些东西实现的
Dictionaries are typically implemented underneath the hood using something
像哈希表
like a hash table.
回想一下，即使它确实是
And recall that, even though it was really
如果您选择非常好的哈希值，则可以实现恒定时间的目标
a goal of achieving constant time, if you choose a really good hash
功能和真正-
function and a really--
适当大小的数组进行哈希运算，您可以接近恒定时间。
the right size array to hash into, you can come close to constant time.
同样，在Python字典的功能中
So again, among the features of a dictionary in Python
是它为您提供了非常高的性能。
are that it gives you very high performance.
这不是线性搜索。
It's not linear search.
实际上，回想一下，当我们早些时候开始使用Python时，
And in fact, set-- recall that when we began playing with Python earlier,
然后我使用什么重新实现了拼写器
and I re-implemented speller using, what,
最多10或20行代码，而不是很多行
10 or 20 lines of code max instead of the many
您可能为pset 5编写的更多内容，speller使用了一组。
more that you might have written for pset 5, speller used a set.
集合只是价值的集合。
And a set is just a collection of values.
长话短说，它的精神类似于字典
Long story short, it's similar in spirit to a dictionary
因为它在引擎盖下也使用了哈希表
in that it, too, underneath the hood uses a hash table
让您快速得到答案。
to get you answers quickly.
因此，如果您回想一下之前的那个拼写器示例
So if you think back to what that speller example was from earlier
今天，当我有一行代码说单词等于集合时，
on today, when I had a line of code that just said words equals set,
一行代码几乎实现了全部
that one line of code was implementing pretty much the entirety
您的拼写检查器。
of your spell checker.
所有这些指针，所有哈希表和链以及链接列表
All of those pointers, all of those hash tables and chains and linked lists
被提炼成仅一行代码。
are distilled into just one line of code.
您可以通过语言本身来获得。
You get that with the language itself.
好的。
All right.
对字典有任何疑问吗？
Any questions, then, on dictionaries?
它们会重复出现，并且它们往往是最有用的数据结构之一，
They will recur, and they tend to be one of the most useful data structures,
因为这种将某事物与其他事物联系起来的能力
because this ability to just associate something with something else
事实证明，这只是组织数据的一种好方法。
is just a wonderful way, it turns out, to organize your data.
有什么问题吗？
Any questions here?
是的，索菲娅？
Yeah, Sophia?
听众：是否只有设定的散列函数
AUDIENCE: Is there only a set hash function
Python为这些字典定义的
that Python has defined for these dictionaries,
还是我们可以通过任何方式更改哈希函数？
or can we change the hash function in any way?
戴维·马兰：好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
它为您提供了哈希函数和Python
It comes with a hash function for you, and Python
为您找到所有这些。
figures all of that out for you.
这就是您应该留给图书馆的细节，
So that's the kind of detail that you should leave to the library,
因为别人一直都在思考
because someone else has spent all of the time thinking
关于如何动态适应数据结构，
about how to dynamically adapt the data structure, move things around as
需要，这样您就不再需要强调
needed, so that you no longer need to stress to the degree
您自己实施拼写检查时可能会遇到的问题。
you might have when implementing speller yourself.
事实证明，其他事情也变得容易。
And it turns out, other things get easy, too.
这不一定是通常需要的功能，
This is not a commonly needed feature, necessarily,
但这是我们可以做的。
but it is something we can do.
让我继续编写一个名为swap.py的快速程序。
And let me go ahead and write a quick program called swap.py.
回想几周前在swap.ca中，我们给xa值为1，
Recall that in swap.c a couple of weeks ago, we gave x a value of 1,
ya变量-值为2，然后我打印出一些内容
y a variable-- a value of 2, and then I printed out something
就像“ x是x，y是y”。
like "x is x, y is y."
但是这周我使用格式字符串只是为了打印出来。
But this week I'm using format strings just to print that out.
然后我做了一些交换x，y之类的事情，但我只是希望能做到最好，
Then I did something like swap x, y, and I just kind of hoped for the best,
然后我再次打印出这些值。
and then I printed out those values again.
好吧，事实证明是在Python中，因为您没有指针
Well it turns out in Python, because you don't have pointers
而且您本身没有可访问的地址，
and you don't have addresses per se that you have access to,
你不能像上周那样求助于解决方案
you can't resort to the solution like last week
并通过引用传递这些变量，
and pass these variables around by reference,
可以这么说，按他们的地址。
so to speak, by their address.
那是不可能的。
That's just not possible.
为什么会这样？
Why is that a thing?
好吧，这似乎使您失去了功能，
Well, it would seem to be taking a feature away from you,
但说实话，如果过去一周有任何迹象（包括前一周），
but honestly, if this past week was any indication, including the week prior,
指针很难。
pointers are hard.
并且分割错误频繁发生。
And segmentation faults are frequent.
正确地处理所有这些问题是困难的。最糟糕的是
And getting all of that stuff right is difficult. And at worst,
您的程序可能会受到威胁，因为有人可以访问
your programs can be compromised, because someone can access memory that
他们不应该。
they shouldn't.
因此，Python取消了该功能。
So Python takes that feature away.
Java还使程序员无法使用该功能
Java also takes that feature away from programmers
保护您免于被搞砸，就像您可能
to protect you against yourself from screwing up, like you may have
并且应该在过去一周内有几次。
and should have in some number of times this past week.
但是事实证明，在Python中有解决这些问题的方法。
But it turns out, in Python there are solutions to these problems.
而且，如果您想交换x和y，那就很好。
And if you want to swap x and y, that's fine.
交换x和y。
Swap x and y.
所以现在如果我在这个程序上运行交换python，瞧，繁荣，
And so now if I run python of swap on this program, voila, boom,
它被蒸馏成另一条线。
it's distilled into one other line.
因此，即使他们从我们身边夺走了某些东西，您也可能造成很大的损失
So even though they take something away from us that you can do a lot of damage
还是犯了很多错误，我们仍然可以
with or make a lot of mistakes with, we can nonetheless
只需一根衬板即可更换，让您拥有更强大的功能。
hand you back a more powerful feature with this one liner for swap.
并注意，左边是x逗号，右边是y逗号。
And notice that it's x comma y on the left, but y comma x on the right.
这具有做Brian的作用
And that has the effect of doing what Brian
戴着一瓶做switcheroo的液体，
did with the glasses of liquid of doing the switcheroo,
即使那里没有明确的临时变量，
even without a temporary variable explicitly there,
尽管引擎盖下面发生了一些魔术。
though some magic is happening underneath the hood.
好吧，让我们继续执行第4周的几个最终程序
Well, let's go ahead and implement a couple of final programs from week 4
然后在第6周在这里介绍一些我们自己的内容。
and then introduce a few of our own here in week 6.
让我继续实施另一本电话簿
Let me go ahead and implement another phone book
这是一个更持久的。
that this one's a little more persistent.
让我继续此处并打开-在此处创建一个名为phonebook.csv的文件。
Let me go ahead here and open-- create a file here called phonebook.csv.
让我继续命名该逗号。
And let me go ahead and name this name comma number.
因此，回想起来，CSV文件就像一个非常简单的电子表格。
So CSV file, recall, is like a very simple spreadsheet.
我们将继续进行创建，以便在附近使用。
And we're going to go ahead and just create that so I have it nearby.
然后我要创建一个名为phonebook.py的新文件
And then I'm going to create a new file called phonebook.py that's
最初是空的。
initially empty.
这次我要这样做。
And this time I'm going to do this.
我将像以前一样从cs50导入get_string函数。
I'm going to import from cs50 the get_string function as before.
但是我还将导入一个名为CSV库的库。
But I'm also going to import a library called the CSV library.
事实证明，Python附带了与CSV相关的大量功能
It turns out, Python comes with a whole lot of functionality related to CSV
文件，使您的生活更轻松，并且使使用CSV进行操作变得更加容易。
files to make your life easier and make it easier to do things with CSVs.
我可能想做的事情就是这样。
Among the things I might want to do is this.
我继续以追加模式打开该文件phonebook.csv，
Let me go ahead and open up that file, phonebook.csv, in append mode,
类似于两周前的fopen。
similar to fopen two weeks ago.
让我继续并将其分配给一个名为file的变量。
And let me go ahead and assign that to a variable called file.
然后，让我继续，然后从用户那里获得一个名字。
Then let me go ahead and just get a name from the user.
因此，让我使用get_string在此处获取某人的名称“名称”。
So let me use get_string to get someone's name, "Name" here.
然后让我继续获取-再次使用get_string
Then let me go ahead and get-- use get_string again
在这里获取某人的电话号码，因此请使用“电话号码”。
to get someone's number here, so using "Number."
最后-这是新代码-
And then lastly-- and this is the new code--
让我将该名称和编号保存到文件中。
let me save that name and number to a file.
再回想一下pset 4中的内容，即保存文件并将字节写出到文件中
And recall from pset 4 that saving files and writing bytes out to files
非常参与。
is pretty involved.
就像，您可能花了一段时间才能实现恢复或模糊处理，
Like, it probably took you a while to implement recover, or blur,
任何涉及创建新文件的过滤器。
any of those filters that involved creating new files.
事实证明，CSV库使此操作非常容易。
Turns out the CSV library makes this pretty easy.
让我继续前进，给自己一个所谓的作家。
Let me go ahead and give myself what's called a writer.
我要给自己打电话给文件csv.writer的返回值。
And I'm going to give myself the return value of calling csv.writer of file.
那这是在做什么呢？
So what is this doing?
同样，文件代表我要打开的文件。
File, again, represents the file I'm trying to open.
csv.writer是CSV库随附的一些功能。
csv.writer is some function that comes with the CSV library.
并且它希望您已经打开的文件作为输入。
And it expects as input a file that you've already opened.
并使用一些更高级的功能包装该文件
And it kind of wraps that file with some fancier functionality
这将使我的程序员更轻松
that's going to make it way easier for me the programmer
写入该文件。
to write to that file.
我该怎么办？
What am I going to do?
我将使用那个writer变量来专门写一行
I'm going to use that writer variable to write a row that specifically
包含一个名称和一个数字。
contains a name and a number.
我正在使用一个列表，因为如果您认为
And I'm using a list, because if you think
对于具有列和行的电子表格，列表是一种正确的想法。
of a spreadsheet with columns and rows, a list is kind of the right idea.
从左到右的每个单元格都像一个列表。
Each of the cells from left to right is kind of like a list.
行就像一个列表。
A row is like a list.
因此，我将在此处故意使用一个列表。
So I'm going to deliberately use a list here.
最后，就像过去一样，我将关闭文件。
And then lastly, I'm going to close the file, just as I've done in the past.
所以这里有点神秘。
So it's a little cryptic here.
但是，get_string-get_string现在已经很旧了。
But again, get_string-- get_string is old now.
现在已经老了。
This is old now.
因此，仅有的新内容是导入CSV。
So the only things that are new are importing the CSV.
我正在以追加模式打开此文件，类似于在C中所做的操作。
I'm opening this file in append mode, similar to what I did in C.
然后这些行涉及到用CSV包装文件
And then these lines here involve wrapping the file with the CSV
功能，使用writerow将行写入此文件，
functionality, writing a row to this file with writerow,
然后关闭它。
and then closing it.
因此，让我继续尝试一下。
So let me go ahead and try this now.
让我打开一个phonebook.csv，目前仅
Let me open up a phonebook.csv, which for now only
包含这些标题，这些标题是我刚才创建的。
contains these headers which I created manually a moment ago.
然后，让我继续运行该文件，即phonebook.py的python。
And let me go ahead and run this, python of phonebook.py.
让我继续并添加Brian。
Let me go ahead and add Brian.
而Brian将会是+ 1-617-495-1000，Enter。
And Brian will be +1-617-495-1000, Enter.
现在让我在这里转到我的CSV文件。
And now let me go to my CSV file over here.
该死，我搞砸了。
Dammit, I screwed up.
假装我没有在那打Enter。
Pretend I didn't hit Enter there.
现在可以了。
Now it works.
现在让我继续，然后通过输入再次执行此操作-
Let me go ahead now and do this again by input--
手动创建文件时，我应该按Enter键，
I should have hit Enter when I created the file manually,
但我搞砸了创建它。
but I screwed up on creating it.
因此，让我对此挥手致意，并说服您我做得正确
So let me wave my hand at that and convince you that I did this correctly
在代码中添加自己，David，+ 1-949-468-2750，Enter。
in code by adding myself, David, +1-949-468-2750, Enter.
让我回到我的CSV文件。
Let me go back to my CSV file.
瞧，现在它的格式正确了，因为我做到了-
And voila, now it's formatted correctly, because I did--
writerow为我提供了一行。
writerow includes a line for me.
另外请注意，如果我下载此文件，请让我下载phonebook.csv
And notice, too, if I download this file-- let me download phonebook.csv
就像我过去一周所做的一样。
like I did in a past week.
让我将其下载到我自己的Mac上。
Let me download this to my own Mac.
让我打开此CSV文件。
Let me open this CSV file.
不管您安装的是Apple Numbers还是Microsoft Excel，
And whether you have Apple Numbers installed or Microsoft Excel,
您将打开如下所示的内容。
you'll open something that looks like this.
瞧，我现在是使用Python代码动态创建的，
And voila, I've dynamically created, using Python code now,
我自己的CSV文件类型。
my own sort of CSV file.
事实证明，有一种方法可以将其收紧一点。
And it turns out there's a way to tighten this up just a little bit.
按照我的方式做，这没什么大不了的，但是事实证明
Not a big deal to do it the way I did, but it turns out
您还可以以不同的方式打开和关闭文件。
that you can also open and close files a little differently.
你可以这样做。
You can do this.
带文件-带，而是带文件打开。
With file-- with, rather, with open as file.
然后，我可以在此处缩进所有这些内容，并摆脱掉自己的底线。
Then I can indent all of this here, and I can get rid of my close line.
因此，按照我打开和关闭的方式进行操作没什么大不了的，
So not a big deal to do it the way I did with open and close,
但是我在这里完成此操作的方式有点像Pythonic。
but the way I've done this here is a little more Pythonic.
这个“ with”关键字，与任何东西都不相似
This "with" keyword, which is not something analogous to anything
我们在C中看到with关键字，当您打开文件时，
we've seen in C, the with keyword, when you open a file,
它将最终自动为您关闭。
it will automatically close it for you eventually.
因此，您可能会在一些在线参考资料或其他材料中看到这一点。
So you might see that in some online references or other materials.
但是，它只是自动为您完成此操作。
But again, it just does that for you automatically.
好吧，让我们继续执行此操作。
Well, let's go ahead and do this.
我喜欢我们现在可以操作CSV的事实。
I like the fact that we can now manipulate CSV.
事实证明，如果您曾经使用过Google表单-
And it turns out that if you've ever used Google Forms--
这是从用户收集数据的一种非常流行的方式。
that's a very popular way of collecting data from users.
实际上，让我继续并转到要访问的URL
In fact, let me go ahead and go to a URL which is going
在这里向您展示这样的表格。
to show you a form like this here.
布赖恩，如果您不介意在聊天中输入网址，请转到您的网址，
Brian, if you wouldn't mind typing that into the chat, go to that you URL,
cs50.ly.hogwarts。
cs50.ly.hogwarts.
如果每个人都不介意一起玩，
And if everyone wouldn't mind just playing along,
只需告诉我们您希望分房后将您分配给哪栋房子
just tell us what house you wish you were assigned to by the Sorting
霍格沃茨世界的帽子。
Hat in the world of Hogwarts.
你会在哪间房子里？
What house would you be in?
现在，如果您以前使用过Google Forms，
Now, if you've used Google Forms before, you'll
回想一下，您肯定可以在Google表单本身中看到这些结果-
recall that you can see these results, certainly in the Google Form itself--
你们当中已有122位蜂拥而至。
and already 122 of you have buzzed in.
我们可以看到分布和图形等等。
And we could see a distribution and a graph and so forth.
但是我想要的不是那里的图片分布。
But what I want is not the distribution pictorially there.
我将继续打开电子表格。
I'm going to go ahead and open up a spreadsheet.
因此，如果您以前从未使用过Google Forms，则可以单击一个按钮，
And so if you've never used Google Forms before, you can click a button,
然后您可以获得所有回复的列表
and then you can get a list of all of the responses
现在即将上线。
that are coming in live right now.
默认情况下，Google会跟踪时间戳，
And by default, Google keeps track of the timestamp,
提交表单的时间以及实际使用的房屋。
when the form was submitted, and what house was actually used.
因此，我现在要继续进行此操作。
So I'm going to go ahead now and do this.
让我继续并将其下载到另一个选项卡中。
Let me go ahead and download that in another tab.
请给我一点时间在此屏幕上进行操作。
Give me just a moment to do it on this screen here.
我将继续将该CSV文件下载到我的Mac上
I'm going to go ahead and download that CSV file onto my Mac
在本地，通过转到文件，下载，CSV。
locally, by going to File, Download, CSV.
它将放入我的“下载”文件夹中。
That's going to put it into my Downloads folder.
然后我要继续并将其上传到我的IDE中
And then I'm going to go ahead and upload this into my IDE
只需拖放即可。
by just dragging and dropping.
糟糕，我必须打开文件浏览器。
Whoops, I have to open the file browser.
我将通过拖放文件来做到这一点。
I'm going to do this by dragging and dropping the file.
好的。
All right.
现在我在那里有那个文件。
Now I have that file there.
现在让我继续进行操作，确保文件在那里。
And let me go ahead now and make sure the file's there.
我有一个名为“排序帽子响应-
I have this file called "Sorting Hat Responses--
表格回应1，”，依此类推。
Form Responses 1," and so forth.
好吧，让我继续写一个程序来处理这些数据，
Well, let me go ahead and write a program now that manipulates this data,
如果您经营一个学生团体，
much like you might if running a student group that's
收集Google表单中的数据，或者您只是在收集信息
collecting data in a Google Form, or you're just collecting information
一般而言，并以CSV格式显示。
in general and have it in CSV format.
您现在如何计算所有结果，
How might you now tally up all of the results,
特别是如果Google不只是在讲
especially if Google weren't just telling
您以图形方式显示了什么结果？
you graphically what the results were?
好吧，让我继续编写一个名为hogwarts的程序，
Well, let me go ahead and write a program called hogwarts,
这不是我们以前在C语言中见过的东西。让我继续
which was not something that we've seen ever before in C. Let me go ahead
并导入此CSV库。
and import this CSV library.
首先让我给自己一本字典
Let me give myself initially a dictionary
所谓的房屋，包含一堆钥匙，
called houses that contains a whole bunch of keys,
像“格兰芬多”（Gryffindor），初始计数为0；
like "Gryffindor" with initial count of 0;
初始计数为0的“赫奇帕奇”； “ Ravenclaw”，初始计数为0；
"Hufflepuff" with an initial count of 0; "Ravenclaw" with an initial count of 0;
以及初始计数为0的“ Slytherin”。
and also, "Slytherin" with an initial count of 0.
因此请注意，在字典或Python中的字典中，
So notice, in a dictionary, or dict in Python,
键和值不必是字符串和字符串。
the keys and values don't need to be strings and strings.
当然可以是字符串和数字。
It can certainly be strings and numbers.
因为我最终将使用这本词典来保存
Because I'm going to use this dictionary ultimately to keep
计算一所房子或另一所房子的所有票数。
count of all of the votes for one house or another.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续并打开Sorting Hat文件打开-
Let me go ahead and open up with open the Sorting Hat File--
表单响应1.csv”-长文件名，但这是Google的默认文件-
Form Responses 1.csv"-- long filename, but that's the default from Google--
作为文件。
as file.
因此，我将使用我的一根衬纸，而不必打开和关闭。
So I'm going to use my one liner instead of having to open and close.
这次我要给自己一个读者，这是我们之前从未见过的。
I'm going to give myself this time a reader, which we did not see before.
CSV库具有阅读器功能，该功能允许
CSV library has a reader function that allows
我可以自动读取CSV文件。
me to read a CSV file automatically.
我将继续并跳过第一行。
I'm going to go ahead and skip the first row.
接下来是一个仅跳过第一行的函数，
Next is a function that just skips the first row,
因为回想起那只是时间戳和房子，
because recall that that one is just timestamp and house, which
我想忽略。
I do want to ignore.
我想要你们的真实数据。
I want the real data from you all.
这是Python中CSV的最酷之处。
And here's what's cool about CSVs in Python.
我可以-如果要遍历该电子表格中的所有行，
I can-- if I want to iterate over all of the rows that are in that spreadsheet,
我可以做阅读器中的行。
I can do for row in reader.
现在，让我继续前进，例如到达有关房屋。
And now, let me go ahead and get at, for instance, the house in question.
因此，给定行中的房子将成为该行的第一个条目，索引为0。
So the house in a given row is going to be the row's first entry, 0 indexed.
那么这是怎么回事？
So what is going on here?
好吧，让我先回到Google电子表格。
Well, let me go back to the Google spreadsheet a moment ago.
在Google电子表格中，有两列。
And in the Google spreadsheet, there's two columns.
CSV阅读器的工作方式是一次返回给您-
And the way the CSV reader works is it returns to you one row at a time--
从概念上讲，这非常简单。
and that's conceptually pretty straightforward.
它完全符合电子表格的想法。
It maps perfectly to the idea of a spreadsheet.
但是每一行都以列表的形式返回给您，在这种情况下，列表的大小为2。
But each row is returned to you as a list, a list in this case of size 2.
所以行括号0会给我一个给定的时间戳，行括号
So row bracket 0 would give me a given timestamp, row bracket
1会给我一个给定的房子名称。
1 would give me a given house name.
这就是为什么在IDE中，我要声明一个名为
So that's why here in the IDE, I'm going ahead and declaring a variable called
房子，我将其分配为等于行括号1，因为我
house, and I'm assigning it equal to row bracket 1, because I
不在乎时间戳。
don't care about the timestamp.
我们几乎都在同一时间做到了这一点。
We all just did this roughly at the same time.
但是现在有了房子，我现在可以索引字典了，
But now that I have the house, I can now index into the dictionary, just
像在C中一样，您可以使用数字索引到数组中。
like in C you could index into an array using a number.
但是在字典中，我可以使用字符串。
But in a dictionary, I can use strings.
所以我要继续说，进入房屋字典，
So I'm going to go ahead and say, go into the houses dictionary, which
我在上方定义，然后转到房门钥匙，然后继续
I defined up above, and go to the house key, and go ahead
并增加1。
and increment it by 1.
就是这样。
And that's it.
至此，我已经打开了CSV文件，并使用该库进行了读取。
At this point, I have opened the CSV file and read it using the library.
在此循环中，我要遍历电子表格中的每一行
In this loop, I'm iterating over every row in the spreadsheet
你们都是通过一次又一次地填写表格来创建的。
that you all created by filling out that form again and again.
我只是用一个变量来得到什么
I'm just using a variable to get at whatever's
在第二列（也称为行括号1）中，
in the second column, otherwise known as row bracket 1,
因为行括号0将是时间戳。
because row bracket 0 would be the timestamp.
然后我要进入字典
And then I'm going into the dictionary called
房子，我们在这里定义。
houses, which we defined up here.
我像数组一样索引其中，但在这种情况下是列表，
I'm indexing into it just like an array, but it's a list in this case,
使用其房屋名称查找相应的密钥。
using its house name, which looks up the appropriate key.
然后正等于1会增加其值。
And then plus equals 1 has the effect of incrementing its value.
因此，这是进入字典并递增的一种好方法。
So it's a nice way of going into the dictionary and incrementing.
进入并递增。
Go in and increment.
因此，现在让我们从这里开始，继续打印结果。
So now let's go ahead at the very end here and just print out the result.
“在房屋中换屋子”是一种反复尝试的奇特方法
"For house in houses" is the fancy way to iterate over
字典中的所有键，继续并打印出格式化的字符串
all of the keys in a dictionary, go ahead and print out a formatted string
如下。
as follows.
让我先打印出房子的名称，然后是冒号，然后是房子
Let me print out the house name followed by a colon followed by the houses
字典，用房子索引到它。
dictionary, indexing into it with house.
再说一次，神秘的。
So again, cryptic.
我们一会儿再讲。
We'll come back to this in a second.
霍格沃茨巨蟒。
Python of hogwarts.
让我用手指交叉，以防我没拧紧。
Let me cross my fingers that I didn't screw this up.
而我做到了。
And I did.
IDE早于我就知道了。
The IDE knew before I did.
好的。
All right.
现在让我希望我不要搞砸了，该死。
Now let me hope that I didn't screw this up-- and dammit.
好的。
All right.
该文件的名称略有不同。
The file is called something slightly different.
抱歉，与我练习时相比，Google的名称必须更改了。
Google's name must have changed, sorry, versus when I practiced.
让我复制一下。
Let me copy this.
很近。
So close.
对帽子响应进行排序。
Sorting hat responses.
啊，有我忘了的括号。
Ah, it has parentheses which I forgot.
好的。
All right.
现在让我动动手指，重新运行该程序，该死。
Now let me cross my fingers, rerun the program, dammit.
好，没有这样的文件，或者-
OK, no such file or--
哦，我忘了csv，点csv。
oh, I forgot the csv, dot csv.
好的。
OK.
现在，交叉手指，然后-
Now cross fingers and--
哦，感谢上帝。
oh, thank God.
好的，格兰芬多（Gryffindor）最受欢迎的房子就不足为奇了。
OK so Gryffindor, not surprisingly, the most popular house.
赫奇帕奇（Hufflepuff）40岁，拉文克劳（Ravenclaw）71岁，斯莱特林（Slytherin）–击败赫奇帕奇（Hufflepuff）。
Hufflepuff at 40, Ravenclaw at 71, Slytherin-- oh, beat out Hufflepuff.
无论出于什么社会学原因，都很有趣。
Very interesting for whatever sociological reason.
但是，现在我们有了一个分析CSV的程序。
But here we have a program now that analyzed the CSV.
现在，我们碰巧用愚蠢的哈利·波特数据来做到这一点。
Now, we happened to do it with silly Harry Potter data.
但是，再次想像一下，从用户那里收集您想要的任何数据，
But again, imagine collecting any data you want from users,
以CSV格式下载到您的Mac或PC或IDE，
downloading it as a CSV to your Mac or PC or your IDE,
然后编写用于分析所需数据的代码。
then writing code that analyzes that data however you want.
我做了一个非常简单的总结，但是您当然可以
I did a very simple summation, but you could certainly
想象做些比这更奇妙的事情，
imagine doing something fancier than that,
像是求和或平均值，标准差。
like doing summations or averages, standard deviations.
所有这些功能我们也可以得到。
All of that functionality could we get as well.
好吧，关于字典的任何疑问，现在就开始吧
All right, any questions on dictionaries before we now
提供我们迄今最强大的功能
offer up some of the most powerful features we've yet
用编程语言看过吗？
seen in a programming language?
Brian，您到底要做什么？
Anything at all on your end, Brian?
布莱恩：这里没有举手。
BRIAN: No hands raised here.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
好吧，现在让我继续前进，我实际上将过渡
Well, let me go ahead now, and I'm going to transition actually
到我预先安装了Python的Mac上，
to my Mac where I have in advance pre-installed Python,
只是为了我可以在本地做事。
just so that I can do things locally.
它将使事情变得更快。
It will make things a little faster.
我不必担心互联网速度之类的问题。
I don't have to worry about internet speeds and the like.
的确如此，在您自己的Mac，您的PC上，
And this is indeed the case, that on your own Mac, your own PC,
您可以下载并安装Python解释器，
you can download and install the Python interpreter,
在您自己的Mac和PC上运行它。
run it on your own Mac and PC.
但是，我建议您继续使用此IDE，
However, I would recommend you continue using this IDE,
当然，为了解决问题，直到学期末，
certainly for problem sets' sake until the end of the semester,
也许过渡到Mac或PC进行最终项目
maybe transitioning to your Mac or PC for final projects
只是因为我这个周末做的事花了-
only, only because what I did this weekend was spent--
浪费大量时间只是让愚蠢的库工作
waste a huge amount of time just getting stupid libraries to work
在我自己的Mac上，说起来容易做起来难，
on my own Mac, which is often easier said than done,
只是因为程序员在编写应该可以工作的代码时
just because when programmers are writing code that's supposed to work
在世界上所有可能的Mac和PC上，您和我以及其他所有人
on every possible Mac and PC in the world, you and I and everyone else
版本号略有不同，软件安装也不同，
have slightly different version numbers, different software install,
不同的不兼容性。
different incompatibilities.
因此，当您在本地做事时，这些头痛很快就会出现。
So those kinds of headaches very quickly arise when you're doing things locally.
因此，让我鼓励您等到最终项目结束时，
So let me encourage you to wait until terms end with final projects,
也许，要离开IDE并做些什么
perhaps, to move off of the IDE and do what
我现在要这样做，只是因为您将能够看到更多这些演示
I'm about to now do, just because you'll be able to see these demos more
显然在这里。
clearly here.
我要继续，在我自己的Mac上，
I'm going to go ahead, and on my own Mac,
我将继续创建一个名为Speech.py的程序。
I'm going to go ahead and create a program called speech.py.
预先，我已经安装了一个支持语音合成的库。
In advance, I've installed a library that supports speech synthesis.
如果我想使用该功能，
And if I want access to that functionality,
只需导入pyttsx3，即该人的开源名称
it suffices to import pyttsx3, which is the name of that person's open source
我预先下载并安装在Mac上的免费库。
free library that I downloaded and installed on my Mac in advance.
我阅读了文档。
I read the documentation.
在过去的一周中，我几乎从未使用过此功能。
I literally never used this before this past week.
我发现例如可以声明一个名为engine的变量。
And I found that I can declare a variable called engine, for instance.
然后，我可以调用pyttsx3.init初始化该库。
I can then call pyttsx3.init to initialize the library.
为什么？
Why?
那只是因为程序员是如何设计的。
That's just because of how the programmer designed it.
您必须先对其进行初始化。
You have to initialize it first.
然后，我可以使用该引擎说诸如“ hello”，逗号“ world”之类的内容。
I then can use that engine to say things like, say, "hello," comma "world."
然后在那之后，我应该运行引擎并等待它
Then after that, I should run the engine and wait for it
在我自己的程序退出之前完成。
to finish before my own program quits.
好的。
All right.
现在让我继续并关闭它，然后在我自己的Mac上运行Speech.py的python
Let me go ahead now and close that, and run python of speech.py on my own Mac
这里。
here.
计算机声音：您好，世界。
COMPUTER VOICE: Hello, world.
大卫·马兰：有趣。
DAVID MALAN: Interesting.
所以它说了我输入的内容。
So it said what I typed in.
确实，我可能可以使这一点变得更加有趣。
And indeed, I can probably make this even more interesting.
让我继续说这样的话。
Let me go ahead and say something like this.
让我再次打开speech.py并添加一些功能。
Let me open up speech.py again and add some functionality.
我不会使用CS50库，但也许会使用输入功能。
I won't use the CS50 library, but I will use maybe the input function.
让我继续说，输入姓名，“您叫什么名字，”问号。
Let me go ahead and say name gets input, "What's your name," question mark.
然后让我继续说，而不是说“你好，世界”
And then let me go ahead and say, not "hello, world,"
但让我用f弦
but let me use an f-string--
不必在印刷中使用
which doesn't have to be used in print, you
可以在需要字符串的任何函数中使用它。
can use it in any function that takes a string.
让我继续说那个名字“你好”。
Let me go ahead and say "hello" to that name.
好的。
All right.
让我继续并再次运行python speech.py。
Let me go ahead and run python speech.py again.
哎呀。
Oops.
让我继续并再次运行Speech.py的python。
Let me go ahead and run python of speech.py again.
我的名字是什么？
What's my name?
大卫。
David.
计算机声音：您好，戴维。
COMPUTER VOICE: Hello, David.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：曲折的选择很奇怪，但实际上是综合的。
DAVID MALAN: Weird choice of inflection, but indeed it synthesized it.
让我们尝试Brian。
Let's try Brian.
电脑声音：您好，布莱恩。
COMPUTER VOICE: Hello, Brian.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
所以我们可能可以修改设置
So we could probably tinker with the settings
使声音听起来更自然。
to make the voice sound a little more natural.
但这很酷。
But that's pretty cool.
好吧，让我看一下我这次使用预先编写的一些代码
Well, let me go into some code I wrote in advance this time using
一个不同的库，这个库与面部和面部检测有关。
a different library, this one related to faces and facial detection.
当然，在社交媒体方面非常流行
Certainly very much in vogue when it comes to social media
如今，随着Facebook和其他网站自动为您添加标签，
these days, with Facebook and other websites automatically tagging you,
与州政府和联邦政府的关系越来越密切
very concerning increasingly with state governments and federal governments
和执法部门使用面部检测功能来找到人群。
and law enforcement using facial detection to find people in a crowd.
让我继续在这里打开一个文件，例如，
And let me go ahead and open up a file here, for instance,
更加温和一点，就像一群人在办公室里一样。
a little more benignly, like a whole bunch of people in an office.
这是办公室里一些人的照片。
So here is a photograph of some people in an office.
而且那里有很多面孔。
And there's a lot of faces there.
但是，除了那些面孔之外，还有很多纸箱和其他分散注意力的东西。
But there's a lot of boxes of paper and other distractions besides those faces.
但是，让我继续快速看一下一个名为detect.py的程序。
But let me go ahead and look at, quickly, a program called detect.py.
这个文件的大部分是注释，只是如果您要在家中
Most of this file is comments, just so that if you want at home
您可以继续进行下去，看看它能做什么。
you can follow along and see what it does.
但是，让我仅强调一些明显的界线。
But let me just highlight a few salient lines.
再次是那个枕头库，我在这里
Here is that Pillow library again, where I'm
从预安装的Python函数访问与图像相关的功能。
accessing image related functionality from a pre-installed Python function.
这真是太神奇了。
And this one's just kind of amazing.
如果您想使用面部识别技术，
If you want to use facial recognition technology,
只需导入face_recognition。
just import face_recognition.
那是一个您可以导入的库，它将使您能够访问
That is a library you can import that will give you access
那种力量。
to that kind of power.
现在到这里，我只知道如何通过阅读一些文档来解决这个问题，
Down here now, I only knew how to figure this out by reading some documentation,
但是您访问了名为face_recognition.load_image_file的库，
but you access the library called face_recognition.load_image_file,
这是功能的意思。
which is a function that does what it means.
我正在打开office.jpg。
I'm opening up office.jpg.
然后在此处向下滚动到白色代码，这是实际的代码-
And then scrolling down here to the white code, which is the actual code--
所有的蓝色都是评论，回想一下-
all of the blue is comments, recall--
这行代码是Python所需的全部
this line of code here is all that's required in Python
使用面部识别库，找到所有面部位置
to use the face recognition library, find all of the face locations
在给定的图像中，并将它们存储在一个名为face_locations的列表中。
in a given image, and store them in a list called face_locations.
这行代码只是一个Python循环
This line of code here is just a Python loop
遍历检测到的面部中的每个面部。
that iterates over every face in the faces that were detected.
然后是这几行代码，长话短说，
And then these several lines of code here, long story short,
只是裁剪出个人面孔并使用找到的图像创建新图像
just crop out individual faces and create a new image with the found
面孔。
faces.
因此，无需过多了解库的详细信息，
So without getting too much into the details of the library, which are not
从理论上讲，这些功能对我们而言现在很有趣，
that intellectually interesting, the features are interesting to us for now,
让我运行detect.py的python。
let me run python of detect.py.
让我在这里给我的Mac几秒钟做它的事情。
Let me give my Mac a few seconds here to do its thing.
瞧，如果我放大此处，我们会看到菲利斯和吉姆，
And voila, if I zoom in here we see Phyllis, and Jim,
和罗伊，几乎所有其他面孔
and Roy, and pretty much every other face that
在那张照片中被检测到，并被裁剪成一张单独的脸。
was detected in that photograph, cropped out as, indeed, an individual face.
因此，如果您曾经发现自己身上有一个小方块
So if you've ever noticed a little square on yourself
在Facebook中上传照片时，这正是这种代码
in Facebook when uploading a photo, this is exactly the kind of code
Facebook和其他人正在其服务器上使用该文件来执行该操作。
that Facebook and others are using on their servers in order to execute that.
好吧，你知道吗，这呢？
Well, you know what, how about this?
在同一张办公室的照片中，
In the same office photo, you know, there's
一个似乎总是脱颖而出的人。
one person that always seems to stand out.
没有人真的喜欢他。
No one really likes him.
那就是托比。
And that's Toby.
如果我们在这样一个单独的文件中拍摄了托比的大头照怎么办？
What if we had a mug shot of Toby in a separate file like this?
我们可以在办公室里的这些人中间找到托比吗？
Can we find Toby in a crowd among these people in the office?
好吧，我们可以。
Well, we can.
现在，让我继续运行一个程序，该程序名为Recognition.py，
Let me go ahead now and run a program called recognize.py,
欢迎您在线观看。
which you're welcome to look at online.
这是相似的代码行，不是很多，
It's similar lines of code, It's not terribly many,
那会引起一些思考。
that is going to do some thinking.
它同时开放了办公室JPEG和这一文件。
It's opening up both the office JPEG and this one.
并注意发生了什么，如果我放大，
And notice what just happened, if I zoom in,
奇妙的是，托比是唯一一个脸上有一个大绿框的人，
wonderfully, Toby is the only one with a big green box around his face,
确实得到认可。
having indeed been recognized.
再说一遍，我只看一下代码。
So again, I'll just glance at the code.
这次，如果我打开identify.py，则需要多几行代码。
This time, if I open up recognize.py, it's a few more lines of code.
但同样，我正在导入面部识别和其他一些东西。
But again, I'm importing face recognition and some other things.
我正在加载toby.jpg。
I'm loading toby.jpg.
我正在加载office.jpg。
And I'm loading office.jpg.
然后，这里还有更多代码正在寻找Toby，
And then there's some more code here that's looking for Toby,
寻找托比，然后在脸上画一个大绿框
looking for Toby, and then drawing a big green box around the face that
最终被发现。
is ultimately found.
再说一遍，在一天结束时，它只是循环而已。
So again, at the end of the day, it's just loops.
只是功能而已。
It's just functions.
这只是变量。
It's just variables.
但是现在这些功能非常漂亮而且功能强大，
But now the functions are pretty darn fancy and powerful,
因为他们再次利用了所有其他功能
because again, they're taking advantage of all of these other features
我们自己已经用C之类的语言实现了，
that we ourselves have implemented in a language like C,
或现在已经看到了Python世界的一瞥。
or have now seen glimpses of within the world of Python.
好吧，让我们再做一个。
Well, let's do another one.
让我继续并快速打开一个真正的程序
Let me go ahead and open up real quickly a program
这样我就可以创建这些2D条形码之一，即所谓的QR码。
that will allow me to create one of these 2D barcodes, a so-called QR code.
让我继续创建一个名为qr.py的文件。在此文件中，让我继续
Let me go ahead and create a file called qr.py And in this file, let me go ahead
并做到这一点。
and do this.
出于某种原因导入操作系统库
Import the operating system library, for reasons
我们很快就会看到，让我导入QR码库
we'll soon see, and let me import the QR code library, which
会为我做所有的辛苦工作。
will do all of the hard work for me.
让我继续创建一个名为qr的图像-
Let me go ahead and create an image called qr--
分配了qrcode make的值。
that's assigned the value of qrcode making.
然后让我粘贴该课程的一个讲座视频的URL，
And let me paste in this URL of one of the course's lecture videos,
例如。
for instance.
然后让我继续将此图像另存为qr.png，便携式网络
And then let me go ahead and save this image as qr.png, Portable Network
图形（确实是PNG）是一种非常流行的文件格式
Graphic, as indeed a PNG, a very popular file format
用于照片和其他东西。
for photos and other things.
然后让我实际打开这个东西。
And then let me actually open this thing up.
开放系统-实际上，不，这很好。
Open up system-- actually, nope, that's fine.
让我保持简单。
Let me keep it simple.
我们不需要os库。
We don't need the os library.
不，我们愿意。
Nope, we do.
让我们继续并使用“ open qr.png”打开它。
Let's go ahead and open it up with "open qr.png."
所以三行代码
So three lines of code--
用该URL制作一个QR码，将其另存为qr.png，然后打开文件。
make a QR code with that URL, save it as qr.png, and open the file.
三行代码。
Three lines of code.
让我继续运行qr.py的python。
Let me go ahead and run python of qr.py.
瞧，速度非常快。
Voila, it was pretty fast.
如果您想拿出自己的iPhone或Android手机，
If you would like to take out your own iPhone or Android phone,
如果您的手机支持，请打开相机，
turn on the camera if your phone supports this,
笨拙地将手机对准演讲课，然后扫描3D条码
and scan this 3D barcode by awkwardly just pointing your phone at the lecture
正如我们所说的那样，它应该可以为您打开YouTube，并且具有以下特点：
as we speak, it should open up YouTube for you, hopefully, and with such is--
抱歉，是的，谢谢您向我展示您没有看到的内容。
I apologize to those-- yes, thank you for showing me what you're not seeing.
对于再次这样做，我深表歉意。
I apologize for doing that yet again.
永不变老。
Never gets old.
但是我们所做的只是嵌入二维格式，详细信息
But all we've done is embed in a two-dimensional format, details
其中我们不会在课堂上介绍URL，
of which we won't go into in class, a URL,
这表明您可以在这些二维条形码中存储任何内容，
which suggests that you can store anything inside of these 2D barcodes,
如果用像摄像机这样的东西解码它们
and if you decode them with something like your camera can
这些天在您的手机上运行的软件会为您解码这些内容。
the software running on your phones these days decode these things for you.
好吧，让我做点别的，这次涉及另一种意义，这个
Well, let me do something else, this time involving another sense, this one
听。
listening.
让我进入一个名为listen.py的文件。
Let me go into a file called listen.py.
让我继续做一些非常简单的事情。
And let me go ahead and do something very simple.
让我继续，在名为word的变量中获取用户输入
Let me go ahead and get a user's input in a variable called word
通过使用输入功能。
by using the input function.
说些什么。
Say something.
然后，让我将所有内容都转换为小写，只是为了使事情保持简单。
And then let me just send it all to lowercase, just to keep things simple.
现在让我来做。
And now let me do this.
听到用户的话后，让我继续说：
Once I get the user's words, let me go ahead and say,
如果他们用的是“你好”一词，请继续打印“向你好”
if the word "hello" is in their words, go ahead and print out "Hello to you
也！”
too!"
因此，如果他们打招呼，我想打个招呼。
So if they say hello, I want to say hello back.
Elif，说“你好吗”，然后让我继续并打印出一些内容
Elif, "how are you" in words, then let me go ahead and print out something
比如说“我很好，谢谢”。
like, "I am well, thanks," as the computer.
Elif用话语“再见”，然后让我继续说些合理的话
Elif "goodbye" in words, then let me go ahead and say something reasonable
就像“再见，你也一样。”
like "Goodbye to you too."
最后，否则，让我继续进行打印
And then lastly, else let me go ahead and print out
只是像“嗯？”之类的东西。
just something like "Huh?"
无法识别。
Unrecognized.
因此，如果您愿意的话，这就是人工智能的开始，即AI
So if you will, here is the beginnings of an artificial intelligence, an AI--
一个将以某种方式与我互动的程序
a program that's going to somehow interact with me the human typing
用这句话来形容。
in phrases to this thing.
因此，如果我正确地做到了，那么让我继续运行listen.py的python。
So if I did it correctly, let me go ahead and run python of listen.py.
我没有正确地做某事。
I did not do something correctly.
哦，不是“是”，“在”。
Oh, not "is," "in."
好的，对不起。
OK, sorry.
让我继续并运行listen.py的python。
Let me go ahead and run python of listen.py.
说些什么。
Say something.
我会说“你好”。
I'll say "hello."
哦，你好。
Oh, Hello to you too.
多么好的友好程序。
What a nice friendly program.
让我问问它是什么，“你好吗”，问号。
Let me ask it how it is, "how are you," question mark.
似乎发现了这一点。
It seems to detect that.
让我继续说：“暂时再见。”
Let me go ahead and say, "ok goodbye for now."
而且它也检测到，因为“再见”在短语中
And it detects that, too, because "goodbye" is in the phrase
用户键入的内容。
that the user typed in.
但是，如果我说“嘿”，那是无法识别的。
But if I say something like, "hey there," it's not recognized.
太酷了。
So pretty cool.
我们可以使用in介词使用非常简单的字符串比较
We can use very simple string comparisons using the in preposition
检测事物。
to detect things.
但是我敢打赌-你知道，我敢打赌，如果我们使用正确的库，
But I bet-- you know, I bet if we use the right library,
我们真的可以使它变得更强大。
we can really make this more powerful, too.
让我继续前进，就像我导入面部识别一样，
Let me go ahead, and just like I imported facial recognition,
让我用Python导入语音识别，这是另一个库
let me import speech recognition in Python, which is yet another library
我预先安装的
that I pre-installed.
让我继续，现在要做，识别器等于
Let me go ahead and now do this, recognizer equals
speech_recognition。识别器。
speech_recognition.Recognizer.
这只是创建一个称为识别器的变量
And this is just creating a variable called recognizer
我从字面上遵循了使用该库的文档。
by my having followed literally the documentation for using this library.
然后，让我继续进行操作，也可以从文档中进行操作，
Then let me go ahead and do this, also from the documentation,
以Speech_recognition.Microphone为来源。
with speech_recognition.Microphone as source.
所以这在某种意义上打开了我的麦克风，
So this is opening up my microphone in some sense,
再次按照文档进行操作。
again just following the documentation.
让我继续向用户说“说点什么”。
Let me go ahead and say "Say something" to the user.
然后，让我继续声明
And then after that, let me go ahead and declare
将一个称为音频的变量设置为等于识别器的监听功能，
a variable called audio, set it equal to the recognizer's listen function,
传入我的麦克风作为信号源。
passing in my microphone as the source.
现在，在这里，让我继续说，打印出“您说过”，
And now down here, let me go ahead and say print out "You said,"
在下面，我将打印出identifier.recognize，
and below that I will print out recognizer.recognize,
出于某种原因，它是今天迄今为止最困难的部分，Google音频。
is the hardest part today so far for some reason, google audio.
好的。
All right.
发生什么了？
So what's going on?
这行代码-这里的这些行
This line of code-- these lines of code here
正在与Mac上的麦克风建立连接。
are opening up a connection to my microphone on my Mac.
然后，它使用语音识别库来收听我的麦克风，
It's then using the speech recognition library to listen to my microphone,
并将来自我麦克风的音频存储在一个名为audio的变量中。
and storing the audio from my microphone in a variable called audio.
这些代码行实际上是在打印，
These lines of code down here are literally printing,
“您说了”，然后将其传递给google.com，音频文件
"You said," and then it's passing to the, the google.com, the file of audio
我刚刚记录在麦克风上，并且正在打印
that I just recorded on my microphone, and it's printing out
从Google回来的一切。
whatever comes back from Google.
让我们再来看一次
So let's see what comes out, again, crossing
我没有弄乱的手指。
my fingers that I didn't mess up.
Python的监听。
Python of listen.
你好，世界。
Hello, world.
胡胡。
Hoo.
你好吗？
How are you?
这是一个很好的语音识别。
It's a pretty good speech recognition.
可以这么说，它正在使用云。
It's using the cloud, so to speak.
它正在将其传递给Google。
It's passing it up to Google.
但是现在让我们做些更奇特的事情
But now let's make things a little fancier
并真正回应人类。
and actually respond to the human.
因此，让我回到这里并添加一些先前的逻辑
So let me go back into here and add back some of the previous logic
并说这样的话。
and say something like this.
如果是“ hello”，请像以前一样继续打印并打印出来，
If "hello" in words, then go ahead and print out, like before,
“你也好。”
"Hello to you too."
用Google的话说的Elif“你好吗”，
Elif "how are you" in the words that have come back from Google,
继续并打印出“我很好，谢谢！”
go ahead and print out "I am well, thanks!"
在这里，如果我说“再见”，
And down here if I said "goodbye" in words,
然后继续打印并“再见！”
then go ahead and print out "Goodbye to you too!"
否则，如果我认不出任何东西，让我们打印出“嗯？”
Else if nothing comes back that I recognize, let's just print out "Huh?"
因此，如果我做对了，让我们继续，让我们做listen.py的python。
So if I did this right, let's now go ahead and let's do python of listen.py.
你好。
Hello, there.
哦，该死。
Oh, dammit.
好，待命
OK, standby.
哒哒哒哒
Da-da-da.
哦对不起。
Oh, sorry.
让我查找并替换。
Let me do a find and replace.
我将变量称为“单词”，而不是“音频”。
I called the variable "words" instead of "audio."
我刚刚执行了一个漂亮的命令来替换它。
And I just executed a fancy command to replace it everywhere.
所以我这次要说的是“音频”。
So "audio" is what I meant to say this time.
现在，让我们继续运行此文件，即listen.py的python。
Now, let's go ahead and run this, python of listen.py.
你好，世界。
Hello, world.
该死
Dammit.
AudioData是不可迭代的。
AudioData is not iterable.
这是一个错误。
This is a bug.
给我一点时间仔细检查我的笔记。
Give me one second to double check my notes.
非常抱歉，令人失望。
Very sorry to disappoint.
音频输入-哦，我做到了-
The audio in-- oh, I did--
对不起。
sorry.
我第一次做的是对的，但是方法却是错误的。
I did it right the first time but the wrong way.
让我将我的变量改回单词。
Let me change my variable back to words.
好的。
OK.
我忘了要做的是在这里调用一行代码
What I forgot to do was call one line of code here
那实际上就是坐在我的面前。
that's literally sitting in front of me.
我需要转换识别器的返回值，identify_google音频。
I need to convert the recognizer's return value, recognize_google audio.
我需要存储将音频传递给Google的返回值
I need to store the return value of passing the audio to Google
并将结果文本存储在此处。
and storing the resulting text here.
因此，我在这里使用了变量word来进行重新存储。
And so I have re-stored, using the words variable here.
现在，让我继续并运行listen.py的python。
All right now let me go ahead and run python of listen.py.
你好。
Hello, there.
很不错。
Very nice.
你今天怎么样？
How are you today?
凉爽的。
Cool.
好，再见。
OK, goodbye.
好的。
All right.
因此，我们拥有了更加引人注目的人工智能。
So there we have an even more compelling artificial intelligence.
当然，它不是那么聪明，它只是在寻找预先设定的字符串。
Granted, it's not that intelligent, it's just looking for preordained strings.
但是我敢打赌，我们可以做更多的事情。
But I bet we can do something even more.
实际上，让我继续前进，看看我的同事是否
And in fact, let me go ahead and step inside, and see if a colleague of mine
忍不住实时地做某事。
can't help do something in real time.
在剧院里的一台大型花式PC上，我们
On a big fancy PC here in the theater, we
在CPU上运行其他Python程序
are running some other Python program on a CPU
这样的速度足以实时执行此操作。
that's fast enough to do this in real time.
而且我们已经将其中一台相机连接到该PC，
And we've connected one of our cameras to that PC,
因此，您即将看到的是我们其中一台摄像机的结果
so that what you're about to see is the result of one of our cameras being
连接到这台PC，将相机的输入运行到Python软件中
wired into this PC, running that camera's input into Python software
在该PC上运行。
running on that PC.
我们已经使用此Python软件对PC进行了培训，
And we have trained the PC, using this Python software,
识别过去的某些图像。
to recognize certain images in the past.
让我们看看是否也不能做到这一点。
And let's see if we can't do this as well.
布莱恩，您介意将我显示在屏幕1上吗？
Brian, would you mind putting me on screen 1?
还有荣欣，您要继续加载我们的第一位客人吗？
And Rongxin, do you want to go ahead and load up our first guest?
我认为我们还活着。
I think we are live.
再说一次，您在这里看到我的嘴与爱因斯坦步调一致。
So again, you see my mouth moving in lock step with Einstein here.
他的嘴唇与我的嘴唇相配。
His lips are matching mine.
他的头部动作在移动-
His head movements are moving--
匹配我的。
matching mine.
我们甚至可以变得好奇。
We can even be inquisitive.
如果我的眉毛抬起，请这样移动我的嘴。
If my eyebrows go up, move my mouth this way, this way.
您可以看到Python程序是实时的
And you can see that the Python program in real time
是将我的面部动作映射到其他人的脸上
is mapping my facial movements onto someone else's face, of course
否则称为深造假。
otherwise known as a deep fake.
容欣我们可以试试布莱恩的照片吗？
Rongxin, could we try out Brian's photo instead?
现在，我们这里有布赖恩（Brian），他也同样大笑。
Here now we have Brian who similarly is matching big smile.
在某个时候有点假。
Gets a little fake at some point.
但同样，如果我们将所有这些内容预先渲染而不是实时发布，
But again, if we pre-rendered all of this instead of doing it live,
PC可能会做得更好。
the PC could probably do an even better job.
怎么样，我们邀请哈佛总统拉里·巴科（Larry Bacow）加入我们，
How about could, we invite Harvard president Larry Bacow to join us,
容馨吗
Rongxin?
这是哈佛大学的CS50简介
This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
致计算机科学知识型企业
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
和编程艺术。
and the art of programming.
来自耶鲁大学荣信的彼得·萨洛维（Peter Salovey）总统怎么样？
How about President Peter Salovey from Yale, Rongxin?
这是耶鲁大学的CS50简介
This is CS50, Yale University's introduction
致计算机科学知识型企业
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
和编程艺术。
and the art of programming.
现在，这一点的现实意义
Now at this point, the real-world implications of this
应该越来越清楚了。
should be getting increasingly clear.
虽然在Instagram，TikTok等平台上实现此功能很有趣，但还是有游戏，
While it's all fun and games to do this on Instagram, in TikTok and the like,
如今使用各种移动应用程序，
using various mobile applications these days,
本质上是在做同样的事情-
which are essentially doing the same thing--
而且您可以看到图像并不太跟上
and you can see the image doesn't quite keep up
如果我现在开始移动得太快，请与我同在-
with me if I start moving a little too quickly right now--
这在政治，政府，
this is very real-world implications in the world of politics, government,
商业，实际上更一般地说只是现实世界，
business, and really just the real world more generally,
因为我本质上是在用别人的口说我自己的话。
because I'm essentially putting in someone else's mouth my own words.
虽然很明显，到目前为止，这些例子还不是真的
And while it's clear that these examples thus far aren't really that
令人信服-如果我开始移动太多，
compelling-- if I start to move too much,
您会发现事情开始不同步了-
you see that things start to get out of sync--
试想一下，如果我们等待一年，我们的计算机
just imagine that if we wait one year, our computers
如果有更多的内存等，速度将是以前的两倍。
are going to be twice as fast with even more memory and the like.
软件只会变得越来越好，功能越来越强大，
Software is only getting better and more powerful,
图书馆和人工智能正在接受更多培训。
the libraries and the artificial intelligence is getting more trained.
在接下来的几周的主题中，
And so among the themes for the coming weeks of the class
不只是如何用技术做一些事情
is not just how to do some things with technology
以及如何编写代码，但坦率地说，要求更大，更多
and how to write code, but frankly asking the much bigger, more
您是否应该使用技术做某些事情的重要图片问题，
important picture question of should you do certain things with technology,
并且您是否应该实际编写这样的代码。
and should you actually write such code.
我们确实征求了萨洛维总统和巴科总统的允许
We did ask President Salovey and President Bacow for their permission
事先以这种方式欺骗他们。
in advance to spoof them in this way.
但是我们认为我们会更有趣地结束
But we thought we would more playfully end
也许还有其他一些例子
with just a couple of other examples that you perhaps
在Instagram，TikTok等网站上查看。
see on Instagram, TikTok, and the like.
容欣我们可以邀请帕姆先加入我们吗？
Rongxin, could we invite Pam to join us first?
那某个吉姆呢？
And how about a certain Jim?
好的。
All right.
就是今天的CS50和Python。
That's it for CS50 and Python today.
下次见。
We'll see you next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]